DM: Before you leave
c00002
Wellby: Can we like long rest here or short rest here probably?
c00003
DM: Yeah, definitely
c00004
Seeker: I mean short rest, may as well
c00005
Unknown: Oh
c00006
Unknown: we're gonna-
c00007
DM: Short rest. Seeker has no seventh level slots left, but otherwise hasn't cast any spells, right?
c00008
Delwath: I mean, what's the downside of long resting?
c00009
DM: Oh, wait.
c00010
DM: You used your seventh level slot for teleport.
c00011
Unknown: Yes
c00012
DM: So how would you have u- you must have used an eighth level slot for, I mean, for Plane Shift, so you must have used an eighth level-
c00013
Unknown: No, I Plane Shifted
c00014
DM: Oh, you Plane Shifted, so you've used Plane Shift.
c00015
DM: Seeker's used one seventh level.
c00016
Delwath: So you have Plane Shift, Seeker?
c00017
DM: No
c00018
Seeker: With the wand
c00019
DM: With the wand, right.
c00020
DM: There's no, I mean, there's probably no reason you can't...
c00021
DM: I mean-
c00022
Unknown: We should just long rest
c00023
DM: ... it's been stable for 30 years, right?
c00024
Unknown: Yeah.
c00025
DM: It's like, what is...
c00026
DM: It's not like it's decaying in the next eight hours.
c00027
DM: And you've been
c00028
DM: with... Between every... I mean, you're hungry at this point.
c00029
DM: You've probably been traveling in Limbo for o-
c00030
Unknown: Right
c00031
DM: ... more than 12 hours.
c00032
DM: You started in the morning, so...
c00033
DM: Although actually the food that you made from the tree was incredibly filling.
c00034
Unknown: Mm.
c00035
DM: It's like Lembas. It's like a full meal in one fruit.
c00036
Unknown: Right.
c00037
DM: Um,
c00038
DM: but yes, there's no reason you can't long rest.
c00039
Delwath: If we're doing the long, I may as well then also I'm gonna cast.
c00040
Delwath: So three of us,
c00041
Delwath: um, Kenzo and
c00042
Delwath: Wellby get 30 extra hit points.
c00043
Wellby: Nice.
c00044
Kenzo: Hey, Tim, one question.
c00045
DM: Yeah
c00046
Kenzo: So Vital Burst, at the start of your turn you can activate its effect-
c00047
DM: Plus max HP
c00048
Unknown: ... until the beginning of your next turn.
c00049
Unknown: It increases your max HP.
c00050
Kenzo: So you can only do that one, it's basically just for one turn.
c00051
DM: It's basically like an action surge, yeah.
c00052
DM: So for one turn you can make t- double the number of attacks.
c00053
DM: You get the benefits of
c00054
DM: m- more attacks plus...
c00055
DM: Oh, the fridge is not closed.
c00056
DM: Can-
c00057
Unknown: Oh my,
c00058
Unknown: uh-
c00059
DM: Or is that a timer?
c00060
Delwath: That's my timer.
c00061
DM: Okay.
c00062
DM: So you get the bene- you get free dodge.
c00063
DM: Everybody has disadvantage on you.
c00064
Unknown: Right
c00065
DM: You get to make two extra attacks-
c00066
Delwath: Do you remember what the other resource was?
c00067
DM: ... and you double your speed.
c00068
Unknown: No, I'll just, I'll... You can just, I'll-
c00069
DM: But it's basically like a-
c00070
Unknown: I'm dad, but just one, just one minute
c00071
DM: ... it's just the first, it's like a burst out of combat.
c00072
Delwath: Um, sorry, when I said 20, 30, I meant 20.
c00073
Unknown: It starts combat?
c00074
DM: It's at the beginning. You can choose to do it at the beginning of your turn.
c00075
Unknown: Right.
c00076
DM: So it's-
c00077
Kenzo: Any turn
c00078
DM: ... any turn, yeah.
c00079
Unknown: Tollen, was I supposed to do something?
c00080
Delwath: Uh, 20, not 30.
c00081
Unknown: [clears throat]
c00082
Wellby: 20 HP?
c00083
Delwath: It's... Yeah, max HP goes up by 20, not 30.
c00084
Unknown: Oh, you all get an extra-
c00085
Unknown: You t- you too, yeah
c00086
Unknown: ... 20?
c00087
Unknown: 20, yeah.
c00088
Delwath: Not Seeker. Sorry, Seeker.
c00089
Unknown: All good.
c00090
DM: Seeker has a lot of hit points.
c00091
Delwath: I know. I can only do three people.
c00092
Seeker: I'm not gonna take any damage.
c00093
DM: [laughs]
c00094
Unknown: What?
c00095
DM: Seeker really liked the last battle.
c00096
Delwath: Why is the... How do I turn off the timer?
c00097
Wellby: I think I'm gonna untune from the Kenku armor and tune into Cloak of Protection, 'cause flying is not meaningful here, right?
c00098
Unknown: Yeah.
c00099
DM: That's true. Yes, flying is not meaningful here.
c00100
DM: [laughs]
c00101
Seeker: Um, I was gonna suggest we could all become gaseous form-
c00102
Unknown: How do I-
c00103
Seeker: ... clouds if you want, but-
c00104
Delwath: Yeah, there we go. I got it, I got it
c00105
Seeker: ... that also doesn't seem that useful.
c00106
Unknown: Uh, where's...
c00107
DM: I mean, you could also try and become a gaseous cloud just by imagining yourself as a gaseous cloud.
c00108
DM: [laughs]
c00109
Unknown: Yeah.
c00110
Unknown: Does Astral Being work here?
c00111
DM: Yeah.
c00112
DM: Although again,
c00113
DM: the main, one of the main benefits of Astral Being is flying, which you already can do, and passing through
c00114
DM: solid objects, which you already can sort of do.
c00115
DM: It does let you use the extra damage against the target of your Aura Focus.
c00116
Unknown: Yeah.
c00117
DM: But you don't, it doesn't give you that much benefit in terms of the flight or the pass through objects.
c00118
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c00119
c00120
Kenzo: Can I change Aura Focus during a single turn, like when fighting one and then just like...
c00121
DM: Yeah. Um,
c00122
DM: you can change,
c00123
DM: uh, you can change Aura Focus as a bonus action, but you can also use
c00124
DM: Flurry of Blows as part of the same bonus action.
c00125
Kenzo: That's... Okay. So you can, I can basically move Aura Focus around on our own.
c00126
DM: Yeah.
c00127
DM: All right.
c00128
DM: Okay.
c00129
DM: So you rest,
c00130
DM: um,
c00131
DM: recover. Um, Rai is not super talkative.
c00132
DM: It seems like,
c00133
DM: uh, it takes a fair bit of effort to just
c00134
DM: maintain everything that he's trying to maintain.
c00135
DM: But you do, I mean, you do hear a little bit more about the,
c00136
DM: you know, everything that happened and how most of the story of the events leading up to Rai getting caught here, you've pretty much figured out by now, I think.
c00137
DM: But basically
c00138
DM: he met some of the monks.
c00139
DM: He got worried that
c00140
DM: the
c00141
DM: wound was getting worse,
c00142
DM: and came up here, talked to Beryl,
c00143
DM: hashed a strategy,
c00144
DM: and didn't realize until they got to Isengai with all the monks and started doing this ritual to close a portal that it wasn't in fact a portal,
c00145
DM: and got ripped through.
c00146
DM: Managed to save most of the monks, but it has taken pretty much all of his...
c00147
DM: Oh, and as he g- he tells you as he got, as he was getting ripped through, he knew there was gonna be trouble, and he just sent out a desperate message to the only person he was telepathically connected to
c00148
DM: at the time,
c00149
DM: Dimitar.
c00150
DM: Please go find some powerful Dunmari, tell them what happened, bring help.
c00151
Kenzo: Dimitar did not do that.
c00152
DM: Dimitar didn't, did not do that.
c00153
DM: [laughs]
c00154
Unknown: [laughs]
c00155
Unknown: What the fuck, man?
c00156
DM: Maybe he tried and got distracted.
c00157
Kenzo: Dimitar's definitely got some, like, you know, Seeker Phadrig in him.
c00158
Unknown: Well, you know.
c00159
DM: He probably, like, went to go look for the Dunmari and saw one of the dragonets who were coming from the circular island, and was like, "What's this?"
c00160
DM: And followed them back.
c00161
Unknown: Um.
c00162
DM: 'Cause you know he only showed up on the circular island after Rai vanished, right?
c00163
Unknown: Right.
c00164
Unknown: Yeah.
c00165
Kenzo: But then, but then, um, Rai was also in Drancor.
c00166
Kenzo: Like, what was Rai doing with Apollyon?
c00167
Kenzo: Because he was doing something with Apollyon, too.
c00168
DM: Well, he originally teleported to Drancor after Cha'mutte died to stop-
c00169
Unknown: Okay, right
c00170
DM: ... Apollyon from summoning his phylactery.
c00171
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c00172
DM: Which would've cut through Cha'mutte's prison and released Apollyon into the world.
c00173
Unknown: And then that-
c00174
DM: But he basically re, he basically reinforced Cha'mutte's prison and hid the phylac...
c00175
DM: Remember you spent-
c00176
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
c00177
DM: ... forever, like he reinforced Cha'mutte's prison and hid the phylactery, and then he was sort of like, "Well, what else do I have to do?"
c00178
Seeker: Got it. Okay.
c00179
DM: That's why he started talking to the monks and trying to go back to his original goal, which was to
c00180
DM: finish the Great War and deal with Cha'mutte's issues.
c00181
Kenzo: Cleaning up. The cleaning up thing.
c00182
DM: Cleaning up, yeah.
c00183
DM: Apollyon was pretty stable, and would've...
c00184
DM: I, I mean, nothing would've happened except that.
c00185
Kenzo: So Apollyon destabilizing and starting to escape, and then Rai ending up in the
c00186
Kenzo: Ooze dimension, or in Limbo.
c00187
DM: Those were unrelated.
c00188
Unknown: Okay.
c00189
DM: What hap... A- Apollyon, Apollyon was only able to dis- destabilize and start to escape because he was talking to...
c00190
DM: He had corrupted the whole cleansed and had gotten Fausto to do all this work to get the ritual to go off that...
c00191
DM: Right? That was our whole-
c00192
Kenzo: And then ultimately if Rai, Rai had been around, he might have, like, been able to intervene or, you know, do something.
c00193
Unknown: But he was not around.
c00194
DM: Yeah, he might've been able to.
c00195
Kenzo: So that original vision where, like, Rai's hand explo- Like the, that, that vision that we kept seeing over and over again, that was...
c00196
DM: That was the moment that he tried to close the portal.
c00197
Unknown: Yeah. Okay.
c00198
DM: And his hand exploded in part because of the way he...
c00199
DM: You know, because the magic was...
c00200
DM: He was using the wrong magic.
c00201
Kenzo: Have you known that Rai was in Limbo this whole, this whole campaign?
c00202
DM: Yeah.
c00203
DM: Well,
c00204
DM: so to be fair, I didn't...
c00205
DM: I knew that Rai... I, I basically knew what happened, but the whole Limbo isn't gay connection actually-
c00206
Unknown: Yeah
c00207
DM: ... grew out of you-
c00208
Unknown: Flying over
c00209
DM: ... flying over the ship and-
c00210
Seeker: Basically experimenting with our altitude-
c00211
DM: Right
c00212
Unknown: ... with respect to
c00213
DM: ... So I didn't know exactly what...
c00214
DM: Like, I'd left it vague.
c00215
Delwath: 'Cause we only made up the Heartroot like 10 months ago.
c00216
Unknown: We talked about it.
c00217
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah. No, it was, it was very vague.
c00218
DM: 'Cause remember all the original visions, you just, you didn't see any details that could place it in a location.
c00219
Unknown: Yeah.
c00220
DM: It was just like somewhere Plaguelands-y.
c00221
Unknown: Right, right, right.
c00222
DM: So I let, so I had no idea where the Limbo wound was actually gonna be.
c00223
Unknown: Nice, nice, nice.
c00224
DM: That just sort of dropped into place.
c00225
Delwath: But you, but you knew Cha'mutte was connected to Limbo?
c00226
DM: Yeah, that I decided, like, super early on.
c00227
Kenzo: All right, let's go kill some Limbo, Limbo things.
c00228
Seeker: Since it has the entire Taelgar verse, I thought, "Oh, it should be able to construct the map accurately."
c00229
Seeker: And it did.
c00230
Unknown: [laughs]
c00231
DM: Wait.
c00232
Unknown: Huh.
c00233
Delwath: I mean, what is, what is that?
c00234
DM: Sea of what?
c00235
Unknown: Sea of Rahanga.
c00236
DM: Sea of Arket and Rahanga.
c00237
Kenzo: I like how Simbara and the sea are in the same-
c00238
Unknown: Like sea of the land.
c00239
DM: [laughs]
c00240
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c00241
Unknown: It's a little-
c00242
Seeker: That doesn't quite make sense.
c00243
Delwath: The widdle confused.
c00244
Delwath: It's missed the fact that Dunmar is a plane.
c00245
Unknown: There's no east. Yeah,
c00246
Unknown: [laughs] No east.
c00247
Kenzo: AI's so smart.
c00248
DM: I know.
c00249
Kenzo: It's incredible.
c00250
Kenzo: It's gonna take over and it's gonna be so smart.
c00251
DM: Okay. So after you rest and you, you hear these stories from Rai, and basically, like from his perspective, it's only been about five years
c00252
DM: in here.
c00253
Kenzo: Yeah, interesting.
c00254
DM: But it's-
c00255
Unknown: Also that's for our consideration
c00256
DM: ... but time, time passes strangely.
c00257
DM: It'll be like there's nothing, no...
c00258
DM: Like, it runs at the same rate for a year, and then Limbo just, time stops advancing in Limbo, and the time in the world advances.
c00259
DM: And nobody can predict when...
c00260
DM: Nobody can predict, you know, when Limbo is paused and when it's running at normal.
c00261
Unknown: It's not even that it fluctuates, it just stops.
c00262
DM: Yeah.
c00263
Kenzo: Does it ever go, does it ever reverse?
c00264
Delwath: It probably does. No? Never goes backwards?
c00265
DM: Oh, maybe it does actually.
c00266
DM: It could go backwards.
c00267
Unknown: I think it goes backwards sometimes.
c00268
DM: Maybe sometimes it goes backwards.
c00269
Unknown: It should go backwards sometimes.
c00270
Kenzo: Oh, no. That'd be problematic.
c00271
Delwath: I mean, probably it goes backward.
c00272
Delwath: It, yeah, going backwards is a little tricky, but feels like it should sometimes.
c00273
Unknown: Maybe there's pockets-
c00274
DM: Maybe it just goes sideways.
c00275
Delwath: Yeah. Pockets in Limbo that go backwards.
c00276
DM: It's how you, it's how you, it's how you go to alternate Taelgars.
c00277
Unknown: Mm. Yeah.
c00278
Delwath: It's how we go to, like, some other Taelgar.
c00279
DM: The one-
c00280
Delwath: That's how, that's how we're gonna eventually get to the Cha'mutte 1 Taelgar.
c00281
DM: Yeah.
c00282
Unknown: Oh, that's good. I, I'm sorry, guys.
c00283
Unknown: What's Cha'mutte 1?
c00284
Delwath: The, the Taelgar verse where Cha'mutte won the Great War.
c00285
Unknown: Oh.
c00286
Delwath: And the gods are all dead, and it's like arcane steampunk, like-
c00287
Delwath: Chardin is like the great hobgoblin empire.
c00288
Seeker: And then there's Izzy's Talgard.
c00289
DM: Right.
c00290
Seeker: Which is, it's kind of like the beginning of Fellowship, where the whole story is oriented around these two little moles inside Mount Doom.
c00291
DM: Right.
c00292
Seeker: But they go on to become incredibly powerful later on.
c00293
Unknown: Dude, the moles are dope.
c00294
DM: Yeah, Izzy's Talgard is great.
c00295
DM: I can never get my kids interested in those kinds of stories.
c00296
DM: Isaac, Isaac's entree to D&D was much more rules focused.
c00297
DM: He like wanted to play a character that had rules.
c00298
Unknown: Hmm. Hmm.
c00299
Delwath: Charlie was super into that kind of story, as a...
c00300
Delwath: There, there was a whole series of stories I used to tell.
c00301
Delwath: I think Isaac was in them too.
c00302
DM: Well, Isaac, Isaac ran games for
c00303
DM: Charlie and Nathaniel and Sasha.
c00304
Unknown: Yeah.
c00305
DM: Like he made up.
c00306
Unknown: Yes.
c00307
DM: He made up a whole bunch of games where he was the
c00308
DM: DM, basically.
c00309
Unknown: Which is the story that-
c00310
DM: Like when he was six.
c00311
Unknown: Yeah.
c00312
Unknown: Wow.
c00313
Seeker: That's cool.
c00314
DM: Okay. So everybody long rested?
c00315
Unknown: Yeah.
c00316
Unknown: Yeah. Short rested.
c00317
DM: No, long rest.
c00318
Seeker: Oh, long rest.
c00319
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c00320
DM: There's no reason not to.
c00321
Unknown: Yeah.
c00322
DM: So,
c00323
DM: uh.
c00324
Unknown: Are we gonna wait for Schwartz or?
c00325
DM: Yeah, I... Okay.
c00326
DM: I don't... Yeah, let's wait for Schwartz.
c00327
DM: I don't know how long,
c00328
DM: I don't know how long he'll be.
c00329
Delwath: Oh, well, I think he just, I think he just had to make a-
c00330
DM: Make a call
c00331
Unknown: ... short call. I don't-
c00332
DM: Okay
c00333
Delwath: ... I don't, didn't get the impression it was gonna be a long time.
c00334
DM: Yeah, let's wait.
c00335
DM: Okay.
c00336
DM: So as you finish your rest [coughs] and you leave
c00337
DM: the,
c00338
DM: um, be- you prepare to leave the sanctuary, um,
c00339
DM: the, the monks still, uh, you can see now that some, that they'll, they take shifts, and so some of them will rest.
c00340
DM: Um, and the rest of them are, are sort of going through.
c00341
DM: And they'll, they'll acknowledge you.
c00342
DM: Like they, they nod briefly, especially at Kenzo, and the ones that you rescued are now sort of
c00343
DM: mostly substantial, though it's probably still gonna take another few weeks before they're fully recovered.
c00344
DM: Um, but they'll, they'll sort of nod to you, but you can, you can see that they're all, there's like this underlying
c00345
DM: air of sort of nervousness and fear.
c00346
DM: Like, they've lost people who
c00347
DM: fell off, who like got distracted and weren't focused on the task, and so drifted out, slowly decaying more and more.
c00348
Unknown: Mm.
c00349
DM: And at least a few of them were just have been completely lost to Limbo itself.
c00350
DM: So they try, you know, they're pretty,
c00351
DM: uh, rigorous about making sure that they stick to their routines and their, um,
c00352
DM: uh, and their patterns.
c00353
DM: Uh, Rai has, um [coughs] uh, so Rai is connected, has a connection to the,
c00354
DM: to the relic, because he's also f- you know, essentially fighting with this ancient Limbo being,
c00355
DM: trying to keep it from gaining full control over the relic.
c00356
Kenzo: He's multitasking.
c00357
DM: He's multitasking.
c00358
DM: And,
c00359
DM: uh, so he can make showing up just through the threads of Limbo, like a glowing chain, like a bunch of links of sort of, um,
c00360
DM: greenish gold energy forming a chain that stretches off into the distance, and, um, he yanks,
c00361
DM: and the ch- and the chain,
c00362
DM: the sanctuary begins to move.
c00363
Unknown: Oh, question. Uh,
c00364
Kenzo: wait, is he bringing us to TC Trevor?
c00365
DM: He's bringing you close.
c00366
Kenzo: So can we, uh, ke- can we have Rai in our, uh, telepathy circle so he can like give us a, you know, like give you little...
c00367
Unknown: Oh, good question.
c00368
DM: For the first 50 minutes, or first hour, yeah.
c00369
Seeker: Hell yeah.
c00370
Kenzo: All right. Let's do that.
c00371
Kenzo: First hour of battle?
c00372
DM: The first hour that you're in the dungeon.
c00373
Unknown: That we're exploring.
c00374
DM: That you're exploring.
c00375
DM: He's not gonna bring it like d- like immediately next to you because-
c00376
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah, sure
c00377
DM: ... um.
c00378
DM: So a few moments pass.
c00379
DM: Um,
c00380
DM: you can actually see, so as this stops, uh,
c00381
DM: your, you know, Rai tells you to go.
c00382
DM: He's in the telepathy for a time anyway, and you pass back through the, um,
c00383
DM: you, you pa- and oh, he, uh,
c00384
DM: so he
c00385
DM: tells you, like you've, you've, there's fewer monks now who are sort of lost on the edges.
c00386
DM: Um,
c00387
DM: but also,
c00388
DM: you know, if you,
c00389
DM: he kind of asks if you have any way to,
c00390
DM: uh,
c00391
DM: to communicate with him.
c00392
Kenzo: Yeah, telepathy.
c00393
DM: But once it ends.
c00394
Kenzo: Oh, once it ends. Yeah. Huh.
c00395
Kenzo: Do we have Sending?
c00396
Unknown: Sendings down.
c00397
Unknown: Dreaming.
c00398
Wellby: Do, do we have a pair of, uh, uh, Sending flowers or?
c00399
DM: They're not, you have two, but they're not linked to each other.
c00400
DM: You should go find that boy in Chardin and take back his-
c00401
Wellby: We should, we should get the one back from Sora too.
c00402
DM: You should also, she probably doesn't want them anymore.
c00403
Unknown: Yeah.
c00404
Unknown: How about the fox messenger?
c00405
Delwath: Oh, yeah. Yeah. I can send him a message.
c00406
DM: Yeah, yeah.
c00407
DM: That's enough if you, uh, if you are...
c00408
DM: He says, "Warn me, because when
c00409
DM: i- if you succeed-" And you take the relic,
c00410
DM: the place you are in is likely to decay quickly as soon as the attunement between the [clears throat] the, um,
c00411
DM: entity and the relic is destroyed.
c00412
DM: So whether you remove the relic or you kill the entity,
c00413
DM: um, you're only gonna have moments before it decays into Limbo.
c00414
DM: Warn me so I can light a path back for you.
c00415
Unknown: Yeah.
c00416
DM: Otherwise,
c00417
DM: you'll be lo- I mean, you found me once, so maybe you can find me again, but...
c00418
Seeker: So our plan for sending a message to Rai is?
c00419
Delwath: Delwath's shield.
c00420
Seeker: Delwath's shield. How, how fast does that message travel?
c00421
Delwath: And then [laughs]
c00422
Wellby: Two grumlomphers per hour.
c00423
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah.
c00424
DM: No, it's, it's pretty fast.
c00425
Wellby: Four grumlomphers per hour.
c00426
DM: No, it's like-
c00427
Unknown: Like hundreds of grumlomphers per hour?
c00428
Wellby: Se-
c00429
DM: Like
c00430
DM: 45.
c00431
Unknown: Wow.
c00432
Wellby: Or furflings.
c00433
DM: Fur- furflings per mergelfuff.
c00434
DM: [laughs]
c00435
Seeker: R- Rai, is there any way that [laughs] information-
c00436
Wellby: [laughs] Neither time nor distance exists here
c00437
Seeker: ... travels across distance here in Limbo that
c00438
Seeker: we might take advantage of?
c00439
Seeker: Light or sound or shockwaves of any kind?
c00440
DM: Oh, he thinks for a moment.
c00441
DM: He says, "Oh, of course.
c00442
DM: Well,"
c00443
DM: he sort of jiggles on the chain, "If you're all holding on to the relic,
c00444
DM: I'll just yank you back."
c00445
Unknown: Oh.
c00446
Seeker: And you'll know when because we'll pull on our end.
c00447
Unknown: We'll tug-
c00448
DM: But-
c00449
Seeker: Three sh- sharp, short tugs
c00450
DM: Well, you'll... That'll only work-
c00451
Unknown: Short pull on
c00452
DM: ... that'll only work if you're attuned to it.
c00453
Seeker: Attuned to it.
c00454
Unknown: To the relic?
c00455
DM: Yeah.
c00456
DM: Which takes a short rest, so you may or may not have an hour.
c00457
Seeker: Seems like we're not gonna do that.
c00458
DM: But
c00459
DM: send me a message and hold on tight.
c00460
Wellby: What we're trying to solve for right now is once we-
c00461
Unknown: Right
c00462
Wellby: ... defeat this dude-
c00463
Unknown: Yeah
c00464
Wellby: ... it's all gonna come to pieces?
c00465
Kenzo: Yeah, it's all gonna collapse and then we have to escape.
c00466
Wellby: Ultimately... Wait, wait, wait.
c00467
Wellby: When that happens, is there a risk to Rai?
c00468
Wellby: Like do we immediately need to solve Rai and the monks' problem?
c00469
DM: No, no, no.
c00470
Wellby: 'Cause another option would be we rainbow bridge back
c00471
Wellby: instantly out of there.
c00472
DM: Well, I, I think-
c00473
Wellby: We hang for a while and Plane Shift back at the end.
c00474
Delwath: I think, I mean, the link goes pretty fast if the distance isn't that far.
c00475
DM: You don't know.
c00476
Unknown: But also the
c00477
DM: Rai doesn't actually know what will ha- Like he doesn't think his sanctuary's gonna instantaneously collapse, but...
c00478
Kenzo: We should bring the thing back with us-
c00479
Wellby: Yeah
c00480
Kenzo: ... and then let them, let, let, you know-
c00481
Seeker: I, yeah, I was wondering about that too.
c00482
Seeker: Let's, um, figure it out when we get there.
c00483
Kenzo: Uh, so when we're...
c00484
DM: [laughs]
c00485
Kenzo: So, you know, obviously we've never fought, uh, original Limbo beings, um-
c00486
Wellby: That we know of
c00487
Kenzo: ... that we know of.
c00488
Kenzo: Um, so any advice if, when, if when we encounter them?
c00489
Kenzo: Helpful, helpful tips?
c00490
DM: He thinks for a minute.
c00491
DM: [clears throat]
c00492
Seeker: Vulnerabilities, sensitive topics, discuss with them.
c00493
Kenzo: Vicious mockery.
c00494
Unknown: Yeah.
c00495
DM: All, all I can sense from a distance wrestling with her-
c00496
Kenzo: Her? Gendered
c00497
DM: ...
c00498
DM: is that,
c00499
DM: um, she has an incredible force of will.
c00500
Unknown: Hmm.
c00501
Seeker: Which is exactly what makes you strong and stable here in Limbo.
c00502
DM: Yes.
c00503
Unknown: Is that-
c00504
Unknown: One of us has a force of will
c00505
Seeker: ... a little bit metagame correspond to constitution?
c00506
Delwath: No, it's probably mental saves.
c00507
Delwath: It probably has like almost un...
c00508
Delwath: Probably spells that require save, mental saves, would be very difficult/pointless.
c00509
DM: Yeah. So target dex or strength or maybe con.
c00510
DM: Don't attempt.
c00511
DM: Don't waste your spells on the plus 15 wisdom, charisma, and intelligence saves-
c00512
Unknown: Got it
c00513
DM: ... is the advice Rai is giving you.
c00514
Unknown: Yeah.
c00515
Unknown: And, uh,
c00516
Kenzo: we'll ask him about the Order of Stability.
c00517
Unknown: And, uh,
c00518
Unknown: is she
c00519
Seeker: big or small? We'll, we'll find out.
c00520
DM: He's only like-
c00521
Delwath: Mergelfuffs across.
c00522
Unknown: Right.
c00523
DM: He's only like struggled with, like mentally wrestled for control of the relic with her.
c00524
DM: He hasn't ever seen her.
c00525
Wellby: Oh, shoot. Wait. What's the relic?
c00526
Delwath: The Piece of Order.
c00527
DM: The, the Piece of... The, the Relic of Stability, the like thing that's-
c00528
Seeker: Covered in runes
c00529
DM: ... covered in runes that you have, that lets you move the-
c00530
Unknown: You have to read the runes in the right order. Oh, you can't...
c00531
Unknown: Yeah.
c00532
Unknown: You have to make-
c00533
Kenzo: You have to make like a super insanely high arcana check to read the r- runes in the right order.
c00534
DM: If you read the runes in the right order, you can reshape the planes and move Limbo away from Earth, from the material plane.
c00535
Kenzo: Otherwise, it's mined for you to dissolve into Limbo and chaos.
c00536
Seeker: Right. So Seeker 6 is gonna do it.
c00537
Seeker: [laughs] Right, Seeker 6?
c00538
Unknown: Yep.
c00539
DM: [laughs] If Seeker 6 survives.
c00540
Delwath: Seeker 6 won't survive, though.
c00541
Seeker: The combat.
c00542
DM: Seeker 6 rarely...
c00543
DM: Seeker psamathens never really survive.
c00544
Delwath: They rarely survive, in fairness.
c00545
Seeker: It's true they are cannon fodder a little bit.
c00546
Delwath: I mean, there's a little bit of a like-
c00547
Wellby: There's a reason it's Seeker 6 and not Seeker 1.
c00548
Wellby: [laughs]
c00549
Unknown: [laughs] There's a little...
c00550
Seeker: Damn it, you're right. [laughs] There's something I need to confront here about my
c00551
Seeker: treatment of my own psamathen.
c00552
Delwath: Wow, 'cause you know it's not a good lie
c00553
Delwath: ... 'cause Se- Seeker's like, "You're not real."
c00554
Unknown: You're just a-"
c00555
DM: Right, but each new Somraka you create copies Seeker's memories-
c00556
Unknown: Not the old ones
c00557
DM: ... not the old Somraka's memories.
c00558
Delwath: So they don't think the other ones are real either.
c00559
DM: [laughs]
c00560
Unknown: Right?
c00561
DM: They're like, "I'm the only real one, obviously."
c00562
Unknown: [laughs]
c00563
Kenzo: This whole campaign has to end with Seeker-
c00564
DM: This is-
c00565
Kenzo: There, another Seeker is like on the circle island and, and it's like, "Wait, what?"
c00566
Unknown: Come on.
c00567
Kenzo: Like, who is the original Seeker?
c00568
Wellby: No, I'm ready like for Seeker's mind to melt, and then it turns out he's just snow.
c00569
DM: Yeah.
c00570
Kenzo: [laughs]
c00571
Unknown: Seeker's been snow his whole life.
c00572
DM: Seeker's been snow ever since the-
c00573
Unknown: He was
c00574
DM: ... the curse, like for,
c00575
DM: for I-
c00576
Unknown: Yeah
c00577
DM: ... for like years Seeker's just been snow.
c00578
Seeker: Seeker just wants to be a real boy.
c00579
DM: [laughs] Okay, so, uh, you exit through the
c00580
DM: shimmering concentric circles of-
c00581
Wellby: Oh, we missed the chance to get an autograph
c00582
DM: ...
c00583
DM: from-
c00584
Seeker: He can't move though.
c00585
Unknown: Well, we, uh, why, why-
c00586
DM: [laughs] Rai can neither see nor move.
c00587
DM: He can only mentally perceive the world.
c00588
Delwath: But you could autograph something like...
c00589
Unknown: So-
c00590
DM: [laughs]
c00591
Delwath: Kind of like a hot potato, but yeah.
c00592
Delwath: Um, Seeker's trick of drawing on the chalkboard with his mind.
c00593
DM: Oh, yeah.
c00594
Unknown: Right.
c00595
DM: Yeah.
c00596
Unknown: That's cool.
c00597
DM: Rai can do that. So you exit,
c00598
DM: um, and you travel only a short distance through, um,
c00599
DM: a relatively tame...
c00600
DM: Wait, hold on.
c00601
DM: Maybe it's not tame.
c00602
DM: Yeah, it's
c00603
DM: r- rel- relatively tame.
c00604
DM: Uh, uh, actually Seeker, you better make an in check 'cause you've rested, so there's no sphere of stability up anymore.
c00605
Unknown: Oh.
c00606
Seeker: Sphere of stability.
c00607
DM: This one only needs a 15 to defeat.
c00608
Seeker: This is, uh, uh, 7 plus 5 is 12, which is-
c00609
DM: So you exit
c00610
Seeker: ... really close to 15.
c00611
DM: It's very close to 15.
c00612
Wellby: Do you want bardic inspiration from, uh [metal clangs] from Seeker?
c00613
DM: That's, you could.
c00614
Seeker: I don't wanna, I don't wanna waste that though.
c00615
DM: Um-
c00616
Wellby: Would it be wasted though?
c00617
Unknown: I mean...
c00618
DM: Uh, you c- I mean, you can try again, but you're gonna get hit by these.
c00619
DM: So you exit, and Seeker starts to try and form.
c00620
DM: You exit into a, um,
c00621
DM: a sort of drifting sea of, of ash that smells sweet and pleasant, and you can hear sort of a drifting lullaby.
c00622
DM: But as the, but as you
c00623
DM: step, the ash sort of starts to cling to you and suck all the moisture out of you.
c00624
Unknown: Ooh.
c00625
DM: Um, and,
c00626
DM: uh, every...
c00627
DM: Where did it go? Everybody takes
c00628
DM: 11, 12,
c00629
DM: 15 points of necrotic damage as you begin to desiccate in the,
c00630
DM: uh, in the ash.
c00631
DM: And Seeker can try again.
c00632
Seeker: Ah, forgot to bring a humidifier.
c00633
Unknown: Potion of moisturizer. [die rolls]
c00634
Seeker: That's, uh,
c00635
Seeker: 13 plus 5, 18.
c00636
DM: Yeah. Okay. So after a moment,
c00637
DM: um, Seeker manage it.
c00638
DM: What are you trying to shape?
c00639
Delwath: Tim, I'm gonna, can somebody remember how much damage I took?
c00640
DM: Yeah.
c00641
Delwath: Or can you...
c00642
Delwath: I just, I'm not-
c00643
DM: I got it. I'll do your damage.
c00644
Seeker: Um, any shape requests?
c00645
Seeker: Go with a...
c00646
Delwath: Something like sub- like subtle.
c00647
Delwath: Can we do like... I don't think we're gonna successfully sneak up on this person, but can we like
c00648
Delwath: not immediately be like a big...
c00649
Unknown: I don't, I don't know what to say.
c00650
DM: I mean, you don't even have to create something.
c00651
DM: All you really have to do is like make a little humidifier so you're not all drying out and desiccated.
c00652
DM: Like, you don't have to create a platform to stand on.
c00653
DM: Remember, you can just drift.
c00654
Seeker: Oh, we can just drift, right.
c00655
Delwath: Why don't we just drift?
c00656
Seeker: We're in a b- a glass ball.
c00657
DM: Yeah, you just need to establish a new sphere of protection around you that is strong enough to prevent those effects from damaging you.
c00658
Seeker: Yeah, we're in a glass sphere.
c00659
DM: So you drift
c00660
Unknown: Oof, that was 18
c00661
DM: slowly through the ash, and the ash begins to get thinner and thinner as you drift following the lights of this chain, um, until, um, you emerge
c00662
DM: looking...
c00663
DM: It's not clear if it's really down or sideways, um, into a valley
c00664
DM: that's shaped of this same ash.
c00665
DM: There's like ash that comes up, but it's a, it's not a Euclidean valley.
c00666
DM: It's a valley that like comes to, to a point in every direction despite being a valley.
c00667
Unknown: Oh, my God.
c00668
DM: Um-
c00669
Unknown: All right
c00670
DM: ... so it's like a valley sphere.
c00671
Unknown: Healthy Mandelbrot.
c00672
Unknown: What's that?
c00673
Delwath: Healthy Mandelbrot.
c00674
Kenzo: Oh.
c00675
Unknown: Oh, we're gonna eat good.
c00676
Kenzo: Beautiful.
c00677
DM: I think we... Yeah, let's.
c00678
Kenzo: Yeah.
c00679
DM: Like, we can get bowls if somebody doesn't mind serving me.
c00680
Unknown: Sure.
c00681
DM: So, and inside this ash valley,
c00682
DM: you can see there's a tower,
c00683
DM: but this isn't like a normal tower.
c00684
DM: Um-
c00685
Seeker: This was no ordinary tower
c00686
DM: ... coming out of the, coming out of the floor of the valley is it's made of this dull metal that's just not,
c00687
DM: um, completely unreflective.
c00688
Delwath: And at the ground, at the-
c00689
Unknown: I think he's...
c00690
Unknown: See it
c00691
DM: ... at the bottom-
c00692
Unknown: Yeah
c00693
DM: ... you see
c00694
DM: a door, but like a
c00695
DM: 20 foot tall set of green emerald doors- With two,
c00696
DM: what look like, um,
c00697
DM: n- nine-foot tall,
c00698
DM: half...
c00699
DM: They're sort of like, um, a child's drawing of a centaur
c00700
Delwath: Well, they're kind of huge, so just, uh-
c00701
DM: Yeah. It's like you see standing outside what looks like a, like a badly sculpted drawing of a centaur with, like, ash puffing out around it.
c00702
DM: But as the ash puffs out around it, it, um, it is,
c00703
DM: um, it is solidifying and hardening into steel.
c00704
DM: Two of these things kind of pacing in front of the door.
c00705
DM: And then the tower goes, like, in some nonsensical twisty shape and there's a few places where it, like, comes to a point and then crosses and
c00706
DM: goes back the other way.
c00707
DM: Um-
c00708
Kenzo: Where next?
c00709
DM: The entire thing is made of this dull, matte black
c00710
Unknown: Just take them
c00711
DM: metal-ish thing.
c00712
DM: At the moment, you are, like, 300 feet away and still in a light ash fall.
c00713
DM: Nobody has seen you.
c00714
Delwath: So wait, the-
c00715
DM: So you're approaching... You're, you're coming from the, like, infinity point
c00716
Delwath: There's, like, a centaur by the gates, a weird-
c00717
DM: Two. Two
c00718
Unknown: ... two centaurs.
c00719
DM: Yeah.
c00720
Delwath: But what's above them?
c00721
DM: The tower goes up for a ways and then it, like, turns like this, and then it twists and spirals, and then it goes, like, up again.
c00722
DM: It's like-
c00723
DM: Super weird.
c00724
DM: But they are standing in front of the only obvious doors that you can see.
c00725
Delwath: Wait, but the... And the tower's made of glass?
c00726
DM: It's made of a black metal,
c00727
DM: completely non-reflective black matte metal.
c00728
Unknown: So, like,
c00729
Delwath: no way through it clearly.
c00730
Unknown: Well, we could Dimension Door.
c00731
DM: No entrances or exits except for the doors that you can see.
c00732
Seeker: All right. We, we, uh,
c00733
Unknown: we've got...
c00734
DM: Yeah.
c00735
Seeker: I guess I could try Clairvoyance and-
c00736
Unknown: I've got Arcane Eye.
c00737
DM: Yeah, yeah.
c00738
Delwath: We have to be 30 feet away from it though.
c00739
Wellby: Do these centaur things see us,
c00740
Unknown: respond?
c00741
DM: They have not seen you at the moment.
c00742
DM: You're still... There's, like, ash fall.
c00743
DM: You're coming, emerging out of the ash fall.
c00744
DM: You are lightly obscured by the ash.
c00745
Delwath: But we're still a couple hundred feet away, right?
c00746
DM: Yeah, you're, like, 300 feet away.
c00747
Seeker: Let's try Clairvoyance inside.
c00748
Unknown: See how much longer it takes.
c00749
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c00750
Seeker: Mm-hmm. So on the far...
c00751
Unknown: Just
c00752
Seeker: see what's beyond the doors maybe, unless
c00753
Unknown: anybody has a different suggestion.
c00754
Unknown: Sure.
c00755
Unknown: Okay.
c00756
DM: Uh, you go to cast the spell.
c00757
DM: Seeker stands there. It's a 10 minute casting time, so you begin chanting.
c00758
DM: You focus-
c00759
Unknown: Oh, Clairvoyance has a long casting time
c00760
DM: ... and-
c00761
Seeker: I forgot about that
c00762
DM: ...
c00763
DM: your spell is deflected.
c00764
Unknown: Oh.
c00765
DM: Divination spells cannot penetrate through this wall.
c00766
Seeker: Oh, it wasn't somebody actively counter-spelling or something.
c00767
DM: Nope.
c00768
Unknown: Hmm.
c00769
Delwath: You can, you can tell when you fin- when you complete the casting.
c00770
DM: Like, the spell fails because the place you were, like, the place you were trying to blocks your spell.
c00771
Unknown: Yeah.
c00772
Unknown: My clock is loud.
c00773
Wellby: No entrances, no openings?
c00774
DM: Doors.
c00775
Delwath: There's doors.
c00776
Unknown: Hmm.
c00777
Unknown: 20 foot tall green doors.
c00778
Unknown: They're closed.
c00779
DM: That are closed.
c00780
Unknown: And guarded, like you said.
c00781
DM: And guarded. No windows anywhere.
c00782
Delwath: So Dimension Door might be a little risky too.
c00783
Unknown: It is.
c00784
Unknown: Try it though.
c00785
Wellby: I'd prefer to use Teleport, seriously.
c00786
Unknown: It is risky.
c00787
Delwath: But you can't Teleport to somewhere you can't see.
c00788
Unknown: [laughs]
c00789
Unknown: But we could...
c00790
Unknown: With four of us, we...
c00791
Delwath: If Seeker casts Dim Door and Delwath casts Dim Door we can both...
c00792
Delwath: We can each take one person.
c00793
Unknown: Right.
c00794
Unknown: Uh,
c00795
Unknown: I guess I'm gonna-
c00796
Delwath: Oh, no. We'd have to leave behind, um-
c00797
Unknown: [laughs]
c00798
Delwath: We could. Wow.
c00799
Seeker: Actually, it might be good to leave Seeker Six behind
c00800
Seeker: so he can save the day if we all die.
c00801
Unknown: Huh?
c00802
DM: I mean, Seeker Six can also cast Dimension Door.
c00803
Delwath: I was gonna say, Seeker Six could just cast Dimension Door.
c00804
Unknown: Right.
c00805
Unknown: Um, or we could just, we could...
c00806
Delwath: I don't see any good options other than Dimension Door or go to the gate.
c00807
Kenzo: Well, we don't, but we don't have fight... We don't waste our energy fighting these centaurs right now, right?
c00808
Kenzo: We can sneak past them. Let's just do it.
c00809
Kenzo: Is Dimension Door not... Now, Dimension Door is not a divination magic, right?
c00810
DM: It's not.
c00811
DM: I mean-
c00812
Delwath: But it could still fail.
c00813
Unknown: Um,
c00814
Seeker: I bring up the ladder and the construct.
c00815
Delwath: You should bring up both 'cause we can't dimension door.
c00816
DM: You can't dimension door them both.
c00817
Kenzo: Wait until after we're on the other side.
c00818
Unknown: Just one.
c00819
DM: Well, the construct lasts only a minute, right?
c00820
DM: Construct lasts... They both last an hour.
c00821
Unknown: They both last an hour.
c00822
Unknown: Well, start with the ladder, then.
c00823
DM: Right.
c00824
Kenzo: Wait, don't we want to get to the other side before we start invoking stuff?
c00825
Unknown: We've got less than an hour.
c00826
DM: The ladder lasts an hour.
c00827
Kenzo: But then we won't build a dimension door then.
c00828
Delwath: No, no, no. We have six people.
c00829
Unknown: Oh.
c00830
Unknown: We now have-
c00831
Delwath: We have three dimension door casters, so six people.
c00832
Unknown: Right.
c00833
Unknown: Oh, okay.
c00834
Unknown: I didn't realize that at first. Yeah.
c00835
Unknown: Okay.
c00836
DM: So your... The range of dimension door is 500 feet.
c00837
Unknown: Yeah.
c00838
Unknown: So we could do it from right here?
c00839
DM: You could do it from right here. Where are you trying to dimension door to?
c00840
Seeker: It folds back at some point, right?
c00841
DM: The, the... Yeah.
c00842
DM: The f- it goes up like this normally and then it twists at like almost a 90-degree angle, and then the walls collapse to a point and then expand out again.
c00843
DM: And then it curves in a spiral, and then the very end points down.
c00844
Delwath: How about right past where the walls collapse?
c00845
Seeker: Why is it like that, though? Do you have a good mental model of what's inside there on that, on that spot?
c00846
Unknown: Because-
c00847
Unknown: Feels like Super Mario-
c00848
DM: No. [laughs]
c00849
Kenzo: Feels like Super Mario Brothers, like the pipes.
c00850
Delwath: I mean, uh, Delwath is all ears for better suggestions.
c00851
Delwath: I have no confidence whatsoever in his idea.
c00852
Wellby: I think, I think the, the opposite twisty thing is gonna be just fine 'cause, like, if the...
c00853
Wellby: If all of, like, space within it is also similarly folded, then we could just walk through it and we'd...
c00854
Wellby: Like, we'd just end up reversed on the other side, which would be fine.
c00855
Unknown: So on this side of the twisty thing?
c00856
Unknown: Like closer?
c00857
Seeker: See, once you walk through it, you come out all the same except your right hand is on your left side.
c00858
Unknown: Yes.
c00859
Wellby: You come out mirrored.
c00860
Unknown: Yeah.
c00861
Wellby: In three dimensions.
c00862
Unknown: Tim.
c00863
DM: [laughs]
c00864
Kenzo: Instead of trying to sense for consciousness-
c00865
Unknown: Hmm
c00866
Unknown: ...
c00867
Kenzo: um, Kenzo will sense for stability.
c00868
DM: Oh.
c00869
DM: All right.
c00870
Kenzo: Just like, where the fuck is this? Where the fuck are we going?
c00871
Kenzo: You know? We don't even know where the fuck we're going.
c00872
DM: Um,
c00873
DM: so this whole area is
c00874
DM: m- much more stable than the rest of anywhere you've passed through except for the center of the Limbo sands.
c00875
Unknown: Oh, okay. I hope the-
c00876
DM: This is intended
c00877
Unknown: ... good
c00878
DM: ... like that's your sen- this is not, like, chaos.
c00879
Unknown: Yeah.
c00880
DM: This is inte- intentionally designed in this way.
c00881
Kenzo: Okay. So actually, here, just
c00882
Kenzo: if it is okay to retcon this.
c00883
DM: Yeah.
c00884
Kenzo: I think when Kenzo was with the monks and with Rai in the safe space.
c00885
DM: Uh-huh.
c00886
Kenzo: So he's in... That's, like, structured space inside Limbo.
c00887
Kenzo: Kenzo experiments with, um, you know, his natural sensing abilities.
c00888
DM: Yeah.
c00889
Kenzo: Is he able to, like, sense things inside the stable stuff place?
c00890
DM: Yes.
c00891
Unknown: Okay, perfect. Then
c00892
Kenzo: Kenzo will... So, well, first off, I'm gonna soul sight the centaurs.
c00893
DM: Oh, too far away. Too far away.
c00894
Kenzo: Too far away. Okay. But can I sense the centaurs?
c00895
DM: With your, with your, like, um-
c00896
Unknown: Yes.
c00897
DM: Yeah, yeah. Um, yes, you can sense them.
c00898
Kenzo: Amazing. Great. So now I will reach out and do my diagnostic sweep and s- look for other entities.
c00899
DM: There's nothing... There's, there's one other thing buried in the ash outside.
c00900
DM: The tower itself is in negative space-
c00901
Unknown: Oh, wait, wait. Hold, hold, hold, wait, wait
c00902
DM: ... in your sensations.
c00903
Unknown: Negative space?
c00904
Kenzo: No, wait. But he just said there's something buried in the ash, like below the centaurs.
c00905
DM: Below the centaurs.
c00906
Kenzo: Okay. So I just sniffed out a se- some, like, trap thing if we were to...
c00907
Unknown: Okay, that's good.
c00908
Unknown: Word.
c00909
Unknown: And then, and then-
c00910
Delwath: I mean, I think there's, like, a 10% chance dimension door works.
c00911
Unknown: Yeah.
c00912
Delwath: But let's try it.
c00913
Unknown: The tower is-
c00914
Unknown: Oh, right
c00915
Unknown: ... is-
c00916
Seeker: 'Cause the clairvoyance is blocked.
c00917
Unknown: Dimension door won't work
c00918
Delwath: ... yeah. I mean, that... You can't... It's not divination magic.
c00919
Unknown: Yeah.
c00920
Delwath: But it might not exist.
c00921
Unknown: Yeah.
c00922
Delwath: Tower might not exist until you go through the door.
c00923
Unknown: Yeah.
c00924
Delwath: Some, some anti s- but let's try.
c00925
Unknown: But, but what was the negative one thing?
c00926
Unknown: Or so-
c00927
DM: It's, it's like, it's like the tower has been cut out of your vision of the world.
c00928
DM: It doesn't exist in your vision of the world.
c00929
DM: There's nothing you can sense inside the tower whatsoever.
c00930
Unknown: Fuck.
c00931
DM: Yeah. You feel like the coldness of the metal of the outside, but the interior is completely gone, like opaque and impossible.
c00932
Unknown: Well, I...
c00933
Delwath: Some Lacrim seeker maybe goes first, wait like one second before, so if it fails, you, Seeker and Delweth do it.
c00934
Unknown: Seeker and Delweth do it.
c00935
DM: Good call.
c00936
Seeker: And who... Wait, Seeker 6 was gonna bring
c00937
DM: The ladder?
c00938
Seeker: The ladder. Okay.
c00939
Kenzo: Yeah, [laughs] they're like the B team.
c00940
Unknown: [laughs]
c00941
Delwath: But like also, is there a way we know if they like died instantly?
c00942
Unknown: Presumably they won't die instantly.
c00943
DM: No, because
c00944
DM: your telepathy will s- if it, divination spells can't pass through, your telepathy will cease to work as soon as you go inside the tower.
c00945
DM: So you have no idea what happens to them.
c00946
Unknown: And then... Hmm.
c00947
Delwath: But that's okay. We're just going.
c00948
Seeker: Do it. So step one, [clears throat] Seeker six-
c00949
Unknown: [laughs]
c00950
Seeker: And ladder.
c00951
Unknown: Yeah.
c00952
Seeker: Dimension Door through the doors.
c00953
DM: Okay.
c00954
Wellby: Step two, Seeker seven.
c00955
Wellby: [laughs]
c00956
Unknown: [laughs]
c00957
Unknown: It is.
c00958
DM: Roll a D4.
c00959
Unknown: Oh, God.
c00960
DM: So this is gonna get complicated.
c00961
Unknown: I'm so excited.
c00962
DM: Who's going next?
c00963
Seeker: We will, we will remember you fondly, Seeker six.
c00964
Delwath: Ah, who's coming with Delweth?
c00965
Wellby: Well-
c00966
Kenzo: Just wait, hold on. It's, it's just, this is-
c00967
DM: Well, that's a four.
c00968
Unknown: Okay. [laughs]
c00969
DM: I mean... [laughs]
c00970
Wellby: [laughs]
c00971
DM: Okay.
c00972
Unknown: Let's go.
c00973
Seeker: So we take a breath. All is quiet.
c00974
Unknown: Who's coming with Delweth?
c00975
Unknown: Wait, and then who would I go with?
c00976
Unknown: Seeker
c00977
Delwath: or Delweth.
c00978
Seeker: Oh. Yeah, we just gotta form two pairs here.
c00979
Unknown: We just gotta form two pairs.
c00980
Wellby: All right, let's do it.
c00981
Unknown: Yeah.
c00982
Delwath: All right. I got Wellby.
c00983
Unknown: I still have to roll a D4 too.
c00984
Unknown: [laughs]
c00985
Wellby: Wellby crosses both his fingers and toes in case that has a mechanical benefit.
c00986
Unknown: Two.
c00987
Kenzo: We're all ending up in different places.
c00988
Unknown: This is, that's-
c00989
Unknown: Yeah
c00990
Kenzo: ... we're not, we're not gonna be together.
c00991
DM: Okay. This was Delweth and-
c00992
Unknown: Yeah
c00993
DM: ... Wellby.
c00994
Unknown: Yeah.
c00995
Kenzo: Oh, this, this feels really, this feels r-
c00996
Unknown: This is such a great plan
c00997
Unknown: ... I don't-
c00998
Seeker: It's gonna work out so great.
c00999
Unknown: Yeah, we...
c01000
Seeker: So and I do, I assume I roll as well.
c01001
DM: Yep.
c01002
Seeker: Okay, Kenzo, here we go.
c01003
Unknown: Oh my God.
c01004
Seeker: That's a one.
c01005
Unknown: [laughs]
c01006
Kenzo: We're definitely all in different places, buddy adventures.
c01007
DM: Kenzo plus Seeker.
c01008
Wellby: Good luck, guys. [laughs]
c01009
Kenzo: Ooh, or is it like a Freaky Friday thing and now I'm inside Wellby and like-
c01010
DM: Wait, wait, hold on.
c01011
Wellby: That'd be really funny.
c01012
DM: Let me look at my map real quick.
c01013
Unknown: That actually would be kind of fun.
c01014
Seeker: Or like, um, was it Being John Malkovich?
c01015
Seeker: All of us are Seeker. [laughs]
c01016
Unknown: [laughs] Right.
c01017
Kenzo: I think that's V for Vendetta.
c01018
DM: So you rolled a one?
c01019
Unknown: Yeah. Yes.
c01020
DM: Okay.
c01021
DM: Um,
c01022
DM: you guys can't see this because you've already disappeared.
c01023
DM: I'll tell you what you see in a minute.
c01024
DM: Nobody knows what's happening with Seeker six and-
c01025
Unknown: The ladder
c01026
DM: ... the ladder.
c01027
DM: Um,
c01028
DM: uh, you
c01029
DM: find yourself appearing right in front of the door.
c01030
Kenzo: Just Seeker or me and Seeker?
c01031
DM: You too.
c01032
Unknown: Okay.
c01033
DM: The Dimension Door like-
c01034
Wellby: Next to the centaurs?
c01035
DM: ... bounces, bounces off the-
c01036
Unknown: Oh, boy
c01037
DM: ... the wall.
c01038
Seeker: Oh, we're not inside
c01039
DM: ... and redirects you down to the ground.
c01040
Unknown: So we're outside.
c01041
DM: Yes.
c01042
Seeker: Uh-oh. Uh, Kenzo, I don't think that worked.
c01043
Wellby: [laughs]
c01044
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo ch- the astral plane's astral.
c01045
Delwath: C- can we tel- is his health telepathy gone?
c01046
Seeker: Do you vanish?
c01047
DM: Uh, you cannot t- telepathy with them.
c01048
Delwath: Can we telepathy with Se- with Seeker six?
c01049
DM: Uh,
c01050
DM: yes.
c01051
Delwath: Okay. I assume Seeker six is not immediately in front of us.
c01052
DM: Seeker six is not immediately in front of you.
c01053
Unknown: Okay. [laughs]
c01054
DM: You, um, see you are inside
c01055
DM: a chamber.
c01056
DM: Um, the chamber is-
c01057
Unknown: Happy
c01058
DM: ... uh,
c01059
DM: it's a, it's like maybe...
c01060
DM: Hold on, let me just, sorry, let me just check.
c01061
DM: I gotta pull up my map and look here.
c01062
DM: Um,
c01063
DM: the chamber is like
c01064
DM: about like 40 or 50 feet across.
c01065
DM: Um, the entire surface of the chamber is covered in this intricate mosaic that ripples with magic.
c01066
Unknown: Nice.
c01067
DM: The walls and the ceiling are showing like these ever shifting scenes.
c01068
DM: Um, most of them are showing like a central humanoid or some...
c01069
DM: They're moving, right? They're mo- they're like moving illusions, showing like a central humanoid striding through a landscape, um, the ground behind them decohering into
c01070
DM: this sort of limbo chaos as they walk.
c01071
DM: Um, whereas others seem to be showing contests of will between these humanoid shapes and like strange geared creatures that look like construct, clockwork
c01072
DM: constructs.
c01073
DM: The humanoids that you're looking at seem like vaguely elemental in form, kind of, uh, like fire shaped into a human form that gives off rippling waves of
c01074
DM: water smoke or like vapor stone around a core of condensed air or ice like burning casting a, um,
c01075
DM: dark fire, and it seems to be depicting some kind of
c01076
DM: war.
c01077
DM: Like these chaos humanoids are like striding to battle and trying to
c01078
DM: conquer territory.
c01079
DM: There's four pillars in the room, each with flicker with flames of darkness that suck the light and the warmth from the room.
c01080
DM: Um, you both have true sight.
c01081
Unknown: Yeah.
c01082
DM: Right?
c01083
Unknown: Yeah.
c01084
DM: The floor is an illusion
c01085
DM: and, um, although it looks like tile work, there's, there's actually 20, um,
c01086
DM: like, uh- ...
c01087
DM: droplets of liquid stone that have grasping tentacles that flicker in and out of existence, hovering below the
c01088
DM: illusory floor waiting to pounce on somebody.
c01089
Delwath: Can I take a step up off the floor into the air?
c01090
DM: Yeah.
c01091
Wellby: Yeah. Otherwise I'm in...
c01092
Unknown: Yeah.
c01093
Delwath: Okay. Let's not stand on the floor.
c01094
Unknown: Nope.
c01095
DM: Meanwhile...
c01096
DM: Wow, you guys had to make this the most complicated possible thing to run.
c01097
DM: It's great. I love it.
c01098
DM: Um-
c01099
Delwath: [laughs] We didn't make it the most complicated thing to run, Tim.
c01100
Unknown: [laughs]
c01101
DM: [laughs]
c01102
Delwath: It wasn't us.
c01103
Unknown: I'm not sure the blame is entirely on us.
c01104
DM: Well, you didn't really...
c01105
DM: After everything, did you really think teleportation magic was gonna work smoothly in Limbo?
c01106
Delwath: I said I thought it had a 10% chance of working.
c01107
Unknown: [laughs]
c01108
c01109
DM: Fair. Um-
c01110
Wellby: This is not just, like, a powerful be- This is, like, the ruler of Limbo.
c01111
Unknown: This is, like, the-
c01112
DM: Yeah
c01113
Unknown: ... creator of Limbo.
c01114
DM: Not the creator, but maybe the creator.
c01115
DM: I guess you'll find out. Um-
c01116
Unknown: I like our odds a lot less
c01117
DM: ... meanwhile, the two stone creatures-
c01118
Delwath: We don't have to kill it, Tim. We just have to steal the thing
c01119
Unknown: Right
c01120
Unknown: ... steal the thing
c01121
DM: ... clank, clank over towards you.
c01122
Unknown: Wait, uh-
c01123
Unknown: Oh, they clank?
c01124
DM: As they move. There's like, the smoke is, like, hardening into metal, and it's like, as they move, there's like metal plates clanking.
c01125
DM: They look, and one of them says, rapidly cycling through languages, each word a different language, but Kenzo can understand all languages.
c01126
Unknown: Oh.
c01127
DM: So you understand. "Visitors.
c01128
DM: Visitors.
c01129
DM: Strange." Looks over at his or her companion.
c01130
DM: "Are you here to worship?
c01131
DM: Have you come to give yourselves
c01132
DM: to the Great Goal?"
c01133
Unknown: The Great what?
c01134
Unknown: Goal.
c01135
c01136
Unknown: Like G-O-A-L?
c01137
DM: G-O-A-L, yes.
c01138
Seeker: Uh, yes. We're here to worship.
c01139
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo, Kenzo's an astral form.
c01140
Unknown: Does that... What does that mean?
c01141
Kenzo: We're, we're, we're standing in front of the door, right?
c01142
Unknown: Well, the, the door, right?
c01143
DM: Yeah.
c01144
Kenzo: Kenzo just kind of, like, reaches back behind.
c01145
Unknown: Like-
c01146
DM: [laughs]
c01147
Kenzo: ... does his hand pass through the door?
c01148
DM: No.
c01149
Unknown: Oh.
c01150
Unknown: Are you visible?
c01151
DM: Yeah.
c01152
Unknown: I'm like, I'm like shimmery.
c01153
DM: Not fully formed. He's, like, ghost-like.
c01154
Unknown: Yeah, okay.
c01155
DM: Shimmering, ghostly.
c01156
Unknown: And
c01157
Seeker: did you see something underneath the ash?
c01158
Seeker: I can't, I can't pass through the door.
c01159
Unknown: [laughs]
c01160
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, I, I noticed you...
c01161
Unknown: Okay.
c01162
Unknown: I'm gonna have a little more of these.
c01163
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c01164
Delwath: You want, do you want any more, David?
c01165
DM: Yeah, I'll have a little more.
c01166
Unknown: All right.
c01167
Unknown: If, if, if there's, there's very little left.
c01168
DM: Not very much. I just need, like...
c01169
DM: Give me, like, one piece of sausage.
c01170
Kenzo: There, there was one more sausage.
c01171
Unknown: There is a piece of sausage.
c01172
DM: Give me one potato.
c01173
Seeker: Well, I'm done. That's...
c01174
Delwath: Yeah, how about... Would you like a potato too?
c01175
DM: One potato.
c01176
DM: Stop.
c01177
Unknown: Please.
c01178
DM: I want some more.
c01179
Wellby: There's more aruba if anybody wants aruba.
c01180
Unknown: That was-
c01181
Delwath: I guess I should have gotten, uh... Well, I guess we had 20 or 30, but-
c01182
Unknown: That was very tasty.
c01183
Unknown: It was really-
c01184
DM: Yeah, it is really good
c01185
Unknown: ... really good.
c01186
DM: That should be our, our mandelbrot standard from now on.
c01187
Kenzo: Yeah, that was fantastic, Mike.
c01188
Unknown: Thank you.
c01189
Unknown: Actually really easy.
c01190
DM: I think we, like, invented something like this up in Alexandria a few years ago, but this is better.
c01191
Seeker: But unfortunately, I don't feel like my body is, like, fighting off some massive-
c01192
DM: Right, it's 'cause of all the-
c01193
Unknown: ... counterattack on it
c01194
Wellby: ... we're, we're like, we're moving through the space of all possible mandelbrot.
c01195
DM: [laughs]
c01196
Wellby: Like, we're at a different scale at this point.
c01197
Unknown: Well, the, the mandelfold.
c01198
DM: Right.
c01199
Unknown: Exactly.
c01200
Seeker: The mandelbrot mandelfold.
c01201
DM: So-
c01202
Kenzo: The mandelverse
c01203
DM: ... in front of the door, uh,
c01204
DM: Otesea did say-
c01205
Unknown: Otesea
c01206
DM: ... "Don't," the other one, Elbos, "Don't...
c01207
DM: We don't know who these are, don't tell them anything."
c01208
Unknown: We are friends.
c01209
Unknown: We are expected.
c01210
DM: "That seems very unlikely," says the grumpier, gruffer one.
c01211
Kenzo: Ah, but we've arrived just in time.
c01212
Seeker: Wouldn't want to displease the boss.
c01213
Kenzo: Thanks for letting us in. [laughs]
c01214
Unknown: [laughs]
c01215
Unknown: Or to a grave.
c01216
DM: Make a...
c01217
DM: One of you make a persuasion check.
c01218
Seeker: That's gonna be you.
c01219
Kenzo: What's, uh, what's... I don't know.
c01220
Unknown: I'm very persuasive.
c01221
DM: Neither of you have very good persuasion.
c01222
Kenzo: I think, I think we're being very persuasive.
c01223
DM: Meanwhile [laughs]
c01224
Wellby: The only persuasive party member is inside of me.
c01225
DM: What are you-
c01226
Delwath: Uh, uh,
c01227
Delwath: there... Are there any doors out?
c01228
Unknown: Plus one?
c01229
DM: There is... No, there are no doors.
c01230
DM: There's just this-
c01231
Unknown: Plus one
c01232
DM: ... um, the only things in the-
c01233
Unknown: You got, you got this
c01234
DM: ... is the four pillars.
c01235
DM: Did I mention there's a violet orb that hovers four feet off the ground?
c01236
Delwath: You did not mention that, no.
c01237
Delwath: Seeker, Seeker.
c01238
Unknown: One of them violet orbs, huh?
c01239
Unknown: Seeker.
c01240
Delwath: Uh, a violet orb. Like, how big is a violet orb?
c01241
Delwath: Like a head size? A golf ball size?
c01242
DM: Um-
c01243
Unknown: Like, huge?
c01244
DM: Like, that big.
c01245
Wellby: Just to be clear, there's no entrances or exits from this space that we're in?
c01246
DM: There are no entrances or exits from the space.
c01247
DM: Uh, make a perception check.
c01248
Delwath: Seeker, Seeker, Seeker.
c01249
DM: Um, and then roll initiative.
c01250
Unknown: Uh, oh, shit. [laughs]
c01251
Unknown: [laughs]
c01252
Wellby: I think it's a tw- uh, it's a-
c01253
DM: With a... Don't forget you always have advantage.
c01254
Unknown: Oh, I do forget.
c01255
Wellby: That's better. That is a 29.
c01256
DM: Um.
c01257
Unknown: I've got my...
c01258
DM: What are you looking for?
c01259
Unknown: My phone.
c01260
Seeker: Can we retcon that we-
c01261
Unknown: Oh, check this
c01262
Seeker: ... passed around, um,
c01263
Unknown: uh,
c01264
Seeker: inspirations between the two Seekers to everybody else?
c01265
DM: Sure.
c01266
Kenzo: That's pretty standard.
c01267
Unknown: That's pretty standard.
c01268
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c01269
DM: Uh,
c01270
Delwath: probably should use yours mostly.
c01271
DM: So everybody... Seeker-
c01272
Delwath: Everybody gets one of regular.
c01273
Delwath: Don't you... How many do you have? Like, six?
c01274
DM: Six total.
c01275
Delwath: So give one to all three of us from you.
c01276
Unknown: [coughs]
c01277
Delwath: Then you'll have used three.
c01278
DM: And, and the... And Seeker Six-
c01279
Unknown: Seeker Six
c01280
DM: ... also has six and has used one.
c01281
Delwath: So, and then gives one to you.
c01282
DM: So Seeker Six gives one to you.
c01283
DM: So Seeker Six has used two.
c01284
Unknown: Okay.
c01285
DM: Oh, and Seeker Six used a dimension door, so that's a fifth level spell.
c01286
Delwath: Yes. Fourth.
c01287
DM: Sorry, a fourth level spell.
c01288
DM: So one seven-
c01289
Delwath: Two, seven dimension door
c01290
DM: Uh, so you are, you are not surprised because you have true sight as these 20 things emerge up from the floor to come swarm and attack you.
c01291
DM: You notice that, uh, the door...
c01292
DM: So like on one side of the room is the
c01293
DM: violet sphere.
c01294
Unknown: [laughs]
c01295
DM: On the opposite side of the room from the violet sphere, there's a small crack in the wall that looks like the seam of a door.
c01296
Unknown: Door.
c01297
Delwath: Let's go that way.
c01298
Delwath: But I, but I guess we have a, uh...
c01299
Delwath: I guess we have some problems first.
c01300
Unknown: [laughs]
c01301
Seeker: So a bit of a situation here. [laughs]
c01302
Unknown: That's a big room.
c01303
Seeker: Are these five or 10 foot?
c01304
Unknown: Five.
c01305
DM: Five f- that's a very, very bad circle.
c01306
DM: So the seam of the door is here.
c01307
DM: The
c01308
DM: purple orb is floating there, and then there's these four pillars
c01309
DM: that give off darkness.
c01310
Unknown: Okay.
c01311
DM: But you have true sight, so it doesn't matter.
c01312
DM: Um, and then these things that are floating, these like stone tentacle things that are floating up-
c01313
Unknown: How many squares is it?
c01314
Wellby: Eight
c01315
DM: ... are minions,
c01316
DM: but there are 20 of them.
c01317
DM: So somebody put down-
c01318
Seeker: Oh, what a perfect token for that.
c01319
DM: Somebody put down 20 minions.
c01320
Unknown: From the dungeon.
c01321
Delwath: Are they just like-
c01322
DM: They're just sort of scattered all around, emerging up through the floor.
c01323
DM: Put them in like, put them in three big clumps.
c01324
Delwath: I'm not really counting them, so...
c01325
DM: Meanwhile-
c01326
Unknown: So here's seven
c01327
DM: ... Adam, tell me what you roll for initiative.
c01328
Unknown: 22 for me.
c01329
Delwath: Uh, 13. That's seven, eight, nine, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18.
c01330
DM: Okay, so-
c01331
Unknown: 19, 20.
c01332
DM: Uh-
c01333
Unknown: I mean, do we, uh,
c01334
Delwath: do we fight them or like just...
c01335
Delwath: I guess we should probably-
c01336
DM: Yeah, that looks perfect.
c01337
DM: So they're all... There's an illusion on the floor, which normally would have kept them concealed and allowed them to ambush anybody who enters the room.
c01338
DM: Um,
c01339
DM: you of course saw through the illusion.
c01340
DM: However, they're still emerging up to attack you.
c01341
DM: Um, Wellby is first.
c01342
Wellby: Do we want to fight them or we just want to go?
c01343
DM: Go where?
c01344
Unknown: To the door.
c01345
Unknown: Uh, through the door.
c01346
DM: Okay.
c01347
Unknown: I mean-
c01348
DM: We'll come back to you in a minute.
c01349
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c01350
DM: What did you roll on your persuasion check?
c01351
Seeker: Uh, that's a 10-
c01352
Unknown: 15
c01353
Seeker: ... plus five, 15.
c01354
DM: Okay.
c01355
DM: I,
c01356
DM: I mean-
c01357
Unknown: Do I inspire that or?
c01358
DM: Let's r-
c01359
Delwath: Uh, I mean we can get to the door super easy.
c01360
Unknown: I feel like we're gonna go combat. One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
c01361
Unknown: Well, that'll be...
c01362
Seeker: Yeah, it's not great.
c01363
Kenzo: This is me and you, you know.
c01364
Unknown: Yeah.
c01365
Unknown: What's your move? Oh, your move.
c01366
Delwath: 60. Delwath is all of a sudden super fast.
c01367
Wellby: Can See the Blind could even go around.
c01368
Kenzo: Yeah. One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
c01369
DM: All right, I use my inspiration, right?
c01370
Delwath: But I don't know. I don't know if that might go before Delwath is the problem.
c01371
Kenzo: Well, you can do another dimension door, right?
c01372
Delwath: So getting swarmed is the downside.
c01373
Kenzo: Like theoretically you could cast another spell.
c01374
Wellby: Would you roll for initiative?
c01375
Seeker: Oh, 'cause we think it works.
c01376
Unknown: So 13.
c01377
Kenzo: It clearly... Yeah, it, it did.
c01378
Unknown: At least some of it.
c01379
Delwath: So it might be worse.
c01380
Unknown: Let's just take another one.
c01381
Kenzo: So that's another back, backdoor out.
c01382
Unknown: Take them out.
c01383
Delwath: Or at least, at least like try and take it down a little bit and then next turn run for the door.
c01384
Kenzo: I, I think we try to just be really charming.
c01385
Unknown: All right, all right. Let's, let's do charming.
c01386
Unknown: All right.
c01387
Seeker: Do you have any areas under 12?
c01388
Wellby: Not really.
c01389
DM: I think it's DC 10.
c01390
Wellby: I have a lightning arrow, but it's a line rather than-
c01391
Unknown: Yeah, that's not great.
c01392
DM: You pick one. Take the highest.
c01393
Seeker: I inspire myself.
c01394
Unknown: You got 20.
c01395
Seeker: 15 plus 5. Yeah, it's 20.
c01396
Unknown: 20, 20. 20 persuasion.
c01397
DM: 20? Okay.
c01398
Unknown: Yeah.
c01399
Delwath: Oh, you used one of your persuasion, your, uh-
c01400
Seeker: Yeah. Yeah.
c01401
DM: Good job.
c01402
Seeker: Kong persuaded me to persuade.
c01403
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. I think, I think it's gonna be...
c01404
Kenzo: That this is otherwise we want to-
c01405
DM: Okay. So Wellby's up first. What are you doing?
c01406
Unknown: Uh, I'm gonna go for the door.
c01407
Kenzo: We also don't know what's under the ash below us, you know?
c01408
Unknown: And I think combat-
c01409
Unknown: Yes
c01410
Kenzo: ... is gonna be not a good situation for us, you know?
c01411
Unknown: Yep. We're a good-
c01412
Unknown: One, two, three, four-
c01413
Seeker: The two of us are a good team, but-
c01414
DM: Are you using-
c01415
Unknown: [laughs] It's definitely that
c01416
DM: ... bonus action disengage, or are you gonna just take the opportunity attacks or try and dodge?
c01417
Wellby: I am gonna bonus action boots of speed and not come near them.
c01418
DM: Okay.
c01419
Wellby: One, two, three, four, five, six,
c01420
Unknown: six, seven, eight-
c01421
Unknown: Where's the door?
c01422
Wellby: ... nine, 10, 11, 12, 13, something like that.
c01423
DM: Okay.
c01424
Unknown: Where's the door?
c01425
Wellby: Uh, I think I'm standing right in front of it now.
c01426
Delwath: Yeah. Oh, yeah. I could get there too.
c01427
DM: Uh, you're gonna push the door open?
c01428
Unknown: Is it locked?
c01429
DM: No.
c01430
Delwath: [laughs] You...
c01431
Unknown: This was your call.
c01432
Delwath: Delwath looks at you like, "Dude, you ran for the door and you're not opening it?"
c01433
Unknown: [laughs]
c01434
Wellby: I don't know, something about the way you said it just made me pause.
c01435
Unknown: [laughs]
c01436
Delwath: You could just turn and fight them if you want.
c01437
Wellby: You're gonna push the door? Of course, yeah, of course I'm gonna push the door open.
c01438
DM: Okay.
c01439
Unknown: Make the checks.
c01440
DM: You push the door open.
c01441
DM: You are talking to these...
c01442
DM: We'll come back to you in a minute.
c01443
Unknown: Oh, nice.
c01444
DM: You still have your action.
c01445
Unknown: Nice.
c01446
DM: You're talking to, um, these two guards and they're like-
c01447
Delwath: It's not a good sign that you need to know that you still have your action.
c01448
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
c01449
DM: Uh, they're, they're like, they're listening to you and you're being very...
c01450
DM: You, Seeker is like talking about how, just like riffing and making stuff up about-
c01451
Kenzo: Just yeah, we're, we're guests. We're, we're here.
c01452
DM: We're guests.
c01453
DM: We're here. Um, and they're like, "Maybe they are, um...
c01454
DM: Okay, well at least you came to the front door.
c01455
Delwath: It's good of you.
c01456
DM: Um, we'll let you in."
c01457
DM: The moment they say that the door swings open and you see Wellby-
c01458
Unknown: [laughs]
c01459
c01460
Unknown: [laughs]
c01461
Wellby: And someone's, someone's like, "They're ready for you.
c01462
Unknown: Come on in, guys."
c01463
Unknown: [laughs]
c01464
DM: [laughs] Uh, do you want to do anything with your action?
c01465
DM: And their, their look of their face like, "Do you know these intruders?"
c01466
Unknown: To them? [laughs]
c01467
DM: No, to you.
c01468
Unknown: Yeah.
c01469
DM: Do you know these intruders?
c01470
Kenzo: No. No. We have no idea who they are.
c01471
Unknown: [laughs]
c01472
Wellby: We're not intruders, we work here.
c01473
Kenzo: [laughs] What?
c01474
Wellby: I'm just trying to persuade them that it's okay for us to be there.
c01475
Unknown: What are you doing?
c01476
DM: Ah, that would be your action.
c01477
DM: It's not gonna be an easy roll.
c01478
Unknown: More than a 20, you think?
c01479
DM: Yeah. I mean, you're trying to persuade them that you teleported inside the tower as a halfling and you are supposed to be there.
c01480
Unknown: Well, I guess that's tricky.
c01481
Unknown: Um-
c01482
Unknown: Fuck.
c01483
DM: I mean, maybe if you looked like a chaos elemental or something.
c01484
Seeker: We should have just said that they were with us-
c01485
Unknown: Ah [laughs]
c01486
Seeker: ... because they already trust us-
c01487
DM: Uh
c01488
Seeker: ... enough to open the door.
c01489
Wellby: There's no other way out of this room?
c01490
Delwath: Well, presumably there is somewhere.
c01491
DM: There are four pillars.
c01492
DM: There's a purple orb.
c01493
DM: That's the... That's all you see in there.
c01494
DM: You're sure there's no other doors.
c01495
Unknown: Did you look up?
c01496
Unknown: Yeah.
c01497
Unknown: Uh.
c01498
Seeker: What, what's, what's the ceiling?
c01499
Delwath: Can you, like, hide?
c01500
Wellby: Yeah, I'm gonna [laughs]...
c01501
Delwath: Hide. And then you guys just say, "Wait, what people?"
c01502
Unknown: [laughs]
c01503
DM: I'm gonna close the door [laughs].
c01504
Unknown: No, no, no.
c01505
Unknown: [laughs]
c01506
Delwath: No, they have to run in.
c01507
Unknown: [laughs]
c01508
Delwath: Seriously, hide.
c01509
Unknown: Yeah.
c01510
Unknown: Isn't it...
c01511
Delwath: Oh, no, it's an illusion, never mind.
c01512
DM: Ah.
c01513
Unknown: So he can say whatever.
c01514
DM: These pillars of fire
c01515
DM: are... There's darkness around each of those pillars.
c01516
DM: Like in a five-foot radius around each pillar it would be pitch black.
c01517
Seeker: So you could run-
c01518
DM: Not for you, because you have true sight.
c01519
Unknown: Right
c01520
DM: ... but for anybody who doesn't have true sight.
c01521
DM: You could, like, run into the illusion and hide inside it.
c01522
Wellby: Yes. I will do that and, um-
c01523
Unknown: How much move do you have left?
c01524
Wellby: Uh, let's think about this.
c01525
Unknown: Um,
c01526
Wellby: one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, uh, eight, nine, ten.
c01527
Unknown: 11.
c01528
c01529
Unknown: What's your speed?
c01530
DM: Wait, why won't they see Delwath?
c01531
Unknown: Uh.
c01532
Delwath: Well, I'm gonna have an action very soon.
c01533
DM: Oh, yeah,
c01534
DM: yeah.
c01535
Unknown: Uh, 90.
c01536
Delwath: [laughs] I mean, yes, they'll see Delwath at the moment.
c01537
Wellby: Yeah, so I still have, like, uh...
c01538
Unknown: This is great
c01539
Unknown: ... 90.
c01540
Unknown: It's totally gonna work.
c01541
Wellby: What, I have, like, 35 feet of movement, so-
c01542
Unknown: It's totally gonna work
c01543
Unknown: ... I still...
c01544
DM: It, it might work
c01545
Delwath: ... so one, two, three, four, five, six.
c01546
Unknown: Yeah.
c01547
Unknown: Yeah, you can easily make it.
c01548
Unknown: Yeah.
c01549
DM: Yeah. So, um, there's no reason to roll because you cannot fail your DC 15 check to hide, but roll so I know what the DC is for somebody to find you.
c01550
Wellby: Uh, this is my good skill.
c01551
Wellby: That's a 29.
c01552
Seeker: Okay, so nobody's gonna find you.
c01553
Kenzo: So then it's like,
c01554
Kenzo: what are you talking about? Like, there's...
c01555
Kenzo: I don't... We don't see anything. Yeah.
c01556
DM: Uh, do you wanna use your action for anything?
c01557
Wellby: I think I have to use my action to hide.
c01558
Delwath: You can't bonus action hide?
c01559
Wellby: No, bonus action to activate the boots of speed.
c01560
DM: Oh, yeah, so you have to use your action to hide.
c01561
Unknown: Yeah.
c01562
DM: Great. Okay. Um,
c01563
DM: uh, sorry Delwath,
c01564
DM: um, two of the groups of minions beat you,
c01565
DM: so they are going to-
c01566
Kenzo: Wait, but do the centaurs now, are they cool?
c01567
Kenzo: Are they... Or is this, uh-
c01568
DM: No, they're like, like, "What the hell is happening?"
c01569
DM: Yeah.
c01570
Kenzo: But then we're like, uh, n- like s- like there's, there's nothing, nobody's here.
c01571
DM: Um.
c01572
Seeker: And the, the door is still open or swinging shut?
c01573
DM: Yeah, yeah, it's still open.
c01574
DM: Uh, so that's going one, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
c01575
Seeker: Yeah, we play dumb.
c01576
DM: Um.
c01577
Unknown: What do you mean?
c01578
DM: That's, uh-
c01579
Unknown: What are you talking about?
c01580
DM: ...
c01581
DM: 23 to hit.
c01582
Unknown: What was the name of the... Potions?
c01583
Unknown: I'll cast Shield.
c01584
Seeker: Yeah, it was, uh, uh, something like that.
c01585
DM: Um, ooh, that's
c01586
DM: worse, so the second one misses too.
c01587
DM: Oh, they rolled very poorly for you.
c01588
Unknown: Delwath's up?
c01589
DM: Delwath's up. So the two groups of minions behind you and in front of you each shoot this, like, massive-
c01590
Delwath: Are they moving towards me or just...?
c01591
DM: They're not moving.
c01592
Unknown: Oh.
c01593
DM: Each one blast in a 30-foot...
c01594
DM: They're both within 30 feet of you, so each one sent a blast of, like, stone water that looks like it would have really hurt if it had hit you, but you managed to
c01595
DM: dodge out of the way of both of them thanks to their
c01596
DM: seven and two rolls.
c01597
Delwath: Uh, actually,
c01598
Delwath: yeah, I'll go there.
c01599
Delwath: Uh, and then, um, a- attack.
c01600
DM: Okay, so you're stepping inside the illusion of darkness?
c01601
Unknown: Yeah.
c01602
DM: Okay.
c01603
Unknown: Uh.
c01604
Unknown: Wait, you're gonna attack or you're gonna hide?
c01605
Unknown: Well-
c01606
Kenzo: 'Cause the centaurs right now, if they don't see you guys-
c01607
DM: Yeah
c01608
Kenzo: ... then they're, then they're, they'll be like, "Okay, cool, go ahead," and they'll close the door and then the f- well, the four of us will be together.
c01609
Unknown: If you attack-
c01610
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. All right
c01611
Kenzo: ... then the centaurs are gonna be like, "Oh, fuck."
c01612
Unknown: Sure, sure, sure.
c01613
Unknown: Like, who the fuck are these?
c01614
Delwath: I won't attack.
c01615
Seeker: Stay cool. Yeah. Hide.
c01616
Kenzo: Be hidden.
c01617
DM: I'll just... I, yeah, fine.
c01618
Unknown: I will just hide.
c01619
DM: Okay.
c01620
Delwath: Although, I assume, again, I'm hidden behind...
c01621
Delwath: The centaurs presumably can't see me.
c01622
DM: No, they can't see you, but make a-
c01623
Unknown: Yeah
c01624
DM: ... make
c01625
DM: a stealth check anyway.
c01626
Unknown: Mm, five.
c01627
Unknown: Uh.
c01628
Delwath: Got a little better than that. Uh,
c01629
Unknown: uh.
c01630
Kenzo: Good thing the centaurs have-
c01631
Unknown: Uh, six.
c01632
DM: Okay.
c01633
Kenzo: Good thing the centaurs have bad vision.
c01634
Unknown: [laughs]
c01635
Delwath: Well, I'm in darkness.
c01636
Kenzo: Yeah, I'm in darkness.
c01637
DM: He's in darkness.
c01638
Wellby: And also obscured in line of sight, too, from the pillars.
c01639
DM: He's far enough away from the centaurs that they can't see him, but he's not well enough hidden that the minions-
c01640
Unknown: Right
c01641
DM: ... didn't hear him stomp into the-
c01642
Unknown: Right.
c01643
DM: So the last round of minions might attempt to attack him, although it will be at a disadvantage because you are unseen but they know where you are.
c01644
Delwath: But I'm also not within 30 feet.
c01645
Delwath: Well, you can't move faster.
c01646
Delwath: Yes, I know. I know. [laughs]
c01647
Unknown: Not, not your way of thinking.
c01648
Unknown: A lot, a lot of things.
c01649
DM: The, the centaur, the two, like, weird m- semi-metallic centaurs outside, um,
c01650
DM: turn and look at you. "This is, this is very irregular.
c01651
DM: They're... The,
c01652
DM: the stone drops wouldn't be so agitated if something wasn't in that room.
c01653
DM: I...
c01654
DM: We have to go at least tell people what's happening.
c01655
DM: Maybe you just wait here for a moment?"
c01656
Unknown: Well, we're, we're late.
c01657
DM: "We'll, we'll go in and let them know."
c01658
Kenzo: We're late. We're late 'cause our appointment is late, so we'll see you later, but I think there's nothing irregular here that I can tell.
c01659
Seeker: Well, we can, we can report on the stone drop activity, uh, to the boss when we, when we get inside.
c01660
DM: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
c01661
Kenzo: Yeah, I think that's, I think that's the right thing to do.
c01662
DM: That... We, um, no.
c01663
DM: It's in- imperative.
c01664
DM: I, I must tell... Uh, yeah, no.
c01665
DM: Um.
c01666
Unknown: We'll, we'll see-
c01667
Wellby: That's not, that's not bad though 'cause if they go in and you...
c01668
Wellby: Like, they can show us how to use the elevator.
c01669
DM: Go, go, go ahead and wait in the antechamber and when it's safe-
c01670
Unknown: Okay. Okay
c01671
DM: ... we'll send you up.
c01672
Kenzo: Okay. Sounds great.
c01673
DM: Meanwhile, these... What is that?
c01674
DM: Those six move, like, 30 feet closer-
c01675
Unknown: [laughs]
c01676
DM: ... and launch a bolt of stone at Delwath.
c01677
DM: Ugh That's 14 plus, that's 25.
c01678
Unknown: Misses.
c01679
DM: So that deflects off of Delwath's shield
c01680
Unknown: I cast shield.
c01681
Unknown: Ah.
c01682
Delwath: So I have a 26 AC.
c01683
Unknown: Damn.
c01684
DM: Nice. Um, we have-
c01685
Wellby: Do you guys just try and kill the centaur things before they go up, or
c01686
Unknown: just let them go so that-
c01687
DM: The, the two...
c01688
Delwath: The centaurs have-
c01689
DM: I don't a- I don't actually have centaurs.
c01690
DM: I have like stone, stone people here.
c01691
DM: Um,
c01692
DM: where did they go?
c01693
DM: Oh, here they are.
c01694
Kenzo: Remember, there's something buried in the ash outside, too.
c01695
Unknown: Yep.
c01696
Seeker: Yeah, we better go in.
c01697
Wellby: Also, somewhere in this structure is a ladder.
c01698
Unknown: Yeah.
c01699
Kenzo: Yeah, a ladder. We still need to do
c01700
Unknown: So these two things-
c01701
DM: Oh, and then there's Seeker
c01702
Unknown: ... come through
c01703
DM: Somewhere
c01704
DM: They like wave at the, wave at these, um, like droplets of stone.
c01705
DM: Uh, yeah, where did, where did...
c01706
DM: I wrote down where Seeker and, and then the other one showed up.
c01707
Unknown: [sighs]
c01708
Kenzo: So do we kill the centaurs now, or do we let them...
c01709
Kenzo: I think we should let the doors close behind them.
c01710
DM: Yes.
c01711
Kenzo: So that whatever's hiding in the ash doesn't-
c01712
Unknown: Yeah, that's why
c01713
Unknown: ... pop out. 'Cause that's, I don't-
c01714
DM: Yeah
c01715
Kenzo: ... I feel like that's not gonna be-
c01716
Seeker: And then like 10 years from now we're all retired and getting back together again to re- reminisce, and then like suddenly poof, a ladder and Seeker 6 appears.
c01717
Unknown: [laughs]
c01718
Unknown: Guys.
c01719
DM: Um, the ladder and-
c01720
Unknown: We're trying to find the relic
c01721
DM: ...
c01722
DM: Seeker 6 might
c01723
DM: con- well, we'll see what, I'll see what happens.
c01724
Wellby: Can we communicate with them telepathically?
c01725
Unknown: Yeah, we can tell them what's going on.
c01726
DM: No, now we're all inside. Yeah, yeah.
c01727
DM: You, you actually-
c01728
Unknown: Are they alive?
c01729
DM: Um,
c01730
DM: uh, they are [laughs]...
c01731
Unknown: Uh-oh
c01732
DM: Um, hold on. Let me-
c01733
Unknown: Yeah
c01734
DM: ... let me do things in order. Um, so,
c01735
DM: so they step in. They're like shooing,
c01736
DM: shooing the-
c01737
Unknown: The minions
c01738
DM: ... the, the minions. Um,
c01739
DM: they walk through.
c01740
DM: Um,
c01741
DM: they-
c01742
Delwath: Wait, wait. Hold on, hold on.
c01743
DM: Yeah?
c01744
Delwath: Well, no, what the... I mean, I'm just... Are we gonna, uh,
c01745
Unknown: kill them or are you-
c01746
DM: They're walking through. They're shooing the minions off to the side, so the minions like-
c01747
Kenzo: I think like let's let 'em, let's let 'em walk through for now.
c01748
DM: Move-
c01749
Delwath: But we don't want them to tell anybody we're here
c01750
DM: ... move away.
c01751
Unknown: That's true.
c01752
Unknown: That's true. Fuck.
c01753
Delwath: No, don't let 'em... We... They can't like get to the orb and send on their little communicators, "Intruders!
c01754
Unknown: Intruders!"
c01755
Seeker: W- wait till they're between you.
c01756
DM: Yeah.
c01757
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c01758
Unknown: Yeah.
c01759
Unknown: Am- ambush them.
c01760
Kenzo: All right. Fine.
c01761
Unknown: Yeah.
c01762
Kenzo: Yeah, I think you're, yeah, you're right.
c01763
DM: Okay. Uh,
c01764
DM: let's, let me, let me...
c01765
DM: I gotta see. What, what can-
c01766
Unknown: This ended up being the perfect trap.
c01767
Seeker: Well, it's... We executed it flawlessly, right?
c01768
Kenzo: Yeah. This is, this is exactly how we planned it.
c01769
Unknown: Is that what we planned?
c01770
Kenzo: This was, this was exactly what we drew up.
c01771
Kenzo: You guys teleport in first.
c01772
Unknown: [laughs]
c01773
Kenzo: We lure them in with our charisma, and then we've got them surrounded and we kill them.
c01774
DM: Exactly.
c01775
DM: Um-
c01776
Unknown: Close.
c01777
Unknown: Yeah, we drew it up.
c01778
DM: Okay. What can, what can, uh,
c01779
DM: what can Seeker 6 do?
c01780
DM: Hold on.
c01781
DM: Um...
c01782
Unknown: Do you have to resolve Seeker 6 right now?
c01783
DM: Well, if you're gonna ask-
c01784
Unknown: Oh
c01785
DM: ... what's happening with Seeker 6, I have to figure out what Seeker 6 is doing.
c01786
Unknown: That's true.
c01787
Wellby: Do we have advantage attacking from hiding?
c01788
Unknown: Yeah.
c01789
DM: Yep.
c01790
Unknown: Sweet.
c01791
DM: Okay, so are you at...
c01792
DM: Let me add them.
c01793
DM: Why don't we add everybody to the initiative count here?
c01794
DM: Um, it...
c01795
DM: We'll say it's gonna just start again at the top.
c01796
DM: Well, they rolled very badly here.
c01797
DM: Um, they shut the door behind them, so whatever's hiding outside is not-
c01798
Delwath: But you guys are like here.
c01799
Unknown: Yep.
c01800
DM: You two are right in the-
c01801
Unknown: This is, this is ideal.
c01802
Unknown: Yeah.
c01803
DM: Yeah.
c01804
Unknown: Roll initiative.
c01805
Delwath: Kenzo and Seeker, just to get in the slot.
c01806
Seeker: [dice rolling] All right.
c01807
DM: Uh, 17.
c01808
Kenzo: Ooh, plus 11. [dice rolling] 28.
c01809
Wellby: Can you Soul Sight at the top?
c01810
Unknown: Yeah.
c01811
Unknown: Thank you.
c01812
Kenzo: I've, I've already Soul Sighted the centaurs.
c01813
Delwath: Oh, did you Soul Sight the centaurs?
c01814
DM: Well, you presumably must have as soon as you-
c01815
Unknown: Yeah. Yep
c01816
Delwath: What's their deal, then?
c01817
DM: Um, they are CR 10.
c01818
DM: They're immune to poison,
c01819
DM: exhaustion, frightened, petrified, and poisoned conditions.
c01820
DM: They resist fire damage.
c01821
DM: They're good at strength. They're not very smart.
c01822
Unknown: We got this.
c01823
DM: Okay. Um, 17 was Seeker.
c01824
Unknown: Yeah.
c01825
DM: And they have
c01826
DM: a zero. Oof.
c01827
DM: Okay.
c01828
DM: [dice rolling]
c01829
Unknown: Please eat these.
c01830
Kenzo: Oh, they're like Swedish Fish but-
c01831
Unknown: Yeah
c01832
Unknown: ... Seeker Fish.
c01833
Seeker: Scandinavian swimmers.
c01834
Delwath: They're Trader Joe's knockoff Swedish Fish.
c01835
DM: Um, meanwhile, um, you hear from
c01836
DM: Seeker 6,
c01837
DM: uh-
c01838
Unknown: Okay
c01839
DM: ... uh, we,
c01840
DM: we showed up in a library of sorts.
c01841
Unknown: Hmm.
c01842
DM: Uh, it's not great.
c01843
DM: Um, there's like a weird violet orb here and some desks and, um, two,
c01844
DM: uh, people trying to kill us.
c01845
DM: I made a wall of stone and we're hiding behind it, but I don't know how long it's gonna last.
c01846
Unknown: What kind of people are trying to kill you?
c01847
DM: Um, well,
c01848
DM: one of them,
c01849
DM: one of them is like a, uh...
c01850
DM: I don't know how to describe it exactly other to say that it's like metallic blood.
c01851
Unknown: Oh, they're Chaos Metal.
c01852
Unknown: Hmm. Hmm?
c01853
DM: No, it's like blood that's solidified into metal with a giant like pointy polearm.
c01854
Unknown: Oh.
c01855
DM: Um, with lots of spikes that seem to be made out of
c01856
DM: glass or water,
c01857
DM: water spikes. They look very sharp.
c01858
Delwath: Sounds pleasant.
c01859
DM: Um, the other one-
c01860
Unknown: Shrike from Japan
c01861
DM: ...
c01862
DM: uh, the other one is, um,
c01863
DM: like
c01864
DM: it looks like...
c01865
DM: ... weird.
c01866
DM: It's all like shiny dark,
c01867
DM: but there's like
c01868
DM: jagged lines of light and lightning that,
c01869
DM: uh, drift through it and it has a head that looks like a mini sun.
c01870
Unknown: [laughs] What the fuck?
c01871
Seeker: It's pretty generous to call these things people.
c01872
Unknown: [laughs]
c01873
DM: Um [laughs].
c01874
Kenzo: That was a really good description. That was great.
c01875
Kenzo: That was like charades. It was like very-
c01876
Wellby: I mean, this is a ladder and a snowman.
c01877
Unknown: [laughs]
c01878
DM: [laughs] Fair point.
c01879
Kenzo: [laughs] We're generous in- This is, this is like the Spiderman meme except it's like [laughs] like a ladder and then [laughs].
c01880
DM: Yeah.
c01881
DM: [laughs] Um, well,
c01882
Delwath: well, well hopefully they're like, if they're right above us, if this orb goes up to that orb.
c01883
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah, there seems to be some kind of teleportation or transition.
c01884
Delwath: Yeah, no. Let's um, let's um, let's try and get there soon.
c01885
Delwath: I mean we, we should probably, uh, kill these guys.
c01886
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c01887
DM: Mm-hmm.
c01888
Seeker: Yeah. Just, uh, hold tight.
c01889
Unknown: We'll be there soon.
c01890
DM: We're taking the risks.
c01891
Delwath: Or never.
c01892
DM: [laughs]
c01893
Kenzo: And, uh, have we lost contact with Rai,
c01894
Unknown: Telepath?
c01895
DM: We've lost contact with Rai.
c01896
Unknown: Yeah.
c01897
DM: Can we still see the chain?
c01898
Unknown: No.
c01899
Seeker: Could we see it from just outside the tower?
c01900
DM: Yes, but it sort of faded into a mist somewhere in the vicinity.
c01901
Unknown: It
c01902
DM: didn't tell you where the thing was in the tower.
c01903
DM: Yeah.
c01904
DM: Uh, so Kenzo's first.
c01905
Kenzo: I feel a little bad now killing these guys.
c01906
Kenzo: They were pretty nice to let us in. Um-
c01907
Wellby: Swap with me first and then you'll get advantage.
c01908
Unknown: Swap with, uh, Wellby.
c01909
DM: No, that's only the first round of combat.
c01910
DM: This is like the second round of combat.
c01911
Wellby: Swap with me first. I'll try and blind both of them and whichever one I succeed in blinding you'll have advantage.
c01912
Unknown: Swap with Wellby.
c01913
DM: Okay.
c01914
Wellby: Uh.
c01915
Unknown: [laughs]
c01916
DM: So Wellby's first.
c01917
Wellby: All right. Uh, I'm gonna sneak attack both of them.
c01918
Wellby: Uh, 26.
c01919
Wellby: And I'll check for a crit.
c01920
Wellby: And then that's not great.
c01921
Wellby: 15, uh, 21.
c01922
Wellby: 26 and 21.
c01923
DM: Both hits.
c01924
Wellby: Awesome. Both of them get a DC 19 dex save.
c01925
Unknown: For the blinded?
c01926
Wellby: Yep.
c01927
DM: Um,
c01928
DM: oh whoops. I'm looking at the wrong stat block.
c01929
Unknown: For both.
c01930
DM: I don't think they have that good of dex.
c01931
DM: Yeah, they both, uh, they both fail.
c01932
Unknown: They're both blinded?
c01933
Wellby: Yep. Plus 31 damage on one.
c01934
Wellby: And okay, that's decent rolling.
c01935
Wellby: Uh, 10, 22, 26 damage on the other.
c01936
DM: 26 and 31.
c01937
Delwath: Are they actually this size? They're large?
c01938
DM: Yeah, they're both large.
c01939
Unknown: Okay.
c01940
DM: Uh, that
c01941
DM: ends your... You still have a bonus action?
c01942
Wellby: Mm, I guess I'll move. Uh, no, no, no.
c01943
Wellby: I want to stay in-
c01944
DM: Hide. Hide.
c01945
Wellby: I'm still obscured, right? 'Cause I'm in magical darkness.
c01946
DM: Yep.
c01947
Wellby: So yeah.
c01948
Delwath: But attacking reveals your position, so you should hide.
c01949
DM: I know where you are. You can hide again.
c01950
Wellby: I'll go over there and hide there.
c01951
DM: Okay.
c01952
DM: So make another...
c01953
DM: Not that it matters.
c01954
Wellby: Well, it's one re-roll.
c01955
Wellby: That's a 17 plus 17 is 34.
c01956
DM: You're hidden again.
c01957
DM: Uh,
c01958
DM: Kenzo?
c01959
Unknown: Yes.
c01960
DM: Blind is 'til the start of your turn or the end of their turn?
c01961
Wellby: End of its next turn.
c01962
DM: Okay.
c01963
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo will, uh, roll up.
c01964
Seeker: Summon gigantic guns.
c01965
Kenzo: [laughs] And, uh, attack this guy
c01966
Unknown: in the front.
c01967
DM: Okay.
c01968
Unknown: Um,
c01969
Kenzo: and yeah, I don't need to waste special things on these guys, right?
c01970
Unknown: No, I wouldn't.
c01971
DM: So that-
c01972
Unknown: I'm only renewable
c01973
DM: ... that one, the one that's silvery, I'm calling that one, um, Centaur One.
c01974
DM: The one that's more gold-y and bigger, I'm calling Centaur Two.
c01975
Kenzo: No, no. That one's called Goldie and the first one's called Bob.
c01976
Kenzo: All right. So I'm gonna attack Bob first.
c01977
DM: So Centaur One is Bob and Centaur Two is Goldie?
c01978
Kenzo: Yes. All right. Bob, I'm attacking with my staff.
c01979
DM: Advantage 'cause it's blind.
c01980
Kenzo: Yeah, okay. Advantage 'cause it's blind.
c01981
Unknown: So it's plus 13.
c01982
Kenzo: That's pretty cool.
c01983
Unknown: Uh, 24.
c01984
DM: Yep. Roll your damage at the same time so it-
c01985
Kenzo: Oh, okay, okay, okay. These guys are creatures of Limbo, yes?
c01986
DM: Yes.
c01987
Unknown: D12.
c01988
Kenzo: Uh, so that's, uh, 12 damage on the first attack.
c01989
DM: Very nice.
c01990
Kenzo: Second attack.
c01991
Kenzo: Oh, natural, a crit.
c01992
Kenzo: So then I roll this again? Yep.
c01993
DM: Yep.
c01994
Kenzo: So three plus
c01995
Kenzo: nine is 12, plus seven.
c01996
DM: 19.
c01997
Kenzo: Yes. Oh. Oh wait, but I'm also doing the, the, uh, the aura focus thing.
c01998
Kenzo: So I also get an extra D12, right?
c01999
Unknown: Yes.
c02000
DM: Well, which you're...
c02001
DM: Yeah, yeah. You can-
c02002
Unknown: Yeah
c02003
DM: ... that's once per turn you can do an extra D12.
c02004
Kenzo: All right. So I'll do that right now. So that was 19 plus
c02005
Kenzo: another two, so that's 21.
c02006
DM: Okay.
c02007
Unknown: Um,
c02008
Kenzo: third attack.
c02009
Kenzo: Oh shit, I'm also realizing fuck I forgot to activate my tattoo.
c02010
DM: Well, I don't know that you'd bother activating your tattoo for this.
c02011
Kenzo: Yeah, that's true. All right. I won't do that.
c02012
Kenzo: All right. So, so this is the third attack.
c02013
Kenzo: Oh, 19. That's really good.
c02014
Kenzo: That definitely hits. Oh shit, I forgot to roll this.
c02015
Unknown: Uh, four.
c02016
Kenzo: That's another,
c02017
Kenzo: uh, nine damage.
c02018
Kenzo: Oh, the D12 is only once. Okay.
c02019
DM: Yeah.
c02020
Kenzo: Okay. Fourth attack.
c02021
DM: That was another how much damage?
c02022
Unknown: Uh, nine damage.
c02023
DM: Okay.
c02024
Unknown: Fourth attack
c02025
Kenzo: Oh no, I think I missed. Fuck. Wait.
c02026
Unknown: Oh, actually no, no. Uh, does 18 hit?
c02027
DM: 18 misses.
c02028
Kenzo: Damn. All right, and then last attack.
c02029
Unknown: Uh,
c02030
Kenzo: 23 hits.
c02031
DM: Yep.
c02032
Kenzo: Oh, and that's eight plus five, 13 damage.
c02033
DM: Okay. So Kenzo
c02034
DM: rushes in whirling with his staff on this creature which turns around in shock and surprise looking at you like, "I thought we were friends."
c02035
Unknown: [laughs]
c02036
Unknown: [laughs] Kenzo's like, "I'm so sorry."
c02037
Unknown: [laughs]
c02038
Wellby: Bob, I'm so sorry.
c02039
Delwath: But it, it can't see Kenzo at the moment.
c02040
Unknown: It's blind.
c02041
DM: Yeah, yeah. No.
c02042
Delwath: It doesn't know what's hitting it.
c02043
DM: True.
c02044
Unknown: Yeah, but still, I mean-
c02045
DM: It still kinda knows.
c02046
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. And I... Kenzo's still really sorry.
c02047
Unknown: Like, I'm sorry, dude.
c02048
DM: Seeker's up.
c02049
Unknown: Be like, be like, "The things are attacking you.
c02050
Unknown: It's not me."
c02051
Seeker: Sorry, Bob. I, um,
c02052
Seeker: summon construct at fourth level.
c02053
Delwath: Fourth level, fifth level.
c02054
Delwath: Lasts for an hour?
c02055
Unknown: Yeah.
c02056
Unknown: Yeah, fifth level I think.
c02057
Unknown: Fifth level.
c02058
Seeker: I summon construct at fifth level.
c02059
Seeker: Where are you, construct? There you are.
c02060
Seeker: And can I just drop him in between these guys or does he not fit there?
c02061
DM: Uh-
c02062
Unknown: 15
c02063
DM: ... he needs to occupy a s- yeah, he can fit there.
c02064
DM: They're both large, so he can't fit in between them.
c02065
Unknown: Yeah, that's good.
c02066
Seeker: And he is gonna be...
c02067
Seeker: Where is everyone? Um, I'm liking the clay version.
c02068
DM: Okay.
c02069
Seeker: He's gonna be a clay construct.
c02070
Unknown: And then he-
c02071
Unknown: Which one are you?
c02072
Seeker: Half the spell's level round down is two attacks.
c02073
Unknown: Um,
c02074
Seeker: and then it's 1d8 plus four plus...
c02075
Seeker: 1d8 plus nine
c02076
Seeker: damage. All right, so
c02077
Seeker: just make my two attacks on-
c02078
Unknown: On the next one
c02079
DM: Yeah
c02080
Unknown: ... yeah
c02081
Seeker: ... on Bob.
c02082
DM: Mm-hmm.
c02083
Seeker: They're both 17s.
c02084
Delwath: You have advantage though. He's blinded.
c02085
Wellby: He rolled two d20s.
c02086
Unknown: Yeah.
c02087
Delwath: You have advantage 'cause it's like blinded.
c02088
Seeker: So does that count for one of my rolls?
c02089
Unknown: Yeah.
c02090
Unknown: 'Cause I rolled two.
c02091
DM: Yeah.
c02092
Seeker: Okay. So I roll again.
c02093
DM: Wait, are you attacking Bob or Goldie?
c02094
Unknown: Uh, Bob.
c02095
DM: All right. [laughs]
c02096
Seeker: So the first one is a 17 plus 11 is 28.
c02097
Unknown: Somebody's gonna get [laughs]...
c02098
Seeker: Oh, no. The... Is that...
c02099
Seeker: What is his attack?
c02100
Seeker: I forget how that works.
c02101
Delwath: It's... Isn't it your spell attack?
c02102
DM: It's your spell attack, yeah.
c02103
Seeker: Plus 11, yeah. Plus 1d8.
c02104
Seeker: And then that one is-
c02105
Unknown: 18
c02106
Seeker: ... uh, 29.
c02107
Unknown: With hit.
c02108
DM: Yep.
c02109
Seeker: And so then both of those are-
c02110
Delwath: It's 1d8 plus nine,
c02111
Unknown: you said?
c02112
Delwath: There's a d8. Yeah, d8.
c02113
Wellby: So would be a plus 18 then?
c02114
Unknown: Yeah.
c02115
Unknown: So that's seven.
c02116
Unknown: 25.
c02117
DM: 25 damage?
c02118
Unknown: Thank you, yep.
c02119
Delwath: All right. [sighs] Minions.
c02120
Unknown: Bob is asleep. So bad.
c02121
DM: Uh, yeah. Hold on. Um,
c02122
DM: uh...
c02123
DM: Oh, wait. Sorry. I...
c02124
DM: You were both attacking Bob, right?
c02125
Delwath: Everybody was attacking Bob.
c02126
DM: Okay. And put that down on Goldie, not Bob.
c02127
DM: But I'll change it.
c02128
Unknown: Why didn't they put a little sleep or something like that?
c02129
Unknown: It's so Dad and I was like, "Kill them."
c02130
DM: Um-
c02131
Delwath: Nah, 'cause then it's gonna wake up and warn people
c02132
Unknown: Yeah, fuck.
c02133
Unknown: Yeah, they gotta go.
c02134
DM: Man.
c02135
Delwath: They're not good people.
c02136
Unknown: How do we know?
c02137
Wellby: Do we know that?
c02138
Unknown: How do we know?
c02139
DM: This one's almost dead. Bob is almost dead.
c02140
Wellby: Good people work for bad bosses all the time.
c02141
DM: True.
c02142
Kenzo: Seriously, man.
c02143
DM: Ah.
c02144
Kenzo: Train is where they blame, not the management, you know?
c02145
Unknown: That's right. [laughs]
c02146
DM: Okay.
c02147
Unknown: [laughs]
c02148
DM: Uh, this group was-
c02149
Unknown: What Bob Goldie need is a union
c02150
DM: ... this group of minions back here,
c02151
DM: um,
c02152
DM: you're still-
c02153
Delwath: If that doesn't work, we're gonna fight
c02154
DM: ... skewed, but you're-
c02155
Kenzo: And then we just, you know.
c02156
DM: Okay, this group of minions back here is going to-
c02157
Unknown: Join us
c02158
DM: ... collapse against Seeker.
c02159
Unknown: Oh, boy.
c02160
DM: These five.
c02161
DM: Um,
c02162
DM: uh, that's a
c02163
DM: 20,
c02164
DM: 30,
c02165
DM: 32 to hit.
c02166
DM: Um, you take
c02167
DM: 50 points of bludgeoning damage.
c02168
Unknown: 50?
c02169
DM: And make a dex saving throw.
c02170
Wellby: Wait.
c02171
Wellby: What?
c02172
Delwath: That's pretty bad.
c02173
Wellby: For who?
c02174
Unknown: Who's that, whose that against?
c02175
DM: These five minions attacked...
c02176
DM: You guys gotta clean up minions.
c02177
Seeker: Um, right. Uh-
c02178
Delwath: When we, we, we're trying to hide
c02179
Wellby: Yeah, miscalculated here. Yeah
c02180
DM: ... for-
c02181
Seeker: I, I said we should fight the minions. No, no, no, no.
c02182
Kenzo: Th- they, they wouldn't have come inside until-
c02183
Wellby: Right, right, right
c02184
Kenzo: ... you asked it. So this all, we did the right thing.
c02185
Wellby: We did the right thing.
c02186
DM: No, I mean instead of attacking the two centaurs, Wellby and Kenzo could have killed...
c02187
DM: Kenzo can kill a lot of minions.
c02188
Unknown: Sure.
c02189
Wellby: That's true, yeah.
c02190
Seeker: So it's just plus eight for my saving throw for dex.
c02191
DM: Yep.
c02192
Seeker: So 21.
c02193
DM: 21.
c02194
Unknown: Solid.
c02195
Unknown: Yeah.
c02196
DM: So you remain... You are not this, like, this massive blob of stone strikes you, and you manage to hold your ground.
c02197
DM: It does not pull you down to the ground.
c02198
Unknown: Okay.
c02199
DM: Um, minion group two is gonna attack the constr- uh, actually Kenzo.
c02200
Seeker: So can a construct... Aw.
c02201
Seeker: It's all right.
c02202
Unknown: Well, it's kind of split up. It's actually gonna split into two groups.
c02203
Wellby: You want to send these over that way?
c02204
DM: So these four are gonna come to Kenzo.
c02205
Wellby: These guys?
c02206
DM: Yeah. Now these two are just gonna attack the construct.
c02207
DM: So these three, this one's gonna move.
c02208
DM: No. That one.
c02209
Unknown: S-
c02210
DM: This one's attacking the...
c02211
DM: These three are attacking the construct.
c02212
DM: Those five are attacking Kenzo.
c02213
DM: And that minion group three is-
c02214
Unknown: The construct gets a-
c02215
DM: ... has a bad initiative. They're at the end
c02216
Seeker: ... like a berserker attacks when it gets, when it takes damage or something.
c02217
DM: Um, so the construct, that's, um, t- 30 something to hit.
c02218
DM: Construct takes 30 points of damage and has to make a,
c02219
DM: um,
c02220
DM: a dex saving throw Um, and these five on you K- on Kenzo
c02221
Kenzo: Uh, I'm gonna Disappear as a...
c02222
Unknown: Why?
c02223
DM: Well, you'd have to do that during your...
c02224
DM: That takes a bonus action during your turn.
c02225
Kenzo: Oh, shit. Okay.
c02226
DM: So that's a 22, 26 to hit you.
c02227
Kenzo: That is 15.
c02228
DM: So you take 50 points of bludgeoning damage.
c02229
Unknown: Much better.
c02230
Kenzo: Except I don't.
c02231
Unknown: I'm gonna deflect.
c02232
DM: Okay.
c02233
Delwath: Man, these are scary.
c02234
Delwath: But I really wanna take these guys out so they don't-
c02235
Kenzo: Wait, but, um, can I do a deflect attack on...
c02236
Kenzo: How would that work on minions?
c02237
Unknown: But I mean-
c02238
DM: Yeah, you can deflect
c02239
Unknown: ... if I just cast a spell?
c02240
DM: You can deflect it on minions.
c02241
Kenzo: Yeah. Normally I would deflect... I would try to take the dam- you know, 'cause the damage is split up amongst a bunch of them
c02242
DM: You could... You're only... With your deflect, you can o- We are...
c02243
DM: Well, I don't think you're gonna reduce it to zero, so.
c02244
Kenzo: Well, I know, but that- that's the... The damage isn't all...
c02245
Kenzo: The damage is collective damage from all five of them, presumably anyway.
c02246
DM: Ah, no, but the way minions work is they do...
c02247
DM: It's all one hit.
c02248
Unknown: Okay.
c02249
DM: So you can deflect
c02250
DM: up to...
c02251
DM: You can reduce the full amount that you roll, but you won't reduce it to zero and do nothing.
c02252
Unknown: Um.
c02253
Unknown: Okay.
c02254
Seeker: The Clay's berserk,
c02255
Seeker: he rolled a 15.
c02256
DM: What does that mean?
c02257
Unknown: 20.
c02258
DM: I don't know what-
c02259
Wellby: Isn't it better to-
c02260
DM: This... When a spirit-
c02261
Wellby: ... like, take it as reduced by half
c02262
Seeker: ... takes a damage from a creature, the spirit makes a sling attack-
c02263
Unknown: I can uncanny dodge
c02264
Unknown: ... against that creature if possible.
c02265
DM: Oh, okay.
c02266
Unknown: So.
c02267
Unknown: I guess I rolled a four.
c02268
DM: Okay.
c02269
Kenzo: Which is, that was a 15 to hit.
c02270
DM: To hit the minion.
c02271
Unknown: Yeah.
c02272
Kenzo: That would have been impossible five years in
c02273
DM: Um, that misses the minions.
c02274
Kenzo: Okay. Huh. I can uncanny dodge, right?
c02275
DM: No.
c02276
Kenzo: Yeah. Okay. Uh, I reduced it by 25 then.
c02277
Wellby: You just... The dex save.
c02278
DM: He just has the dex then. So you take 25 points of damage.
c02279
Unknown: Oof. Okay.
c02280
DM: And that ends the minions' turns. Delwath is up.
c02281
DM: Center Bob is after Delwath.
c02282
Unknown: Center Bob. I feel bad for him.
c02283
DM: Center Bob is very badly hurt.
c02284
Wellby: Do you want to just slice up the slow group of minions?
c02285
Delwath: I mean, it's not a bad idea.
c02286
Delwath: Um, I'm just debating, do I just cast a spell that, like, hits all of them?
c02287
Kenzo: Oh, that would be nice.
c02288
Delwath: It's just a spell. One, two, three, four, five, six.
c02289
DM: Remember, spells, unless they fail their save, it doesn't auto kill them.
c02290
Delwath: What about spells that don't require...
c02291
Delwath: I took, um, Jazalli's Storm of Radiance.
c02292
DM: Okay. I don't know what that does.
c02293
Delwath: There's no save.
c02294
Unknown: Uh, oh.
c02295
Delwath: Uh, each creature makes a con saving throw, uh, taking 4d10 damage, but half as much on a successful save.
c02296
DM: So they still take damage, but m- minions have hit points.
c02297
Delwath: I know, but it's 4d10.
c02298
DM: That... Thinking how much damage they do, you might not kill them with-
c02299
Unknown: Right
c02300
DM: ... half.
c02301
Delwath: I guess, I guess they don't...
c02302
Delwath: It seems a little bit...
c02303
Unknown: They don't...
c02304
Delwath: Area of effect spells aren't extra effective against minions?
c02305
DM: No, every single one who fails a save instantly dies.
c02306
Unknown: Instantly. Okay.
c02307
DM: Anyone who succeeds on a save only dies if you beat its hit points.
c02308
Delwath: Right. But they don't...
c02309
Delwath: Do they... Are there three?
c02310
Delwath: How many, how many...
c02311
Delwath: Does each individual one take-
c02312
DM: Make a save.
c02313
Unknown: But-
c02314
DM: And, and take damage.
c02315
Unknown: Okay. Huh.
c02316
Delwath: So it's doing
c02317
Delwath: 4d10 against every single minion.
c02318
DM: Exactly. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c02319
DM: It's just if you-
c02320
Unknown: That's good
c02321
DM: ... yeah.
c02322
Delwath: Yeah, I mean, I'm burning through spells, but I can get them back.
c02323
Delwath: I have two, two shots at re- refreshing spells.
c02324
Delwath: I'm gonna cast that.
c02325
DM: Okay.
c02326
Unknown: And-
c02327
DM: How big a radius is it?
c02328
Kenzo: Let me see.
c02329
Delwath: Uh, hold on a second. It is...
c02330
Delwath: Uh, it's only... You know what? It's not...
c02331
Delwath: It's a small radius.
c02332
Delwath: It's only a 10-foot radius, so that's not actually gonna get that many of them.
c02333
Unknown: I don't know if that's worth it. It's a tiny radius.
c02334
Delwath: Sickening Radiance might be better,
c02335
Delwath: which is a huge radius.
c02336
Delwath: But could I put it...
c02337
Delwath: Man, I need the little things on the...
c02338
Unknown: On the, um...
c02339
Delwath: Neither of those are good options.
c02340
Unknown: Um,
c02341
Seeker: hold on a second. Sorry.
c02342
Delwath: 20 foot. What's a 30 foot radius?
c02343
Delwath: That's six squares.
c02344
Unknown: One, two, three, four, five.
c02345
Delwath: So I can't get everybody.
c02346
Delwath: I could get everything here.
c02347
DM: Let's hear it.
c02348
Delwath: If I, if I put it, like, there, one, two, three, four, five, six...
c02349
Delwath: If I put it there, I should be able to get everything in this section with Sickening Radiance.
c02350
Unknown: That doesn't affect me.
c02351
Delwath: I'd have to spend a thing.
c02352
Unknown: Ah, spend.
c02353
DM: It's 30 foot radius?
c02354
Delwath: Sickening is... Yeah, 30 foot radius.
c02355
DM: Yeah, so that goes from here to here.
c02356
Unknown: Right.
c02357
DM: So that would get everybody except for the five around Seeker.
c02358
Unknown: Yeah.
c02359
Delwath: Um, I mean, Sickening Radiance, uh, does no damage if they make their save, but...
c02360
DM: What's the save?
c02361
Unknown: DC 20 con.
c02362
DM: Okay.
c02363
Unknown: Um,
c02364
Delwath: yeah, I'm gonna cast that.
c02365
Unknown: I'm gonna spend...
c02366
Kenzo: Man, I don't wanna be spending all these things, but that's okay.
c02367
Unknown: Um, I... 'Cause I have to also-
c02368
DM: Mm
c02369
Unknown: ... spend a sorcery point.
c02370
DM: That is only seven minions in that one.
c02371
Seeker: Trying to figure out what to do next.
c02372
Delwath: And it gets these two guys, too.
c02373
DM: I know.
c02374
DM: Um,
c02375
DM: I just need to know for the next minion turn what's gonna happen to those minions.
c02376
DM: So-
c02377
Delwath: It actually takes effect... I mean, it happens when they start their turn.
c02378
DM: I know. That's... But I'm pre-rolling for the minion.
c02379
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. Then I'm gonna move.
c02380
DM: Okay.
c02381
Delwath: Um, one-
c02382
Kenzo: Did you kill all the minions?
c02383
Unknown: I don't know.
c02384
DM: So this, um,
c02385
DM: radian burst appears ...
c02386
DM: of sickening radiance spreading from right about here all the way to the edge of those minions.
c02387
Unknown: I guess I'll just... No, that's-
c02388
DM: Mm
c02389
Unknown: ... that's better. I'll move over there then.
c02390
DM: This, this... Okay, so next up is Bob.
c02391
Unknown: Damn it, Bob.
c02392
DM: Who is going to-
c02393
Unknown: Sorry, Bob
c02394
Delwath: Has to do the sickening radiance.
c02395
DM: I know, I've already rolled the save. He's passed the save.
c02396
DM: Uh, he's gonna like turn,
c02397
DM: um, it's the start or end of his turn?
c02398
Wellby: Uh, end of his turn.
c02399
DM: Okay, so he's still blind.
c02400
DM: Stumbling around blind just trying to wildly run away from somebody is gonna go like
c02401
DM: here.
c02402
Unknown: So we get-
c02403
Kenzo: Opportunity attack
c02404
DM: ... two, three, four, five, six-
c02405
Unknown: Opportunity attack
c02406
DM: ... seven. Yep.
c02407
Seeker: And then construct.
c02408
Wellby: Construct, too.
c02409
DM: Both of you get opportunity attacks.
c02410
Delwath: And also basically the sickening-
c02411
DM: Uh, you don't 'cause you used your reaction
c02412
Unknown: ...
c02413
Unknown: radiance just falls.
c02414
Wellby: With advantage though, construct.
c02415
DM: You used your reaction to-
c02416
Unknown: Oh, deflect
c02417
DM: ... deflect. But construct does.
c02418
Unknown: With advantage.
c02419
DM: With advantage 'cause it's blind.
c02420
Wellby: Yeah. [laughs]
c02421
Unknown: Oh.
c02422
Unknown: Last turn.
c02423
Seeker: All right, so then-
c02424
Unknown: We have some advantage
c02425
DM: That's probably gonna kill it
c02426
Seeker: ... d8 plus, what was it?
c02427
Wellby: I don't remember.
c02428
Unknown: Uh, nine.
c02429
DM: Construct.
c02430
Unknown: 2d8 last time.
c02431
Unknown: Construct.
c02432
Unknown: 2d8.
c02433
Unknown: Construct. Construct. Construct.
c02434
Unknown: Construct.
c02435
DM: Nice.
c02436
Wellby: Nice and solid.
c02437
DM: Okay. So as it begins to run it stumbles away from the construct and then
c02438
DM: falls and collapses having not got to do anything-
c02439
Unknown: Sorry, Bob
c02440
DM: ... except die to Kenzo's blows.
c02441
Unknown: Aw.
c02442
DM: Five out of those seven minions died-
c02443
Unknown: Geez
c02444
DM: ... of the sickening radiance. Yes.
c02445
Seeker: Oh, amazing.
c02446
DM: Um, the other two,
c02447
DM: uh, are going to...
c02448
DM: Wellby's still hidden.
c02449
Unknown: Feel bad.
c02450
Wellby: Yep.
c02451
DM: Um.
c02452
Seeker: [laughs] They weren't even really centaurs.
c02453
Unknown: Poor friends.
c02454
DM: Gonna move around the centaur out of its way to the right and then close in on Kenzo,
c02455
DM: and they're both gonna attack Kenzo,
c02456
DM: so that's a 20-something.
c02457
DM: So you take 20 points of d- damage.
c02458
Kenzo: Dude, why are these minions so powerful?
c02459
DM: And that ends those minions' turns.
c02460
DM: This centaur Bob is dead.
c02461
DM: Centaur Goldie,
c02462
DM: um-
c02463
Unknown: Whoa
c02464
DM: ... doesn't know because he's blind.
c02465
Unknown: He has to make a save, too.
c02466
DM: Yeah.
c02467
Wellby: Bob talks and you, "I heard something."
c02468
Wellby: [laughs]
c02469
DM: Uh, he fails.
c02470
Delwath: He takes, uh, 10, 11, 20 points of damage, radiant damage, and he suffers one level of exhaustion.
c02471
DM: He's immune to exhaustion.
c02472
Delwath: Okay. And he glows with a dim greenish light.
c02473
DM: Yep, which he can't see 'cause he's blind.
c02474
DM: Uh, he is going to turn flailing around.
c02475
DM: The nearest thing that he can hear is the construct
c02476
DM: and he's-
c02477
Unknown: Construct
c02478
Unknown: ... and he's gonna shift.
c02479
DM: Um,
c02480
DM: first of all, uh, a bunch of like metal planks just grow where this ash is bellowing out, um, armoring and protecting him.
c02481
Unknown: Ugh.
c02482
DM: And then his arm like shifts into this great blade and he's gonna swing with disadvantage-
c02483
Unknown: Oh, no, I can't spell
c02484
DM: ... uh, three times at the construct.
c02485
DM: So that's-
c02486
Wellby: It is good. We took them out first
c02487
DM: ... uh, 16.
c02488
Unknown: Yeah.
c02489
Wellby: I feel like it... Uh, we wouldn't have been better off.
c02490
DM: That's a 25. What's the construct's AC?
c02491
Kenzo: Uh, we would've been better off when?
c02492
Wellby: Getting the minions first-
c02493
Unknown: Team
c02494
Wellby: ... like-
c02495
Unknown: Yeah, we-
c02496
Wellby: ... either way it would
c02497
Unknown: ... yeah, collaborate
c02498
DM: ... uh, okay, so, uh, two hit.
c02499
Unknown: Construct, you'll be good.
c02500
DM: Um,
c02501
DM: and that does a total of 30-
c02502
Unknown: He's down
c02503
DM: ... nine points of damage.
c02504
Delwath: Yeah, he's down. Bye-bye, construct.
c02505
Seeker: You did, you did well construct.
c02506
DM: And that ends Goldie's turn.
c02507
DM: He is now not blinded.
c02508
DM: Uh, Wellby is up.
c02509
Wellby: Uh, awesome. I will, uh, shoot Goldie again, try and blind him again.
c02510
Wellby: That's a 28.
c02511
Unknown: Oops, got-
c02512
DM: That hits
c02513
Wellby: ... DC19 dex save.
c02514
DM: Not good at dex, fails.
c02515
Wellby: Uh, plus 10, 24 points of damage.
c02516
DM: However, yep, that strikes.
c02517
DM: Your arrow hits,
c02518
DM: its momentum greatly slowed by the iron armor that it's now created around itself.
c02519
DM: Um, so it only takes 12 points of damage.
c02520
Wellby: Awesome, but it's blinded.
c02521
Unknown: Yeah.
c02522
DM: Yep, blinded again.
c02523
Wellby: And then I will shoot the, um,
c02524
Wellby: I think I'll shoot the minions around Seeker.
c02525
DM: Okay.
c02526
Wellby: That makes the most sense, right?
c02527
DM: Yeah, you're not gonna get... Without sneak attack you're not gonna get any punch-through damage.
c02528
DM: But you can kill one. Oh, you can do s- two sneak attacks.
c02529
Wellby: Yep.
c02530
DM: I forgot. [laughs]
c02531
Wellby: Yep. I think so.
c02532
Wellby: That's nat- That's two natural 20s.
c02533
Wellby: [laughs]
c02534
DM: Whoa. [laughs]
c02535
Unknown: What?
c02536
Wellby: Holy shit. So that's four times the regular amount of damage.
c02537
Unknown: That's insane.
c02538
DM: Uh-
c02539
Unknown: 'Cause I rolled two natural 20s.
c02540
DM: Yeah. [laughs]
c02541
Unknown: Is it, though?
c02542
DM: You probably-
c02543
Unknown: No
c02544
DM: ... you, I mean, but-
c02545
Unknown: You'll probably kill all of them
c02546
DM: ... you can, you can... No, you can really only wing three from there.
c02547
DM: Ah, you can't... You gotta move 'cause this pillar's right in your way.
c02548
Unknown: You can't hit anything right now.
c02549
Unknown: Kill the ones next to Kenzo.
c02550
Wellby: Here. And I'll shoot through Kenzo to-
c02551
DM: But you-
c02552
Wellby: ... Seekers.
c02553
DM: Oh, okay.
c02554
Unknown: Yeah.
c02555
DM: Yeah, you can do that.
c02556
Unknown: Yeah.
c02557
DM: So you'll hit these two. You'll hit those three and these two.
c02558
Wellby: Great.
c02559
DM: See how much damage you do.
c02560
Wellby: Two or three?
c02561
Wellby: Uh, okay.
c02562
Wellby: 10 and 20, uh,
c02563
Wellby: 32
c02564
Wellby: plus-
c02565
DM: Uh, that's...
c02566
DM: Oh, you haven't finished yet.
c02567
Wellby: Yep.
c02568
Unknown: [laughs]
c02569
Wellby: Uh, 42, uh, 45, that's 50, 55, 60,
c02570
Wellby: 63 plus-
c02571
Seeker: Four five, five six
c02572
Wellby: ... um, 63 plus five, 68 altogether.
c02573
DM: These three die.
c02574
DM: As your arrow sticks into the third
c02575
DM: minion of stone.
c02576
Unknown: Nice.
c02577
Delwath: Wow. They're like 20 something hit points each.
c02578
Unknown: Oh, great.
c02579
DM: That ends Wellby's turn. Kenzo's up.
c02580
Unknown: All right.
c02581
DM: Watch out. Don't let Seeker die.
c02582
Kenzo: Um, Kenzo will try to kill...
c02583
Unknown: See, you've got s- you're, you've got Seeker-
c02584
Delwath: Seeker has a billion hit points.
c02585
Seeker: I have over 100-
c02586
DM: Okay
c02587
Unknown: ... billion hit points.
c02588
Kenzo: Oh, okay. All right.
c02589
Delwath: You should, you should go-
c02590
Kenzo: I'm gonna kill the minions around me.
c02591
Unknown: All right.
c02592
Unknown: Well, 'cause I, I, if I run away-
c02593
Delwath: Oh, no, no, no. Yeah, do that. Deal with them.
c02594
Unknown: Yeah.
c02595
Unknown: Take this guy.
c02596
Unknown: All right. Uh-
c02597
Delwath: Yeah, and they all get hit by Second Radiance again.
c02598
DM: This guy's-
c02599
Unknown: Oh
c02600
DM: ... Senja's, yeah, Senja's still blinded
c02601
Delwath: ... you should go... You know what? You should... If you can, you should really go after the minions around Seeker.
c02602
Unknown: Yeah. Well, uh-
c02603
Delwath: 'Cause the Second Radiance isn't around those guys.
c02604
Unknown: Uh-
c02605
Delwath: All fi- all six of these, seven of those minions will take damage.
c02606
Kenzo: If I, if I kill these three, can I then move and kill two more?
c02607
DM: Yeah.
c02608
Kenzo: Okay, 'cause then this one won't get an opportunity to attack on me, right?
c02609
DM: You have... Yeah, I mean-
c02610
Unknown: I mean-
c02611
DM: Everybody has disadvantage on opportunity attacks against you, but, you know, still might be worth killing one at least before you go help Seeker.
c02612
Kenzo: I'll go... I'll kill two in front of me and then I'll kill the other three in front with, with Seeker.
c02613
Delwath: You're optimistic that you're gonna kill them.
c02614
DM: Well, he only has to hit.
c02615
Delwath: Oh, minions die automatically.
c02616
DM: They die automatically if you hit.
c02617
Unknown: Right.
c02618
Kenzo: Do I, do I have advantage against these guys?
c02619
DM: Uh, no, they're not blinded.
c02620
Kenzo: Ah, shit.
c02621
Delwath: Yeah, kill... If you kill two here and three there, that would be ideal, and just take one opportunity.
c02622
Kenzo: All right. I will do that. So no advantage, though.
c02623
Unknown: But can you... Oh, no, you can't double bonus action.
c02624
Kenzo: Okay. So that hits.
c02625
DM: That hits.
c02626
Kenzo: And... Oh, sorry, I didn't-
c02627
Delwath: You don't control damage.
c02628
Unknown: Yeah.
c02629
Unknown: They just die.
c02630
Unknown: Oh, they just die.
c02631
DM: W- well, roll da- well-
c02632
Unknown: Yeah
c02633
DM: ... roll damage. No.
c02634
DM: Yeah, don't bother rolling damage-
c02635
Unknown: Okay
c02636
DM: ... unless you get a crit.
c02637
Unknown: He can't do more than 20.
c02638
DM: Yeah-
c02639
Unknown: Unless-
c02640
DM: ... unless you get a crit. Roll damage if you get a crit.
c02641
Delwath: Okay. So-
c02642
DM: So one dies
c02643
Kenzo: ... one dies
c02644
DM: ... with your first strike.
c02645
Kenzo: 24.
c02646
DM: Second one dies with your s- second strike with your staff twice.
c02647
DM: Boom, boom.
c02648
Kenzo: Okay. First-
c02649
Delwath: Wait. You don't have extra reach, do you?
c02650
Unknown: No.
c02651
DM: No.
c02652
Kenzo: Uh, I can do a long sword swap.
c02653
DM: No.
c02654
Kenzo: I, I don't wanna do that. That's only once per day.
c02655
DM: That's only once per day.
c02656
Unknown: Yeah. Okay. Um-
c02657
Unknown: Are you moving or-
c02658
Kenzo: Yeah, I'll move and... Go. I'll go, yeah, that way.
c02659
DM: So you take one-
c02660
Unknown: One
c02661
DM: ... one opportunity attack.
c02662
DM: Uh, that, hmm, that's a f-
c02663
Unknown: Oh, wait
c02664
DM: ... 18.
c02665
Kenzo: I didn't wanna take opportunity attacks. But they, there's disadvantage.
c02666
DM: Oh, disadvantage.
c02667
Unknown: Yeah.
c02668
DM: Uh, natural one.
c02669
Kenzo: Okay, perfect. All right, so now I got three unar- armed strikes here.
c02670
Unknown: Damn it. 13.
c02671
Unknown: That one hits.
c02672
Kenzo: 13's gonna miss.
c02673
Unknown: Yeah.
c02674
DM: Yeah, that misses.
c02675
Unknown: 22.
c02676
DM: That hits.
c02677
Kenzo: And then last one.
c02678
Unknown: [dice颠覆]
c02679
Unknown: Oh.
c02680
DM: What was it?
c02681
Unknown: 14.
c02682
DM: 14 misses.
c02683
Unknown: Nope.
c02684
DM: So Seek, uh...
c02685
DM: Kenzo runs forward smashing these, like, stone tentacle creatures that are globbing up, um,
c02686
DM: and trying to surround
c02687
DM: Seeker, who is up next.
c02688
Unknown: Can I
c02689
Seeker: push my way backward out the door, like, just like that?
c02690
DM: Uh.
c02691
Seeker: Uh, do you want out the door where you-
c02692
DM: Yeah.
c02693
Unknown: Oh.
c02694
Unknown: You won't be able to get back in.
c02695
Seeker: Yeah. You won't be able to get back in.
c02696
Unknown: Hmm.
c02697
Unknown: Go up.
c02698
Delwath: You could just walk up, but then you'd get opportunity attacks.
c02699
Unknown: Yeah, don't do that.
c02700
Seeker: Oh, I shouldn't move at all. You're right.
c02701
Seeker: I was just thinking about Erupting Earth.
c02702
Seeker: I can get two of them.
c02703
Seeker: Oh, no, but not without... Yeah, I can get two of them.
c02704
Seeker: Let's see. And not... And anybody else?
c02705
Seeker: Yeah, there's happens to be a square like this.
c02706
DM: Yeah, you could get the two in front of you-
c02707
Unknown: Yeah
c02708
DM: ... with Erupting Earth.
c02709
Seeker: Yeah. And so I should, I should do a low level Erupting Earth-
c02710
DM: Yeah
c02711
Unknown: ... probably. 'Cause if I fail the save, I'll die.
c02712
DM: If they fail their save, they auto die.
c02713
DM: It's a dex save, is that right?
c02714
Seeker: Third level Erupting Earth, it is a dex saving throw.
c02715
DM: Um,
c02716
DM: those are both 19.
c02717
DM: Uh, sorry, 19 and 23.
c02718
Delwath: 19 should fail, right? I mean, with a DC...
c02719
DM: 20.
c02720
Unknown: 20.
c02721
Seeker: It says save DC 19.
c02722
DM: So they both succeed. [laughs]
c02723
Unknown: Oh, okay.
c02724
DM: Roll damage. How much damage does it do?
c02725
Seeker: 3d12.
c02726
Unknown: Ah.
c02727
DM: It's theoretically possible.
c02728
Seeker: On a failed s-
c02729
DM: Oh, no, it's half damage. They won't...
c02730
DM: It won't matter.
c02731
Seeker: Half damage. On a successful it won't.
c02732
Delwath: 3d12. It's tight.
c02733
Seeker: What's half of 3d12?
c02734
Unknown: Well, just, just roll.
c02735
Unknown: Like 15.
c02736
Delwath: You could get 30-
c02737
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
c02738
Delwath: ... if you rolled really well.
c02739
Delwath: I mean, it probably won't kill them, but...
c02740
Unknown: Yeah.
c02741
Delwath: But they hit points carry over.
c02742
DM: No. If they don't die, they take no damage.
c02743
Unknown: Oh.
c02744
Unknown: Two.
c02745
Seeker: Is there another d12?
c02746
Unknown: Yeah, right.
c02747
Unknown: Yeah.
c02748
Unknown: Nice.
c02749
Delwath: You'd have to roll amazing for this to be worthwhile, but nope.
c02750
Seeker: 19.
c02751
Unknown: Oh, so close.
c02752
Seeker: 29. 3-
c02753
DM: Nope.
c02754
Unknown: No. Ugh.
c02755
DM: Nothing happens.
c02756
Delwath: Actually, there was nothing you could do.
c02757
Delwath: 36. If they take no damage from a success, you couldn't-
c02758
DM: Right
c02759
Unknown: ... nothing could possibly-
c02760
DM: Um,
c02761
DM: so the group three is basically decimated.
c02762
DM: That's the o- uh...
c02763
DM: So these ones are group two.
c02764
DM: Group one has to make saves.
c02765
DM: It's one, two, three, four, five of them in group one.
c02766
DM: Uh,
c02767
DM: one
c02768
DM: success.
c02769
Seeker: It doesn't matter which one. Here, I'll just put that there.
c02770
Seeker: It's difficult to remember.
c02771
DM: Um, group two is, uh,
c02772
DM: they're gonna attack Seeker.
c02773
Delwath: All right. Group three is after Delwath.
c02774
Unknown: Group, group three is dead.
c02775
Unknown: Oh, group three's dead.
c02776
DM: You killed d- group three.
c02777
DM: Um, so that's, uh,
c02778
DM: six plus 11 is 17, plus four is 21.
c02779
Unknown: That hits.
c02780
DM: So make a dex saving throw.
c02781
DM: You take 40 points of bludgeoning damage.
c02782
Seeker: I rolled a six plus eight, a 14 plus-
c02783
DM: And you are knocked prone as this liquid stone pulls you down to the ground.
c02784
DM: You-
c02785
Unknown: How many points of damage?
c02786
DM: 40. You cannot, um, stand up until the end of the minions' next turn.
c02787
DM: So Del's up.
c02788
Unknown: Okay. Uh,
c02789
Delwath: those guys just went.
c02790
Delwath: This guy have not gone.
c02791
DM: That guy has not gone. That, that-
c02792
Delwath: Wait. Who's blinded? Anybody?
c02793
DM: That one's blinded.
c02794
Unknown: He's blinded.
c02795
DM: He's blinded still
c02796
Delwath: So I'm gonna start by attacking the blinded guy.
c02797
DM: Okay.
c02798
Wellby: Whoa, that's a lot of dice.
c02799
Delwath: Well, oops, I rolled too many D20s.
c02800
Wellby: Just do it again.
c02801
DM: Just do your D20s again.
c02802
Delwath: I'm just rolling damage at the same time.
c02803
Delwath: Uh, does a 22 hit?
c02804
DM: Yep.
c02805
Delwath: Uh, so it takes 8, 15, 20, 26 damage.
c02806
DM: Uh,
c02807
DM: uh, damage types matter here.
c02808
Unknown: Force.
c02809
DM: It's all force?
c02810
Delwath: It's all force. That's the ability you gave me for Limbo.
c02811
DM: No, no, no. The, that doesn't include the normal damage-
c02812
Unknown: Oh
c02813
DM: ... of the weapon.
c02814
Unknown: Ah, so
c02815
Delwath: call it five, not force.
c02816
DM: Okay.
c02817
Delwath: Um, the bonus damage is all force.
c02818
DM: Yeah, yeah. The bonus damage is all force.
c02819
Unknown: All force.
c02820
DM: I just wanted you to separate out the weapon damage.
c02821
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. I didn't realize. I'll...
c02822
Unknown: Okay. Um-
c02823
DM: So, sorry, how much?
c02824
Delwath: I, I don't know which one I rolled, so-
c02825
DM: Just how much was the total?
c02826
Unknown: ... call it, it was
c02827
DM: 25.
c02828
DM: Okay.
c02829
Unknown: Call it five force, 25 total.
c02830
Kenzo: How much is, is that to resistance, resistant to?
c02831
Delwath: It's resistant to all damage, I think, probably, except force.
c02832
Wellby: Except force.
c02833
Delwath: Okay. I'm gonna attack him again.
c02834
DM: Okay.
c02835
Wellby: You're attacking?
c02836
Delwath: Uh, thir- uh, 20-something.
c02837
Delwath: This guy, Bob.
c02838
Unknown: So you're over here.
c02839
Delwath: Oh, y- yeah. But I, uh... Oh, you see Delwath's sword warp space and time and just hit him from 20 feet away.
c02840
Unknown: Cool.
c02841
Unknown: That's amazing.
c02842
Delwath: Uh, four force.
c02843
Unknown: Does the...
c02844
Delwath: I mean, sorry, four regular.
c02845
DM: Okay.
c02846
Delwath: And to 12, 20, 25 force.
c02847
Unknown: Wait, the force, the bonus-
c02848
Unknown: The plus six? Okay
c02849
DM: ... the plus six-
c02850
Unknown: So then 10
c02851
DM: ... is 10 regular.
c02852
Delwath: Move six from one to the other.
c02853
DM: 10 regular and how much force?
c02854
Delwath: I said 25, so minus-
c02855
DM: Okay
c02856
Delwath: ... six from that.
c02857
DM: 19.
c02858
Unknown: Yeah.
c02859
Delwath: How's he looking?
c02860
DM: Uh, very wounded.
c02861
DM: [laughs]
c02862
Delwath: Okay. You know what? I'm just gonna keep going on him.
c02863
Delwath: Last attack.
c02864
DM: I mean, very wounded, not like you're gonna kill him in one hit.
c02865
Unknown: Yeah.
c02866
DM: But be- pot-bloodied.
c02867
Delwath: But he has sickening radiance next turn.
c02868
DM: Yes.
c02869
Unknown: Uh, n-
c02870
Unknown: uh, uh,
c02871
Kenzo: that was a crappy roll comparatively.
c02872
Delwath: Um, 13 slashing and ni- eight force.
c02873
DM: Uh, okay.
c02874
Delwath: Um, and then with my bonus action
c02875
Unknown: I will...
c02876
Delwath: I don't really have anything very good to do with a bonus action.
c02877
Wellby: You should move to at least a slightly different spot in the darkness.
c02878
Delwath: Yeah. You know what? I'll move,
c02879
Unknown: I'll move,
c02880
Unknown: uh, all the way over here.
c02881
Wellby: Cool.
c02882
Unknown: No, those are the 60 feet.
c02883
DM: Um,
c02884
DM: Goldie is going to look arou- like, can't see, look around, um-
c02885
Delwath: Does he make the save on sickening?
c02886
DM: Oh. Uh, no.
c02887
Unknown: So he takes-
c02888
DM: Oh, that might kill him actually
c02889
Delwath: ... uh, 9, 12, uh, 18 radiant.
c02890
DM: Okay. Not quite.
c02891
DM: Um,
c02892
DM: looking around, stumbling, beginning to de- decohere a little, just trying to figure out where to run to.
c02893
DM: Turning,
c02894
DM: charging. So Del- Wellby is hidden but Delwath is not.
c02895
Delwath: Not hiding officially-
c02896
DM: Right
c02897
Unknown: ... but in the darkness-
c02898
DM: Yeah
c02899
Unknown: ... and hiding behind the pillar.
c02900
DM: He's gonna turn and just try to, try to make a swing at you
c02901
DM: with disadvantage.
c02902
DM: Not quite sure what he's aiming at, just swinging the sword, um, sort of wildly in,
c02903
DM: um...
c02904
DM: That's a-
c02905
Wellby: [laughs]
c02906
DM: That's a 13.
c02907
Wellby: This is... [laughs]
c02908
DM: That's a
c02909
DM: 24.
c02910
Wellby: Why am
c02911
Wellby: I laughing?
c02912
DM: I, I'll cast... You know what?
c02913
Delwath: I'm just, I'm gonna cast minor image.
c02914
Wellby: I'm glad I wore short-sleeve armor.
c02915
Wellby: [laughs]
c02916
DM: And that's a 19.
c02917
Unknown: Almost.
c02918
DM: So all three swings miss as one glances off Delwath's-
c02919
Delwath: He, he fell down. The stones pulled him to the ground.
c02920
DM: Yeah.
c02921
Wellby: Yeah.
c02922
DM: Now he is not blinded.
c02923
DM: Looks around, sees how close he is to the
c02924
DM: s- to the-
c02925
Unknown: No
c02926
DM: ... his, end of his turn.
c02927
Unknown: His turn marker.
c02928
DM: He can't do anything, but he realizes where he is now and he, like, you can see him locking in on that thing.
c02929
Unknown: Now-
c02930
DM: So you gotta kill him before his next turn
c02931
Unknown: ... no, well-
c02932
DM: Wellby's up
c02933
Unknown: ... kill him.
c02934
Wellby: Awesome. That's the end of that.
c02935
Wellby: Uh, yep, Wellby is gonna shoot him.
c02936
Unknown: I would have not blinded.
c02937
Wellby: That's
c02938
Wellby: a hit.
c02939
Unknown: 20-something.
c02940
DM: I'm gonna... He has 18 hit points left.
c02941
DM: I don't think you need to roll.
c02942
Wellby: That's very much more than 18.
c02943
Unknown: He's dead.
c02944
Wellby: Uh, and then I'll shoot, uh, minions next to, uh-
c02945
Delwath: Yeah. You should come, like-
c02946
DM: Yeah, you can get-
c02947
Delwath: Like, two. Those two in a line
c02948
DM: ... if you just take three steps over you can get two in a line.
c02949
Kenzo: Go up there and get two in a line.
c02950
Wellby: Uh,
c02951
Wellby: which I don't have advantage on because I shot a different group last round.
c02952
DM: You went... You wouldn't have advantage-
c02953
Wellby: Yeah
c02954
DM: ... because you shot a different group, but you do get sneak.
c02955
Wellby: Uh, that's a one. That's a three.
c02956
DM: What's your... Yeah, that's not gonna happen.
c02957
Wellby: My bad. Yeah, 14.
c02958
DM: 14 misses.
c02959
Wellby: Huh.
c02960
Kenzo: You could bardic or rally.
c02961
Wellby: Probably not, right?
c02962
DM: Whack.
c02963
Wellby: Kenzo will take care of it.
c02964
Delwath: Yeah, Kenzo. No, no, no. That's-
c02965
DM: Kenzo's right there. Kenzo can kill them
c02966
Wellby: ... Well- Wellby's mostly just disappointed in himself.
c02967
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
c02968
DM: You're up.
c02969
Unknown: All right.
c02970
DM: So Kenzo goes, "I'm gonna save you, Seeker."
c02971
DM: Yep.
c02972
Kenzo: 23 dead.
c02973
DM: One's dead.
c02974
DM: Whoops. Whoa. [laughs] No, that's cool.
c02975
DM: Next one's dead.
c02976
Kenzo: 27 is dead.
c02977
Unknown: Bonk, bonk.
c02978
Kenzo: D- that one misses.
c02979
DM: That one misses.
c02980
DM: Next one's dead.
c02981
Delwath: But you can attack the one you missed a second time.
c02982
Delwath: You have five attacks.
c02983
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
c02984
DM: Yeah-
c02985
Wellby: So I can-
c02986
DM: ... so he still has one more
c02987
Wellby: ...
c02988
Wellby: I can hit one more. Yeah.
c02989
DM: What is that?
c02990
Unknown: 17.
c02991
DM: Misses.
c02992
Unknown: Dope.
c02993
DM: So Kenzo cleans up a number of these...
c02994
DM: And he, as you hit each one, it sort of dissolves into stone and falls actually through the floor.
c02995
Unknown: Cool.
c02996
Delwath: Uh, that ends Kenzo.
c02997
DM: Seeker, you're up.
c02998
DM: You are pinned to the ground. You can't stand up, but you can still cast spells or do something.
c02999
Unknown: Oh.
c03000
Delwath: Do you have a cantrip?
c03001
Wellby: Like, um-
c03002
Delwath: Do cantrips just kill minions if they hit, presumably, right?
c03003
DM: If they succeed on-
c03004
Unknown: If they attack
c03005
DM: ... if they f- if they s- if they fail the save or if the attack roll hits.
c03006
Unknown: Yeah.
c03007
DM: There's no cantrip that does damage without either a save-
c03008
Unknown: Yeah
c03009
DM: ... or an attack roll. [clears throat]
c03010
Seeker: I, um-
c03011
Delwath: You should've Vicious Mockery.
c03012
Seeker: I, yeah, I explain to this stone drop that it will never amount to anything.
c03013
DM: [laughs]
c03014
Unknown: [laughs] Fucking limbless.
c03015
DM: It just dissolves into nothingness.
c03016
Unknown: Whoa.
c03017
DM: You're convinced.
c03018
Unknown: [laughs]
c03019
Kenzo: And there's still, there's still one left?
c03020
Delwath: Yeah, that, that will-
c03021
DM: That one's gonna-
c03022
Delwath: It's starting its turn
c03023
DM: ... it's starting its turn. It's, it's its turn, but,
c03024
DM: uh...
c03025
DM: What was... No, that succeeds.
c03026
Delwath: DC 20.
c03027
DM: So it's mindlessly going to rush towards whoever's closest.
c03028
Kenzo: Oh, I can kill it now then.
c03029
DM: Um, that hits, 23,
c03030
DM: but it's only 10 damage, so you auto deflect it.
c03031
Unknown: Oh, yeah, I do kill it, yeah.
c03032
DM: So it's dead.
c03033
Delwath: Oh, you deflect it back.
c03034
DM: Yeah. So the last one runs forward just mindlessly trying to attack the intruders, runs into Kenzo, it, like, flies towards Kenzo, and Kenzo's just, "Psh, nope,"
c03035
DM: and deflects it back.
c03036
Delwath: We should probably
c03037
Delwath: immediately go see if we can save, um-
c03038
Kenzo: The ladder and Seeker 6?
c03039
Delwath: ... the ladder and Seeker 6.
c03040
DM: Yes.
c03041
Kenzo: Well, let's go to the orb.
c03042
Wellby: Agreed. Uh, while you're checking the orb-
c03043
DM: I'm just-
c03044
Wellby: I want to quick search the p- do they have anything on them, the centaurs?
c03045
Wellby: Like, are they carrying anything? Are they-
c03046
DM: Uh,
c03047
DM: n- no, but
c03048
DM: they do kind of basically look like they're living chaos metal.
c03049
DM: Like, their limbs are reforming and shifting and, like-
c03050
Wellby: Like, back to being good again?
c03051
Wellby: Like, standing up and attacking us kind of thing?
c03052
DM: No, no, no, no, no.
c03053
Wellby: No.
c03054
DM: I mean, like-
c03055
Unknown: They're no more
c03056
DM: ... as they were fighting, they're inert now.
c03057
Wellby: Oh, okay.
c03058
DM: But as they were fighting, like, their limb was shift-
c03059
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
c03060
DM: ... their limbs were shifting into weapons.
c03061
Wellby: Oh.
c03062
DM: Now they're kind of actually dripping slightly through the floor.
c03063
Delwath: I th- I think we, uh...
c03064
Wellby: I'll-
c03065
Delwath: Seeker, what, can you come check out this...
c03066
Delwath: Looks like, you know, quickly.
c03067
Seeker: Have a look at the orb.
c03068
Seeker: I have a look at the orb.
c03069
DM: Um,
c03070
DM: so it's a
c03071
DM: violet orb about this big hovering about four feet off the ground, giving off a sort of pale violet light.
c03072
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c03073
Seeker: It's clearly magical.
c03074
Seeker: Should I use Identify on it?
c03075
Unknown: How long does that take?
c03076
DM: A minute.
c03077
Unknown: Oh, it does?
c03078
DM: Yeah.
c03079
Delwath: I mean, we either-
c03080
Unknown: Arcana check, you know how to use it
c03081
Unknown: ... we either like-
c03082
DM: You can examine it with your goggles.
c03083
Seeker: Oh, that's what I thought I was doing. Yes.
c03084
Seeker: I examine it with my goggles.
c03085
DM: Oh, yeah, um, so wait, make an arcana check with advantage.
c03086
Unknown: Whoa.
c03087
Unknown: Nice. 23.
c03088
Seeker: So 20 plus 17, not bad.
c03089
DM: Yeah. [laughs] Um, so you, you sort of look, um,
c03090
DM: you can see actually as you're ex- as...
c03091
DM: When you put on your goggles, when you're looking at it through the lenses, you can actually see that there's, there's a, like, a small shape in the bottom that is kind of slowly drifting up,
c03092
DM: but actually looks like it's a knob that you can grab.
c03093
DM: There's, like, insi- there's this purple sphere, and then there's, in the bottom part of the puppers- purple sphere, there's a l- there's a, a, a lever shaped out of light
c03094
DM: that you can, like, grab and turn.
c03095
Seeker: Um, I'm gonna grab the lever and turn it.
c03096
Seeker: Everybody okay with that? Too late.
c03097
Unknown: Are you... [laughs]
c03098
Wellby: Yeah. We'll all-
c03099
Unknown: I was gonna say
c03100
Wellby: ... we'll all come close. We'll, like-
c03101
DM: Are you giving us a chance?
c03102
Wellby: ... at least put our hand on your shoulder or something.
c03103
DM: Yeah. Uh, ev- everybody within 10 feet, which is all of you, um, you suddenly feel a
c03104
DM: sh- y- you're, like, sucked into the
c03105
DM: purple light, and then, like, there's a super disorienting, like, gravity is shifting.
c03106
DM: And as you come out, you are standing in front of another,
c03107
DM: um,
c03108
DM: uh, purple light,
c03109
DM: uh, but you've shifted 90 degrees.
c03110
Unknown: Whoa.
c03111
Delwath: Is this the room with the...
c03112
DM: This, this is the room that pinches at the top
c03113
Unknown: ... the cross at the center?
c03114
DM: No. Uh, you don't know what... So let me say what you see.
c03115
Unknown: Oh.
c03116
DM: Um,
c03117
DM: it's very, it happens quietly.
c03118
DM: Um, you see, like, a d- um,
c03119
DM: a dozen statues of strange warriors similar to, like, the humanoids in the,
c03120
DM: um,
c03121
DM: in the
c03122
DM: m- mosaic below. They're like...
c03123
DM: You wouldn't even really describe them as humanoids, but they're clearly warriors.
c03124
DM: There's about a dozen of these statues, each surrounded by a semicircle of,
c03125
DM: I guess what you might describe as candles, but each one seems to be made of some weird different material.
c03126
DM: Like, there's one of stone, there's one that's made of water that's just a pillar of water, and all the candles are, are burning.
c03127
DM: It's almost like a...
c03128
DM: They're almost like...
c03129
DM: It's like in a church. It's like the sort of tealights in front of an altar in a church.
c03130
DM: Um, there are four pedestals that are much larger than the rest.
c03131
DM: Um, three hold
c03132
DM: big statues.
c03133
DM: One is a statue of whirlwind made of white stone forming a vaguely humanoid shape while the inside of the whirlwind dances with crystals of frost.
c03134
DM: Um, and it has a, a script that's labeled, and again, it seems like every language at once, and it says, "Pel Ossa, the Chalk Storm."
c03135
DM: Another looks like raindrops rising from the ground, each bursting into a fireball as they ascend, forming a humanoid torso that floats on a cloud of wh-
c03136
DM: ... flaming dust water.
c03137
DM: That says, "Zalmira, the arid rain."
c03138
DM: The s- third is a statue of what looks like a gorilla made of glass that dripples and moves like liquid stone.
c03139
DM: That says, "Jalox, the rippling stone."
c03140
DM: And the fourth is labeled as, "Kith-sath, the light of darkness, the burning night, and the flame of unmaking," but the pedestal is empty.
c03141
DM: There are two violet orbs that hover four feet off the ground.
c03142
DM: One that you appeared at, which is near the
c03143
DM: south
c03144
DM: wall to the extent to which directions make any sense.
c03145
DM: The other is at the far side of the room to the north wall.
c03146
DM: Um,
c03147
DM: uh, there is also,
c03148
DM: um,
c03149
DM: a 17 foot tall giant made of lightning frozen in place hunched over one of the smaller statues to the south wrapped in a
c03150
DM: cloak of visible thunder
c03151
DM: with a cowl over his face.
c03152
Unknown: [laughs] Visible thunder.
c03153
Unknown: This is awesome.
c03154
Wellby: I love it.
c03155
Kenzo: This whole description is so crazy.
c03156
Unknown: I love it.
c03157
Unknown: This is like the craziest thing.
c03158
DM: Seems to be in the middle of chanting some kind of spell, has not noticed you.
c03159
DM: Seems to be
c03160
DM: engaged in what he's doing.
c03161
Delwath: Should we just like grab the next orb?
c03162
Unknown: Um-
c03163
Unknown: Yeah.
c03164
Seeker: That's what I was wondering.
c03165
Unknown: We gotta sneak over there though, right?
c03166
Kenzo: If we don't see, if we don't see Seeker 6 and the- Wait, how close to the- We're, we're right next to the other room ...
c03167
Seeker: Seeker is? We're on the opposite side of the room. Opposite side of the room.
c03168
Unknown: Yeah.
c03169
Unknown: Oh, shit.
c03170
Kenzo: Dash, duck, run of frame.
c03171
Wellby: Sneak?
c03172
Unknown: Yeah.
c03173
Wellby: Are we sneaky?
c03174
Unknown: Mm-mm.
c03175
Unknown: Oh, uh, uh, uh-
c03176
Unknown: Then yeah, that one
c03177
DM: ... Dimension Door
c03178
Unknown: Yep
c03179
Unknown: ...
c03180
Seeker: before we go. We're looking at you 'cause you did the thing.
c03181
Delwath: I cast Dimension Door? Yeah.
c03182
Kenzo: They're not... Are Seeker 6 and, and the, the, the latter are not in here?
c03183
DM: They are not in here.
c03184
Kenzo: But they're, but this whole thing, is there, the, the, there's some kind of active combat happening though?
c03185
DM: They, what they told you is they-
c03186
Unknown: Oh
c03187
DM: ... Seeker 6-
c03188
Unknown: Behind
c03189
DM: ... summoned a wall of stone-
c03190
Unknown: Yes
c03191
Unknown: And they're trying to-
c03192
DM: And tombing him-
c03193
Unknown: Yes
c03194
DM: ... against a wall, and-
c03195
Unknown: Right
c03196
DM: ... there were two things fighting them.
c03197
Unknown: Yeah
c03198
DM: And they're trying to hold out inside the tomb.
c03199
Kenzo: Yeah, the wall. Yes, that's right. But that's not, you know, that's not-
c03200
DM: That's, you don't... Oh no, it's clearly not here.
c03201
Kenzo: That, that's what I'm saying, but there's an active battle happening in this room too.
c03202
DM: No, no, no.
c03203
Unknown: No.
c03204
DM: There's no active battle in this room.
c03205
Unknown: Oh.
c03206
DM: There's a guy casting a spell, but it doesn't seem like it's a, it's not a combat spell.
c03207
DM: It's like the middle of a ritual.
c03208
Unknown: Oh, fuck.
c03209
DM: Not paying attention to you.
c03210
Unknown: But how... But hold on, hold on. So
c03211
Delwath: we came up here. The other orb is what?
c03212
Delwath: Like 50, how, 20 feet, 30?
c03213
DM: Like 40 feet away.
c03214
Delwath: Ah, and the guy is like halfway in.
c03215
Kenzo: Do we just like shoot him with an arrow and then get out of here?
c03216
Seeker: Does it blind him? Yeah.
c03217
DM: The, th- th- yeah, the gu- the, the s-
c03218
Unknown: Creature
c03219
DM: ... lightning giant-
c03220
Unknown: Yeah
c03221
DM: ... is...
c03222
DM: So it's like a room.
c03223
DM: Here's the, what the s- the orb you came out.
c03224
DM: Here's the other orb. There's the three big statues in the middle, and then against the walls there's all these little statues.
c03225
DM: Um, the s- lightning giant is standing against one of the,
c03226
DM: the little statues casting a spell, like
c03227
DM: i- in the context of that statue.
c03228
Unknown: Okay.
c03229
DM: You can always use arcana checks to try and identify spells as they're being cast, by the way.
c03230
Seeker: Oh, I used an arcana check to identify spells with me.
c03231
DM: [coughs]
c03232
Seeker: I roll a 20, 19, 17.
c03233
DM: He's casting Legend Lore.
c03234
Delwath: What is that?
c03235
Delwath: That tells you things about- 23 ...
c03236
Delwath: what's the statue?
c03237
DM: I mean, it's that, it's, it's not one of the f- three big ones.
c03238
Delwath: But I mean, is it of like a particular pers- I mean, does it have like identifiable...
c03239
Unknown: Like is it,
c03240
Delwath: is it of like a person or is it like-
c03241
DM: No, no, it's like, it's the same types of creatures that were in the mosaic below.
c03242
DM: They're-
c03243
Unknown: Right
c03244
DM: ...
c03245
DM: semi-humanoid, elemental-ish creatures.
c03246
DM: Actually, the one he's looking at almost looks like one of the chaos elementals you fought in the battle.
c03247
DM: Like it, like it's a whirlwind, humanoid whirlwind of stone.
c03248
DM: It's like one of the chaos elementals that the Empress of Chaos summoned.
c03249
Delwath: Empress of Chaos. Interesting.
c03250
Unknown: Okay.
c03251
Seeker: Oh, oh, oh. Back in the Material Plane.
c03252
DM: Yeah.
c03253
Unknown: Uh-
c03254
DM: I mean, it is definite, like this person is using their action and intention to cast this ritual
c03255
Seeker: And it's to study them?
c03256
DM: Well, Legend Lore would tell you something about the subject of the statue.
c03257
DM: So it would be to get more information about who this person is or was.
c03258
Seeker: So he's a scholar. Maybe he'll be my friend.
c03259
DM: Hmm.
c03260
Unknown: Maybe.
c03261
Unknown: Um,
c03262
Seeker: s- oh, oh, arcana about like a giant made of lightning, or is this just like clearly like a Limbo phenomenon?
c03263
DM: It's clearly just a Limbo, it's a Limbo phenomenon.
c03264
Wellby: Let's
c03265
Wellby: stealth this guy one way or another, 'cause like all of these statues could come to life and kill us-
c03266
Unknown: Oh, absolutely
c03267
Wellby: ... right?
c03268
DM: Let's what?
c03269
Wellby: All e- every statue could come to life and kill us.
c03270
Kenzo: Yeah. So, so what were you saying?
c03271
Wellby: Stealth.
c03272
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, let's get out of here.
c03273
Wellby: Bypass.
c03274
Seeker: Is there some safe way we can all like become invisible or-
c03275
DM: Well, I can cast invisibility
c03276
Unknown: ... would that help?
c03277
Kenzo: Probably if someone- Wait, can you Dimension Door us to the, to the other orb?
c03278
Seeker: Does seem a little ridiculous to Dimension Door across a room.
c03279
Seeker: It does. Unless we can get two people. Can we just, okay, let's see.
c03280
DM: I can only do two people.
c03281
Unknown: Yeah. Okay. Well-
c03282
Wellby: But we can sneak.
c03283
Delwath: Yeah. I can make us invisible.
c03284
Delwath: I mean, then I'm out of spell slots. I gotta get them back.
c03285
Delwath: I gotta take a minute. If we do that, I gotta take a, a minute at some point to get back two of my spell slots.
c03286
DM: If...
c03287
DM: Yeah. Wait, you don't have... Oh, you only have second level sorcerer spell slots.
c03288
Delwath: I could cast invisibility with a second level sorcerer spell.
c03289
DM: I can only get one of you.
c03290
Delwath: That only get one of us, yes. Plus I can get back all of my-
c03291
DM: Right, right
c03292
Delwath: ... spell slots with a prayer of healing and-
c03293
DM: Right
c03294
Unknown: ... two of them with-
c03295
Kenzo: Can I use Step of the Wind and just grab him and just like zip across the room?
c03296
Unknown: We could just follow-
c03297
DM: You could just make a run for it, yeah
c03298
Delwath: ... should we just make a run for it?
c03299
DM: Everybody's super fast except Seeker, and you can just grab Seeker.
c03300
Unknown: Yeah.
c03301
Wellby: You couldn't just-
c03302
Unknown: Are you kidding me?
c03303
Wellby: ... follow us up the elevator, though?
c03304
Wellby: Like, even better to stealth than to-
c03305
DM: Yeah, let's-
c03306
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
c03307
DM: ... let's stealth. I'll just...
c03308
DM: No, it's fine. I'll cast invisibility.
c03309
Delwath: Spells are there to be used. I can get back-
c03310
Unknown: Right
c03311
Delwath: ... I can, as long as we, as long as we take a minute,
c03312
Delwath: I can get back two of my three spell slots.
c03313
Wellby: [laughs]
c03314
Delwath: And if we take 10 minutes, I can get back all of them.
c03315
Wellby: All right.
c03316
DM: So-
c03317
Wellby: So what does invisibility get us?
c03318
DM: We're invisible.
c03319
Wellby: All of us?
c03320
DM: Yeah.
c03321
Wellby: Oh, that's great.
c03322
DM: Oh.
c03323
DM: So still make a stealth check, but I'll say this is a group stealth check.
c03324
DM: Only half of you need to succeed, so probably don't even bother.
c03325
Wellby: This is with advantage or no?
c03326
DM: Not with advantage. Invisibility just lets you sneak when you couldn't otherwise.
c03327
Kenzo: What's your s- my stealth's plus 11.
c03328
Unknown: What's yours?
c03329
Wellby: Plus 17.
c03330
Unknown: Ah, goddamn. What's yours?
c03331
Wellby: Uh, 23.
c03332
DM: No, everybody has to roll.
c03333
Unknown: Oh, half, half succeed.
c03334
DM: Half of you have to succeed.
c03335
Unknown: Oh, okay.
c03336
DM: But I got a 14.
c03337
Unknown: Uh, 18.
c03338
DM: Okay, that's fine. You just need to beat a 15.
c03339
Seeker: 8 plus-
c03340
Wellby: It doesn't matter. We're good
c03341
Seeker: ... 5, 13.
c03342
DM: So Kenzo and Wellby guide you quietly across.
c03343
DM: You reach your hand into the other one and yeah.
c03344
Seeker: I, um, do whatever it takes to get us to a different place that is not where we were before.
c03345
DM: Um, you feel yourselves becoming,
c03346
DM: like, squished into a tiny point, and then-
c03347
Seeker: Ah, going up
c03348
DM: ... and then as you, as you re-expand, you're now,
c03349
DM: like, you feel yourself flipping upside down, and what was the floor is now the ceiling,
c03350
DM: and what was the ceiling is now the floor.
c03351
DM: Um-
c03352
Unknown: A creepy castle
c03353
DM: ... and you, you see yourself, you see now, um,
c03354
DM: three desks.
c03355
Delwath: Oh, this is the room.
c03356
Unknown: They were in a room with desks.
c03357
DM: Two stone desks and a wooden desk that face the north wall.
c03358
Delwath: You're still invisible.
c03359
DM: Um,
c03360
DM: uh, running ar- like, in a circle, like bulging out from the wall right next to one of the stone desks is a
c03361
DM: wall of, is a giant wall of stone.
c03362
Unknown: Ah, got it.
c03363
DM: And there are two creatures, one some sort of armored creature made of
c03364
DM: solid blood that is t- uh, has a spear and is, like, chipping at the stone.
c03365
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c03366
DM: You can see there's a crack that's formed through one of the pieces of stone.
c03367
Unknown: Yeah.
c03368
DM: Um, the other is this weird winged darkness creature with a bright, glowing head, um, that is,
c03369
DM: uh, st-
c03370
Wellby: [laughs]
c03371
Seeker: So weird. So get in here.
c03372
Kenzo: What is going on? [laughs]
c03373
Kenzo: Fun. I wanna watch the movie of this.
c03374
Wellby: Yeah, really.
c03375
DM: That is, that is kind of standing and watching as the, the stone, um-
c03376
Seeker: Super low budget
c03377
DM: ... yes
c03378
Kenzo: ... I was just gonna say, I wanna watch the super low budget of this.
c03379
DM: The low budget.
c03380
DM: [laughs]
c03381
Wellby: Yeah.
c03382
Kenzo: With like paper mache hats.
c03383
DM: Like
c03384
DM: [laughs]
c03385
Unknown: Die.
c03386
DM: Um,
c03387
DM: as you, as you appear,
c03388
DM: um,
c03389
DM: the-
c03390
Wellby: Invisible?
c03391
Unknown: They're invisible
c03392
DM: ... the, the one that's chipping turns and looks straight at you
c03393
DM: and-
c03394
Wellby: How'd they see us? How do they know we're there?
c03395
Unknown: Yeah
c03396
DM: ... there's creatures that can see invisibility.
c03397
Kenzo: There are creatures that can see invisibility.
c03398
DM: And,
c03399
DM: um, says, uh,
c03400
DM: says to the, um,
c03401
DM: to the light, to, like, weird darkness light creature next to it, um,
c03402
DM: again in, so Kenzo and Daluth would understand this, but every time they speak, it's like a mishmash of hundreds of languages being mashed up together.
c03403
DM: Um, "Naren, deal with those intruders.
c03404
DM: I'm almost through here."
c03405
Unknown: Ooh.
c03406
DM: And the, um, light creature begins to move in your direction, glowing,
c03407
DM: and um,
c03408
DM: as, as this radius glows, it illuminates your silhouettes.
c03409
DM: Now the entire room is bathed in incredibly bright light, illuminating the silhouette of everything, visible or not,
c03410
DM: and says, again in this strange language, "Surrender now and the queen will be generous in her judgment of you.
c03411
DM: You will re- be reborn in glory and chaos."
c03412
Delwath: I mean, can we have, like, attacked them long before they started talking?
c03413
DM: Sure. [laughs]
c03414
Seeker: Yeah, I think, I think he starts to say that and then-
c03415
DM: Starts to say that, and go ahead
c03416
Unknown: ...
c03417
Wellby: Throw the sword.
c03418
Delwath: I, I think also, yeah.
c03419
DM: Uh,
c03420
DM: tell me what you got for initiatives.
c03421
Unknown: 9, uh, 11.
c03422
Wellby: 28.
c03423
Unknown: 23.
c03424
Wellby: 12.
c03425
DM: 28 was Wellby?
c03426
Wellby: Yep.
c03427
Kenzo: 23 is Kenza.
c03428
DM: Okay, so you two go first.
c03429
DM: Um, 10 is-
c03430
Wellby: You're first then
c03431
DM: ... who was 10?
c03432
Unknown: Nobody has a 10.
c03433
DM: Oh, sorry, 10 was-
c03434
Wellby: If someone was in melee, 'cause then I could sneak, which I won't get otherwise.
c03435
Unknown: You want me to go first?
c03436
Wellby: Yeah, why don't you? We'll swap. So Kenzo and Wellby will go.
c03437
DM: Uh, sorry, you are 11, Daluth.
c03438
Unknown: Yeah.
c03439
DM: And what was Seeker?
c03440
Unknown: 12.
c03441
Wellby: 12. Unless, do you wanna go first?
c03442
DM: Okay.
c03443
Wellby: Ah.
c03444
DM: Eric, what's your plus to dex?
c03445
Wellby: But no, let's put me second-
c03446
Unknown: Um
c03447
Wellby: ... 'cause then we'll get advantage.
c03448
Seeker: You mean the one who, like-
c03449
DM: What's your, sorry, your initiative bonus?
c03450
Wellby: Yeah.
c03451
DM: I just wanna put Seeker sixth.
c03452
Unknown: Plus two.
c03453
DM: Okay.
c03454
Unknown: Yeah.
c03455
DM: So-
c03456
Delwath: Yeah, he's got soul sight, attack
c03457
DM: ... so Seeker sixth is-
c03458
Unknown: And I'll get advantage
c03459
DM: ... um-
c03460
Wellby: That's more useful.
c03461
Unknown: Yep
c03462
DM: ... Seeker sixth is going right before Seeker.
c03463
Unknown: I'll put fourth, yeah.
c03464
DM: And the, the ladder is gonna shift to operating on Seeker's initiative instead of Seeker sixth's initiative.
c03465
Unknown: Yeah. You go this time.
c03466
Wellby: Cool.
c03467
Unknown: Oh.
c03468
Delwath: Wait, oh, 'cause it's until your-
c03469
Wellby: Okay
c03470
Delwath: ... start of your next turn.
c03471
Wellby: Yep.
c03472
Delwath: Uh, where, where should we...
c03473
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah. Sorry, let me draw it.
c03474
DM: Um-
c03475
Wellby: You want the same two tokens for them again?
c03476
Wellby: Different tokens?
c03477
Unknown: Different tokens.
c03478
DM: No, I have, I've got...
c03479
Wellby: Send these back to the side
c03480
DM: Here, this is the,
c03481
DM: this is the, the one. Yeah, this one here.
c03482
Unknown: Glad you draw the room.
c03483
DM: Um,
c03484
DM: where did my...
c03485
DM: Sh.
c03486
Delwath: This doesn't really want to stay.
c03487
DM: Here, just...
c03488
DM: Um, here, stack, if you stack two it'll work better.
c03489
Unknown: I don't know why a lot of these are very bad at...
c03490
DM: Okay. There's the shadow thing.
c03491
DM: They're both large.
c03492
DM: Okay, so this room is about 50 feet across.
c03493
DM: One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10.
c03494
DM: Also a circle.
c03495
DM: So this one's a bit smaller than the entryway.
c03496
DM: So there's a desk here,
c03497
DM: a desk here,
c03498
DM: and the wooden desk here.
c03499
DM: You emerge here.
c03500
DM: Um, the wall of stone
c03501
DM: goes like that.
c03502
DM: So-
c03503
Unknown: Yeah
c03504
DM: ...
c03505
DM: the ladder,
c03506
DM: that's Seeker 6.
c03507
Unknown: [laughs]
c03508
DM: The ladder and Seeker 6 are encased within the wall of stone.
c03509
DM: Um, this one is attacking the wall of stone, and this one, uh, moves-
c03510
Unknown: Well, doesn't it-
c03511
DM: ... is moving towards you.
c03512
DM: Doesn't it what?
c03513
Delwath: Well, I mean we get to-
c03514
DM: Yeah, yeah. So it's starting here, like it's beginning to move towards you-
c03515
Unknown: Mm-hmm
c03516
DM: ... as you go. So put yourselves right next to the...
c03517
DM: Oh, and
c03518
DM: yeah, there was one other detail about this room I forgot to mention, which you might wanna be aware of.
c03519
DM: Um-
c03520
Unknown: You're looking at the funny tablet
c03521
DM: ...
c03522
DM: there is a,
c03523
DM: on the opposite side of here,
c03524
DM: right here,
c03525
DM: there's a circle of runes on the ground.
c03526
Unknown: Oh.
c03527
Unknown: They're not the-
c03528
DM: There's no orbs here.
c03529
DM: So Wellby's up first.
c03530
Seeker: Oh, there's no orbs.
c03531
Unknown: Uh, Kenzo's up first.
c03532
DM: Sorry, Kenzo's up first. You're, you switched.
c03533
Unknown: Yeah.
c03534
Seeker: All right, Kenzo.
c03535
DM: Soulsight.
c03536
Kenzo: Oh, yeah, first Soulsight.
c03537
DM: Which one? The one that-
c03538
Unknown: Uh, the one
c03539
DM: Okay
c03540
Delwath: ... the guy with the shiny head.
c03541
Delwath: Flashlight head. What's...
c03542
Delwath: Wait, the other guy is, uh... What's the other guy look like?
c03543
DM: Uh, metallic blood.
c03544
Delwath: Right. Flashlight head and-
c03545
Unknown: Blood guy
c03546
Unknown: ... blood guy.
c03547
DM: Flashlight head is CR 12.
c03548
DM: Um, immune to poison, charm, exhausted, frightened.
c03549
DM: Resistant to fire and radiant.
c03550
DM: Good at
c03551
DM: charisma,
c03552
DM: bad at intelligence.
c03553
Kenzo: Um, the defensive thing I can do as a bonus action?
c03554
DM: Yeah.
c03555
Unknown: Okay.
c03556
Unknown: Yeah.
c03557
Delwath: Is... Wait, is Soulsight a bonus action, or...?
c03558
Unknown: Soulsight's-
c03559
DM: But Soulsight's, yes, it's a bonus action, but you can do any of your monk things-
c03560
Unknown: Oh
c03561
DM: ... as part of the same bonus action.
c03562
Kenzo: But I'm gonna do the... This time I'm gonna do the, uh, try, I'm gonna turn on my resistance to everything.
c03563
Unknown: Can you, like-
c03564
DM: Oh, that, that...
c03565
DM: Oh, no, that isn't an, that's not an action at all.
c03566
Unknown: Oh.
c03567
DM: That's just at the start of your turn you can do that.
c03568
Unknown: See, that's what I was saying last time.
c03569
Kenzo: So I c- so I can, so but I can turn that on now.
c03570
DM: You can turn that on now.
c03571
Delwath: Last time you used that.
c03572
DM: Well, it costs you three ki every time you use it.
c03573
Kenzo: Yeah, but they're in combat. Yeah. Ah, that's fine.
c03574
Delwath: You can be resistant to damage?
c03575
Unknown: That's awesome.
c03576
Unknown: Yeah.
c03577
Unknown: You should always do that.
c03578
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c03579
Unknown: Hmm.
c03580
Unknown: That's what I'm doing.
c03581
Unknown: All right. I will, uh,
c03582
Kenzo: start attacking.
c03583
DM: So, um, are you...
c03584
DM: How many ki did you spend in the last fight?
c03585
DM: 'Cause you can also-
c03586
Unknown: Zero.
c03587
DM: Okay.
c03588
Unknown: No, no, zero.
c03589
DM: You spent zero.
c03590
Unknown: Uh-
c03591
Kenzo: Not that many, like three. But I'll, I'll actually-
c03592
DM: Okay
c03593
Kenzo: ... you know what I'm gonna do right now is, uh, I'm gonna-
c03594
DM: I'm just saying, do you wanna use your thing now-
c03595
Unknown: Yeah, sure
c03596
DM: ... or do you wanna save it?
c03597
Kenzo: Oh, no, I'll save it. I'll save it. I'll save it.
c03598
Unknown: I still have plenty.
c03599
DM: I'll just say you used three from last time, so you still have 16.
c03600
Unknown: Yeah.
c03601
DM: But it's, that's another three for the-
c03602
Delwath: The resistance
c03603
Unknown: ... the... I'm checking if it's actually only three.
c03604
Unknown: It's three.
c03605
DM: Okay.
c03606
Delwath: But also, I have a spell that'll let us take a short rest.
c03607
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah. So, okay.
c03608
Kenzo: Um, so first attack, uh, a 29.
c03609
DM: That hits.
c03610
Kenzo: Oh, shit.
c03611
Seeker: We're all low on battery.
c03612
Kenzo: Yeah. 11 damage.
c03613
Kenzo: Second attack,
c03614
Unknown: um,
c03615
Unknown: 26 hits.
c03616
DM: Uh, yes, 26 hits.
c03617
Unknown: Uh, 14 damage.
c03618
DM: Sorry, you said 11 damage, then 14?
c03619
Kenzo: 11... Yeah, 11 and 14.
c03620
Kenzo: And then first unarmed strike,
c03621
Kenzo: uh, 23.
c03622
DM: 23 hits.
c03623
Kenzo: That's another 10.
c03624
Unknown: Um...
c03625
Kenzo: Oh, 23 hits again. That's another 10.
c03626
Kenzo: Oh, wow, I hit every time. That's sweet.
c03627
Kenzo: And then 16.
c03628
DM: Okay. Kenzo does 50,
c03629
DM: 61 points of damage.
c03630
Unknown: Cool.
c03631
DM: As you rush forward, smashing into this
c03632
DM: sunlight head darkness creature.
c03633
DM: That ends your turn. Wellby is up.
c03634
Unknown: Uh-
c03635
Wellby: Awesome. I'm gonna shoot both.
c03636
Unknown: Same guy.
c03637
Unknown: Oh, that's a one.
c03638
Wellby: That was a 20-something.
c03639
Unknown: I-
c03640
Unknown: Get some, uh-
c03641
DM: Yep, that hits
c03642
Unknown: ...
c03643
Unknown: healing power. Um-
c03644
DM: Uh, do you need a USB-C?
c03645
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c03646
Wellby: Uh, blinding, so that's a DC 19 dex.
c03647
Delwath: He might not be able to be blinded.
c03648
Wellby: He's not immune to blind under the full set of conditions.
c03649
Unknown: Oh, that's true.
c03650
DM: This one here-
c03651
Wellby: Yeah
c03652
DM: ... um, is not-
c03653
Unknown: Being sighted
c03654
DM: ... yes, is not immune to blind.
c03655
Wellby: All right, DC 19 dex.
c03656
Wellby: Uh, 10,
c03657
Unknown: 20, 26.
c03658
DM: Fails.
c03659
Wellby: Awesome. And then I will shoot the other-
c03660
DM: 26 damage?
c03661
Wellby: Yep.
c03662
Delwath: The other guy with-
c03663
Wellby: Is the other guy within five feet with the wall in between them?
c03664
DM: Nope.
c03665
Wellby: Uh, 22.
c03666
DM: Uh, 22 hits.
c03667
Unknown: Awesome.
c03668
Wellby: Uh, that's-
c03669
Delwath: It's what? D6 plus six
c03670
Wellby: ... oh, I'm sorry. That should've been another five damage on the first guy.
c03671
Wellby: I didn't add the, uh-
c03672
DM: 26 plus five, so 31.
c03673
Wellby: Yeah. Uh, second guy is seven points of damage.
c03674
DM: Uh, okay.
c03675
Unknown: Awesome.
c03676
DM: That ends Wellby's turn.
c03677
DM: Um, this one is going to first, um,
c03678
DM: the sunlight creature, uh, first thing it's going to do is, um,
c03679
DM: uh, its head is gonna flare.
c03680
DM: And it is going to, uh, regain hit points and remove all conditions.
c03681
Seeker: And do what to all conditions?
c03682
Delwath: Remove all conditions.
c03683
Unknown: Oh.
c03684
Delwath: It's not blinded anymore.
c03685
Unknown: What?
c03686
DM: Um, so that, um,
c03687
DM: down there. And then it's going to, um,
c03688
DM: uh, rush, is going to step forward.
c03689
DM: Uh, wait, who's it- Kenzo's in combat with it?
c03690
Unknown: Yeah.
c03691
DM: It's fine. It'll attack Kenzo.
c03692
Delwath: So you're resistant to all damage. We want you to get...
c03693
Delwath: You're, you're like the tank now.
c03694
Unknown: I know.
c03695
DM: Uh,
c03696
DM: two attacks, so that's a 21 and an 18.
c03697
Unknown: Missed it.
c03698
DM: So the 21 hits, the 18 misses.
c03699
DM: Um, that deals,
c03700
DM: uh, 15, 20 points of damage.
c03701
Unknown: Um, I will, uh-
c03702
DM: So that's 10.
c03703
Seeker: Well, but I'm gonna, um, deflect it.
c03704
DM: You used your reaction, so it's none.
c03705
Unknown: Yes.
c03706
Delwath: Does it take 10?
c03707
Delwath: No, it takes more than that. No, it's D10 plus, plus 24, so it auto- I auto- automatically deflect it.
c03708
DM: Yeah, you automatically deflect it.
c03709
Delwath: And I do two damage back to it.
c03710
DM: The redirect attack costs a ki.
c03711
Unknown: That's fine.
c03712
DM: So you spent four ki.
c03713
Unknown: Yep.
c03714
DM: So you, so you spent seven ki total, so you have 12 ki left.
c03715
Unknown: Yep.
c03716
Unknown: And then it gets a-
c03717
Unknown: DC, DC 18
c03718
DM: ... uh, it succeeds on that.
c03719
Kenzo: So it does not take any damage.
c03720
DM: It doesn't take any damage, yeah.
c03721
Unknown: Okay. Okay, but I take zero damage.
c03722
DM: Yes. And then, um,
c03723
DM: uh,
c03724
DM: for...
c03725
DM: Sorry, then Shimmering Light is, is going to surround it again and it's gonna heal a little more.
c03726
Unknown: It's g- it's healing itself?
c03727
DM: Yeah.
c03728
DM: Uh, that ends its turn.
c03729
DM: It's not any longer blinded.
c03730
DM: Seeker 6 is up. Seeker 6 is, hears you coming, so
c03731
DM: has, cannot really target anything with a spell, but can, like, ready an action or something.
c03732
Unknown: I mean, he could drop the wall.
c03733
DM: He could drop the wall. He could actually drop the wall if he wanted to.
c03734
Unknown: Seeker?
c03735
DM: Seeker 6.
c03736
Unknown: Just summon a location on the wall and then-
c03737
Kenzo: I know, but I'm asking Seeker what-
c03738
Seeker: But is that a good idea or not?
c03739
Unknown: No, probably not.
c03740
Seeker: Is there anything useful I can do from inside the wall?
c03741
DM: Mm-mm.
c03742
Seeker: Probably not. Are there any
c03743
Seeker: attack spells that don't require seeing the thing?
c03744
DM: Uh, if you knew this thing's name.
c03745
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c03746
Unknown: Hmm.
c03747
DM: But we don't.
c03748
DM: But you don't.
c03749
Unknown: I guess...
c03750
Unknown: I don't know.
c03751
Delwath: I think he's better
c03752
Unknown: not.
c03753
Delwath: Maybe he should drop the wall. 'Cause then the ladder could get out too.
c03754
Seeker: Yeah, but this guy is hacking at the wall.
c03755
Unknown: I know. I know.
c03756
Seeker: So he's not attacking anybody-
c03757
Unknown: Yeah
c03758
Seeker: ... while he's hacking at the wall.
c03759
Unknown: Yeah.
c03760
Seeker: But it doesn't look like it's almost down.
c03761
DM: It does look like it's almost down.
c03762
Seeker: Oh, it does look like it's almost down.
c03763
DM: It's probably one or two solid hits and it's gonna break.
c03764
Seeker: I will ready chain lightning-
c03765
Delwath: Oh, ready an action for when the wall breaks.
c03766
Seeker: For when the wall breaks.
c03767
DM: Seeker 6 has no seventh level slots 'cause y- you used the seventh level slot to create Seeker 6.
c03768
Seeker: I can cast it at
c03769
Unknown: six.
c03770
DM: Oh, right. It's a sixth level spell.
c03771
DM: I forgot. Yes, okay.
c03772
DM: Ready chain lightning for when the wall breaks.
c03773
DM: That's a good move.
c03774
Unknown: Okay.
c03775
Seeker: And the, the ladder will ready-
c03776
DM: Just-
c03777
Seeker: ... doing ladder stuff.
c03778
DM: Right
c03779
Seeker: ... when the wall breaks.
c03780
DM: Okay, so that's Seeker 6's move.
c03781
DM: Seeker is up.
c03782
Seeker: Seeker Prime will cast, uh, which one did I see?
c03783
Seeker: Rune of Psychic Disruption
c03784
Seeker: at, what level?
c03785
DM: At the-
c03786
Unknown: [coughs]
c03787
DM: ... sunlight head or the metallic blood?
c03788
Unknown: Sunlight head.
c03789
Delwath: Sunlight head, but I'd save high level.
c03790
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Psychic Disruption can go down to fourth.
c03791
Unknown: I'd do fourth.
c03792
Seeker: I'll do a fourth level Rune of Psychic Disruption.
c03793
DM: W- that's an int save?
c03794
Unknown: Yeah.
c03795
Seeker: Yep, 19, DC 19 int save.
c03796
DM: Uh, it fails.
c03797
Seeker: On a failed save, the target saves takes 7d6 psychic damage.
c03798
DM: And is incapacitated.
c03799
Seeker: And is incapacitated until the start of your next turn.
c03800
Unknown: Ooh.
c03801
Seeker: That was the key thing. He's incapacitated.
c03802
Unknown: There's seven.
c03803
Unknown: Oh, thanks.
c03804
Delwath: And is Delwath next?
c03805
DM: Delwath is next, yep So as Seeker's runic-
c03806
Delwath: Okay, where'd Kenzo go?
c03807
DM: ... explodes in this thing's head
c03808
Unknown: Kenzo, Kenzo. I was just
c03809
DM: Kenzo's being repaired
c03810
DM: Yeah.
c03811
Seeker: 15, 18.
c03812
DM: Okay. Um,
c03813
Unknown: Delwath-
c03814
DM: 18 damage?
c03815
Unknown: Yep.
c03816
Delwath: Delwath is gonna call down Yazali's Curse on this thing.
c03817
DM: Okay.
c03818
Delwath: And then attack
c03819
Unknown: from here.
c03820
DM: Okay.
c03821
Delwath: First attack is, uh, 24
c03822
Delwath: It's not doing much, but... [laughs]
c03823
Unknown: That's ridiculous.
c03824
DM: Okay.
c03825
Kenzo: On that, you know, he's extra angry.
c03826
Delwath: Wait, why am I rolling with advantage?
c03827
Unknown: I-
c03828
DM: Ah, Wellby
c03829
Delwath: ... 'cause of Wellby, right. Uh, do you care about damage types?
c03830
DM: No, not for this one.
c03831
Unknown: Oh.
c03832
DM: The other one, yes, but not this one.
c03833
Delwath: Uh, 14, uh,
c03834
Unknown: That's fantastic
c03835
Unknown: 12,
c03836
Unknown: That's an umbrella
c03837
Unknown: 26, 27
c03838
DM: Okay.
c03839
Seeker: Like an umbrella.
c03840
Unknown: Second attack
c03841
Unknown: Set up
c03842
Delwath: ... uh, is 15, 20,
c03843
Unknown: 32.
c03844
DM: Okay.
c03845
Unknown: Um,
c03846
Delwath: third attack is a crit.
c03847
Delwath: So that's 8,
c03848
Delwath: uh, sorry. Um, 8
c03849
Unknown: plus
c03850
Unknown: 6 is 14,
c03851
Delwath: plus 15 is, uh, 29, plus, um, 4 is 33, plus
c03852
Unknown: 7 is 40.
c03853
DM: Okay. This one's Wellpath bloodied.
c03854
Unknown: Stop that, you ruined my... [laughs]
c03855
Unknown: Yeah.
c03856
DM: That ends Delwath's turn?
c03857
Delwath: Um, yeah.
c03858
Delwath: I'm just trying to think if I wanna move.
c03859
Delwath: Actually, this is a pretty good position for us, to be honest,
c03860
Delwath: keeping Se- Seekers, like, you know...
c03861
Delwath: Delwath will just stay right here.
c03862
Unknown: [laughs]
c03863
DM: Um...
c03864
Kenzo: I'm gonna do this. I'm more ridiculous.
c03865
Unknown: [laughs]
c03866
DM: Uh, okay. The, uh, this, um,
c03867
DM: creature
c03868
DM: is going to turn around and see that its ally is being, um, in trouble,
c03869
DM: and it's going to do, um-
c03870
Delwath: Oh, uh, sorry.
c03871
Unknown: Add
c03872
Unknown: 6.
c03873
Delwath: I hit three times, add 18 damage.
c03874
Unknown: Yeah.
c03875
DM: Okay.
c03876
Unknown: Boom.
c03877
DM: Its ally is on death's door.
c03878
DM: Uh, 18, that's...
c03879
DM: Its ally is on death's door, and it is going to turn...
c03880
DM: First, it's gonna make one last strike at the wall.
c03881
DM: Um, the wall is gonna collapse.
c03882
Unknown: Uh-oh.
c03883
Delwath: Chain lightning.
c03884
DM: So chain lightning goes off.
c03885
Seeker: Oh, my God. What do I... I haven't cast that before.
c03886
Seeker: I actually said... What level would I remember it?
c03887
DM: 6th.
c03888
Unknown: 6th.
c03889
DM: So that's a 6th level slot from-
c03890
Seeker: Oh, for Seeker 6, yeah
c03891
DM: ... Seeker 6. I got Seeker 6.
c03892
Seeker: And so let's
c03893
Unknown: see. Um-
c03894
Unknown: You launch a po- lightning bolt.
c03895
Delwath: Three bolts then away from the targets as many as three other targets.
c03896
Seeker: And it's a dex save.
c03897
Delwath: So it's a dex save.
c03898
Seeker: And then it's 10d8, yeah.
c03899
Unknown: That's 4d8.
c03900
Unknown: That's 68 right there.
c03901
DM: Sorry, the first-
c03902
Unknown: I'll just do 5, but...
c03903
Unknown: Yeah
c03904
DM: ... so the first guy makes a dex save.
c03905
Unknown: Well, both of them do.
c03906
DM: Both of them make dex saves.
c03907
Unknown: Yeah.
c03908
DM: Okay.
c03909
DM: That's a 20 for the first one.
c03910
Seeker: That makes it, it's 19.
c03911
DM: And it's a 17 for the second one.
c03912
Unknown: So this guy fails-
c03913
DM: Okay
c03914
Unknown: ... and connects it?
c03915
DM: Yes.
c03916
Seeker: So it's 5d8 for the first guy.
c03917
Delwath: Well, no, you just rolled once, 10d8.
c03918
Unknown: One takes 10, the other one takes half.
c03919
Unknown: [laughs] It's like-
c03920
DM: I mean, it's Limbo. You can make it however you want.
c03921
Kenzo: Yeah, when Kenzo fights, when he's angry, his staff gets-
c03922
Unknown: 14, 18, 23
c03923
Kenzo: ... his stuff gets all angry, and his stuff gets lit.
c03924
Unknown: 20. All right, 23.
c03925
Seeker: 23.
c03926
Unknown: Now,
c03927
Delwath: 15 plus 5.
c03928
Unknown: Wasn't that a 5?
c03929
Delwath: You had two 7s, an 8 and a 5.
c03930
Delwath: That's not 23. Two 7s, an 8 and a 5.
c03931
Delwath: Two 7, a 7 and 8 is 15, plus 5 is 20, plus 7 is 27.
c03932
Seeker: 27.
c03933
Unknown: Yeah. Well, that's what I said.
c03934
DM: 27 damage.
c03935
Unknown: Now roll it once more.
c03936
DM: Wait, it's 10d8?
c03937
Unknown: Yeah.
c03938
DM: That's a lot of damage
c03939
Unknown: It's a 6th level spell.
c03940
DM: That's great.
c03941
Unknown: 39.
c03942
c03943
DM: 39 total?
c03944
Delwath: Yeah. So one takes 39, one takes half of it.
c03945
DM: Half 39 is,
c03946
DM: uh, 19.
c03947
DM: Um-
c03948
Unknown: Does that kill this guy?
c03949
DM: That one's dead, yeah.
c03950
Delwath: I'm gonna move the Hexblade's Curse to this guy.
c03951
DM: Okay.
c03952
DM: Um-
c03953
Seeker: Chain lightning. Good job, Seeker 6
c03954
Unknown: Yeah.
c03955
DM: Now-
c03956
Unknown: Seeker 6
c03957
DM: ... Ladder gets to attack
c03958
Seeker: That's a 12, plus 11, 23.
c03959
DM: That hits.
c03960
Seeker: And, oh, I forget his
c03961
Seeker: damage.
c03962
Seeker: How does that one work? What's that creature-
c03963
Unknown: The Ladder?
c03964
Unknown: ... even called?
c03965
Seeker: I have to look it up.
c03966
Unknown: And it's... Orenlas
c03967
DM: It's... I think it's-
c03968
Seeker: Dancing. Item
c03969
DM: Yeah.
c03970
Seeker: 1d10 plus PB, which is the 11-
c03971
DM: 6
c03972
Unknown: ... 6.
c03973
Unknown: 6.
c03974
Seeker: D10 plus 6.
c03975
DM: Don't forget about the Ladder's 10-foot move speed aura.
c03976
Unknown: Oh.
c03977
Seeker: So that's 13 damage.
c03978
DM: Okay.
c03979
DM: So that ends the reactions.
c03980
DM: It used one of its attacks.
c03981
DM: It is now gonna make the rest of its attacks.
c03982
DM: Um,
c03983
DM: the first thing it's going to do is-
c03984
Delwath: Wait, can it still see? Oh, no, we're all not invisible anyway
c03985
DM: You're all not invisible anyway. But no, once the light...
c03986
DM: I mean, if you were still invisible when the light ended-
c03987
Unknown: Right
c03988
DM: ... it would, you would be invisible, but it was also the one who saw you from the start.
c03989
Unknown: Right, right
c03990
Unknown: Right.
c03991
DM: Um,
c03992
DM: uh, it is going to,
c03993
DM: um... Who is it gonna target?
c03994
DM: Well, Seeker 6 just cast the lightning bolt, so
c03995
DM: Seeker 6...
c03996
DM: Oh, actually let's do the burn assertion first.
c03997
DM: Um,
c03998
DM: Delwath did a ton of damage to it.
c03999
DM: Delwath, make a constitution saving throw.
c04000
Delwath: Uh, 22.
c04001
DM: Okay. You succeed.
c04002
DM: Nothing happens.
c04003
DM: Um,
c04004
DM: then
c04005
DM: Seeker 6,
c04006
DM: uh-
c04007
Unknown: Let's get it
c04008
DM: ... um, it's going to attack Seeker 6 twice
c04009
Unknown: ... first and then whatever.
c04010
Unknown: Cool
c04011
DM: Um, that's an 18 and a 16.
c04012
DM: [die rolls]
c04013
Seeker: I think they both hit probably.
c04014
DM: Um, so that's going to be one,
c04015
DM: two, three-
c04016
Kenzo: Really happy with Kenza
c04017
DM: ... four.
c04018
Unknown: [laughs]
c04019
DM: That's
c04020
DM: ... it's ridiculous.
c04021
DM: 20,
c04022
DM: 23-
c04023
Unknown: Wait, why is this in your hand?
c04024
Unknown: That's my fuck you.
c04025
DM: 23.
c04026
Kenzo: Ah, fuck you. Yeah. Right.
c04027
DM: 37 points of damage on Seeker 6.
c04028
DM: So that-
c04029
Unknown: Whoa.
c04030
Unknown: [laughs]
c04031
c04032
DM: So that-
c04033
Delwath: Every time somebody like we, they actually...
c04034
Unknown: [laughs]
c04035
DM: That puts Seeker 6 at, at 50.
c04036
DM: Um-
c04037
Unknown: Oh
c04038
DM: ... uh, it heals.
c04039
Wellby: How's it, uh, how's it doing?
c04040
Delwath: Well, this one's dead.
c04041
Unknown: Hey, great.
c04042
DM: And then, um-
c04043
Delwath: Seeker 6 cast a big lightning bolt to kill both of them.
c04044
Unknown: Yeah.
c04045
DM: Uh, that's a-
c04046
Unknown: Very pleased
c04047
DM: ... 30 to hit Seeker 6.
c04048
Unknown: Uh-oh
c04049
DM: ... Seeker-
c04050
Delwath: But is also probably not gonna survive
c04051
DM: ... 6 takes 10-
c04052
Wellby: That'd be the thing we remember him for
c04053
DM: ... um,
c04054
DM: another 16 plus 40, 12.
c04055
DM: [die rolls]
c04056
Unknown: Uh-oh.
c04057
Delwath: How many hit points does he have?
c04058
Seeker: 50 left I think he has.
c04059
DM: 16 plus-
c04060
Unknown: No, 'cause you have more than that
c04061
DM: ... he started with 87.
c04062
Delwath: Oh, 'cause he starts with half.
c04063
DM: Half, yes. So sorry, that was-
c04064
Unknown: I was thinking-
c04065
DM: That was-
c04066
Unknown: Doesn't Erak have, doesn't Seeker have like-
c04067
DM: 16. Sorry.
c04068
DM: 16 plus 12.
c04069
Kenzo: Rolling real dice is fun, but doing the math is-
c04070
DM: I know. It takes forever.
c04071
Unknown: [laughs]
c04072
DM: 16 plus 12 is 28.
c04073
Unknown: You can just roll.
c04074
DM: 30.
c04075
Kenzo: Yeah, I think that's the way.
c04076
DM: Um, plus 11 is
c04077
DM: 41. Seeker 6 is gone.
c04078
Unknown: [laughs]
c04079
Unknown: Hold on.
c04080
DM: Oh, goodbye Seeker 6.
c04081
Unknown: Aw.
c04082
Seeker: Ah. There goes our big plan for Seeker 6 to save the day.
c04083
DM: Seeker 6 crumbles into ice.
c04084
Unknown: No.
c04085
DM: Still smiling with the image of his massive lightning bolt.
c04086
DM: Um-
c04087
Seeker: It was a good way to go out
c04088
DM: ... killing.
c04089
Unknown: We tried to save you.
c04090
Seeker: And the, the wall of stone plan worked well for us.
c04091
DM: It did, and-
c04092
DM: Uh, that ends it
c04093
Seeker: ... and you know, he, he saved the life of the most important person.
c04094
Delwath: Right. There you go. [laughs]
c04095
Kenzo: I don't know, man. That's still pretty bad.
c04096
Kenzo: Seeker 6 could cast a lot of spells and do a lot of shit.
c04097
Seeker: That's pretty rough. He-
c04098
Delwath: That was a, that was a short lived Seeker 6.
c04099
Unknown: Yeah.
c04100
Kenzo: That's right. This, this, this was not a good-
c04101
DM: That ends-
c04102
Unknown: Oh, man
c04103
DM: ... um, the Metallic Blood's turn.
c04104
DM: It is now Kenza, Wellby-
c04105
Delwath: We just cast Wish to make a Seeker 7.
c04106
Unknown: [die rolls]
c04107
Unknown: Is it instant?
c04108
DM: Wish is instant, yeah.
c04109
Unknown: Okay.
c04110
DM: Kenza, Wellby, Seeker, and Delwath all get turns before it goes again.
c04111
Wellby: What round? Is this round two?
c04112
DM: This is round two.
c04113
Unknown: This is round two. [laughs]
c04114
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. And you haven't done anything since the last...
c04115
Unknown: Yeah.
c04116
Unknown: That's wild.
c04117
Delwath: So you still have advantage on this.
c04118
Delwath: Oh, no, you don't get your advantage.
c04119
Unknown: All
c04120
Unknown: right.
c04121
DM: From Vax.
c04122
Kenzo: Soul site on this guy.
c04123
Unknown: We killed the guy.
c04124
DM: CR 19.
c04125
Wellby: A hippogriff, that's right.
c04126
Kenzo: He's a CR 19 guy. CR 19.
c04127
Unknown: CR 19.
c04128
Kenzo: Okay. This is, this is-
c04129
DM: Um, this one-
c04130
Delwath: That's like real
c04131
DM: ... this-
c04132
Delwath: I'm glad I ha- I, I'm glad I used all his curse then
c04133
DM: ... this one is resistant to, um, fire, necrotic, and slashing damage.
c04134
DM: Immune to charmed, frightened, exhausted.
c04135
Kenzo: Uh, what about, uh, ability things?
c04136
DM: Oh, um,
c04137
DM: uh,
c04138
DM: bad at...
c04139
DM: Well, good at con,
c04140
DM: bad at dex.
c04141
Unknown: Excellent.
c04142
Kenzo: What about charisma or wisdom?
c04143
DM: You just get best and worst.
c04144
DM: Best is con, worst is dex.
c04145
Kenzo: Fuck. All right. Um,
c04146
Unknown: I will attack,
c04147
Unknown: um...
c04148
Kenzo: Yeah, but I'm, I'm... So aura focus on this dude.
c04149
Kenzo: Where's the thing where I do an extra, extra D12?
c04150
DM: That's just... It's one attack, but just declare which one you're doing 'cause if you roll a crit it gets doubled, but you can't just wait.
c04151
DM: You have to say it before the attack, so you have to...
c04152
DM: You can't just wait till you-
c04153
Kenzo: Okay. And I get advantage now?
c04154
DM: No, the advantage is over.
c04155
Kenzo: What? I never, I never got advantage...
c04156
Wellby: 'Cause you only had advantage on the other guy.
c04157
Unknown: Damn it.
c04158
Wellby: The other guy.
c04159
Unknown: All right.
c04160
DM: Yeah.
c04161
Kenzo: Uh, 19.
c04162
DM: 19 misses.
c04163
Unknown: Fuck.
c04164
Unknown: Uh-oh.
c04165
DM: That misses.
c04166
Kenzo: Misses. Uh,
c04167
Unknown: 24.
c04168
DM: That hits.
c04169
Unknown: Uh.
c04170
DM: So just do your extra D12 now.
c04171
Unknown: Okay. Extra D12 and then-
c04172
DM: So two D12.
c04173
Unknown: Seeker?
c04174
Unknown: Uh, I'm up.
c04175
Unknown: Oh, Wellby.
c04176
DM: Wellby's next.
c04177
DM: [die rolls]
c04178
Unknown: Two D12.
c04179
Unknown: Where's the D-
c04180
DM: Then Seeker's after Wellby, then Delwath is last.
c04181
Unknown: Give him another.
c04182
Kenzo: Oh, that's good.
c04183
Kenzo: Uh, 19 plus 5 is-
c04184
Unknown: 24
c04185
Unknown: ... yes,
c04186
Kenzo: 24.
c04187
Kenzo: Second unarmed strike,
c04188
Unknown: 20.
c04189
DM: Uh, 20 misses.
c04190
Unknown: Fuck.
c04191
Unknown: Geez.
c04192
Kenzo: Third unarmed strike,
c04193
Kenzo: uh, 22.
c04194
DM: That hits.
c04195
Kenzo: Oh, just one. And then-
c04196
DM: Yeah, that's your last attack. No, your last attack
c04197
Unknown: ... 15.
c04198
DM: Okay
c04199
DM: [dice rattling] That ends Kenzo's turn as you rush forward and, and punch into this gooey metallic blood.
c04200
DM: Uh, that ends your turn.
c04201
DM: Seeker is up.
c04202
Unknown: It says it's resistant to slashing.
c04203
DM: Slashing, yeah.
c04204
Wellby: Uh, Wellby's up.
c04205
DM: Sorry, Wellby's up. Yeah, yeah.
c04206
Wellby: Uh, I'll move over here.
c04207
Wellby: Uh, shoot with advantage, sneak attack, uh, blinding.
c04208
Wellby: [die rolling] That's a 23.
c04209
DM: Uh, okay.
c04210
DM: 23 hits.
c04211
Wellby: Uh, uh, DC 19 dex save.
c04212
Wellby: [paper rustling] Uh.
c04213
DM: So, so just so you know, this, this creature does not have any obvious eyes.
c04214
Wellby: Uh, it was not immune to the blinded condition.
c04215
DM: Uh, yes, but if it has blindsight-
c04216
Delwath: If it had blindsight, then it's not immune.
c04217
Wellby: It's still...
c04218
Unknown: Just doesn't, yeah.
c04219
DM: Blindsight means... Blindsight is like...
c04220
DM: If it has blindsight, it would still be able to see regardless of whether it's blind or not.
c04221
DM: It's a bit semantic whether it's immune to the blinded condition.
c04222
Wellby: Uh, okay. And this was the one that saw us when we first came in.
c04223
DM: This was the one that's-
c04224
Wellby: So it's reasonable to assume that it has blindsight, yeah.
c04225
DM: Yes. So you might want... I'm saying you might want to do something different.
c04226
Wellby: Yeah. Uh, con, con, uh, how about crit?
c04227
Delwath: Prone is always good.
c04228
Wellby: Yeah.
c04229
DM: Okay.
c04230
Wellby: Prone.
c04231
Wellby: Uh, that gives me a couple more dice too.
c04232
DM: Uh, that's a 22 on the save though.
c04233
Wellby: Yeah, that, uh... That's it. Sorry, one, three, six, seven,
c04234
Wellby: nine.
c04235
Wellby: Uh, so,
c04236
Wellby: uh, nine,
c04237
Wellby: 10,
c04238
Wellby: 20, 31, 32, 30, s- uh,
c04239
Wellby: eight.
c04240
DM: Okay.
c04241
Wellby: Uh, and then I'll shoot again, not with sneak attack, but with-
c04242
DM: Just 'cause
c04243
Wellby: ... the other one. Uh, that's a 29.
c04244
Wellby: [die rolling] Uh, seven points of damage.
c04245
DM: Okay. So Wellby's two arrows strike into this thing, um,
c04246
DM: spraying the sort of metallic blood as its body is, like, constantly shaping and re-s- shaping itself.
c04247
DM: Uh, that brings up Seeker.
c04248
Seeker: Who, in honor of the fallen Seeker 6, casts Chain Lightning.
c04249
DM: Okay.
c04250
Seeker: Um, so that's a DC 19 dex save.
c04251
Unknown: [die rolling]
c04252
DM: That's a 24,
c04253
DM: so half damage.
c04254
Unknown: Uh, so 5d8.
c04255
DM: No, you roll... Just roll the whole thing and l- or just roll 5d8.
c04256
DM: It's fine. It doesn't matter. It's faster to just roll 5d8.
c04257
Unknown: Oh man, that was a terrible roll though.
c04258
Seeker: Six, seven.
c04259
Wellby: What?
c04260
Delwath: 5d8, nine, 10, 11, 12.
c04261
Seeker: 12. How'd I get that wrong too?
c04262
Wellby: Crappy rolls.
c04263
DM: It's... It is bloodied though.
c04264
DM: Uh, sorry. Yes, it is bloodied.
c04265
DM: Just barely bloodied.
c04266
DM: That end Seeker's turn, unless...
c04267
DM: Oh, no, Ladder.
c04268
Seeker: The Ladder attacks.
c04269
Seeker: [die rolling] That's a 21 to hit.
c04270
DM: That just hits.
c04271
Unknown: Uh,
c04272
Seeker: I already forget. [laughs]
c04273
Wellby: 20, 10.
c04274
DM: 20, 10 plus six.
c04275
Wellby: Plus six.
c04276
Unknown: Thanks.
c04277
Wellby: Can the Ladder grapple him?
c04278
DM: Oh.
c04279
Wellby: Is that useful?
c04280
DM: Yeah.
c04281
Seeker: I was thinking that earlier, but I forgot.
c04282
Unknown: Yeah, just, just grapple.
c04283
Seeker: So there, there's... I don't roll for damage.
c04284
DM: So you don't roll for dam- damage.
c04285
DM: It's just grappled.
c04286
Seeker: Well, now he's grappled. Look at that.
c04287
Delwath: Does grappled give any advantages to people attacking now, right?
c04288
DM: Uh, the main thing that grapple does is he has disadvantage if he attacks anybody other than the person grappling him.
c04289
Wellby: Okay.
c04290
Unknown: Okay.
c04291
Wellby: That's great. That's fair. For everyone except the Ladder.
c04292
Unknown: Yeah.
c04293
Delwath: But this is the Ladder's job.
c04294
Seeker: The Ladder is a self-sacrificing hero.
c04295
DM: Yeah.
c04296
Seeker: As we know.
c04297
Kenzo: He climbs so other may as ri- others may rise.
c04298
DM: Yeah, exactly.
c04299
Unknown: [laughs]
c04300
DM: Yeah.
c04301
Seeker: That's probably the Ladder's... See, now it makes sense.
c04302
Unknown: You know what I think.
c04303
DM: It's, it's-
c04304
DM: Okay, uh-
c04305
Wellby: It's unfortunately close to the s- um-
c04306
DM: Kenzo, make a-
c04307
Wellby: ... she said so he could run the, like-
c04308
DM: Make a constitution saving throw.
c04309
Wellby: Why?
c04310
Delwath: 'Cause it's trying to do something bad to him.
c04311
DM: Oh, sorry. Wait, Delwath's turn. I forgot about Delwath's turn.
c04312
Unknown: Yeah, I was gonna say. Wait.
c04313
Delwath: Okay, I'm attacking. Wait, I don't have advantage or anything yet, right?
c04314
DM: No.
c04315
Wellby: Oh, I crit.
c04316
Wellby: You crit on a 19?
c04317
Wellby: Yeah.
c04318
Wellby: Sick.
c04319
Delwath: Against the creatures that I'm-
c04320
Wellby: Oh.
c04321
Delwath: Oh, wait, but I need to know which one am I slashing?
c04322
Wellby: Uh,
c04323
Delwath: so that's, uh, eight,
c04324
Delwath: nine, 13.
c04325
Delwath: [die rolling] Uh, plus six.
c04326
Delwath: Uh, 13, 16 plus eight
c04327
Delwath: is 24, 25 force damage.
c04328
DM: Okay.
c04329
Unknown: Plus,
c04330
Unknown: uh,
c04331
Delwath: uh, six damage. I don't know what the bonus damage is.
c04332
DM: It's always your weapon type.
c04333
Wellby: [die rolling] Plus nine.
c04334
Delwath: So then nine, 10.
c04335
Wellby: 9 plus 12.
c04336
Wellby: 21.
c04337
DM: Okay.
c04338
Wellby: 21 slashing.
c04339
Wellby: Um, that's my first attack.
c04340
Seeker: Should've given Seeker 6 some of those potions.
c04341
Wellby: Potions are a bonus action, right?
c04342
DM: Potion is a bonus action, yep.
c04343
Wellby: Uh, that'll miss.
c04344
Seeker: Never did it. Oh, well.
c04345
Unknown: Probably.
c04346
Wellby: That's an idea for the future though.
c04347
Wellby: It's, like, you from all the dead.
c04348
Delwath: Uh, 22 hits, right?
c04349
DM: That hits, yep.
c04350
Wellby: The future.
c04351
DM: Seeker 7?
c04352
Unknown: Oh, oh, uh, wow.
c04353
Wellby: Huh? Seeker 7's gonna make an appearance soon?
c04354
Seeker: I, I think so. And then I'll-
c04355
DM: I mean it-
c04356
Seeker: ... Dragon Up.
c04357
DM: Well, you can't Seeker 7 and Dragon Up.
c04358
Seeker: Oh, you're right.
c04359
Wellby: Yeah.
c04360
DM: You only have one ninth level slot.
c04361
Wellby: 6, 11,
c04362
Wellby: 13,
c04363
Wellby: um-
c04364
Wellby: Let's see what we-
c04365
Delwath: 13 force and 18 slashing.
c04366
Kenzo: If Seeker 7 can Seeker 7, does that go to level 12?
c04367
Unknown: No. Okay.
c04368
DM: Um.
c04369
Delwath: 'Cause you won't have the slot.
c04370
Delwath: That you only have the slots... Wait, does it only have the slots that it has when you create it?
c04371
Delwath: Yeah, if you create a Seeker 6 now-
c04372
Unknown: So weak
c04373
DM: ... it's gonna be very weak 'cause you spent so many slots.
c04374
Wellby: Spent slots.
c04375
Wellby: I realize that.
c04376
Wellby: That's right.
c04377
Unknown: And-
c04378
Wellby: Yeah. There we go
c04379
DM: That... Are you bonus actioning?
c04380
Unknown: Yeah.
c04381
DM: So Delwath sl- slashes at it three times.
c04382
DM: His sword, again, bending through space to target this creature
c04383
Delwath: It, it seems relatively, it's not...
c04384
Delwath: Yeah, I'm not gonna roll this action
c04385
DM: Okay. Kenzo, make a constitution saving throw
c04386
Unknown: With advantage, right?
c04387
DM: Nope
c04388
Kenzo: With, um, the heals disadvantage, right?
c04389
DM: [laughs] If you fail you can re-roll it with a ki.
c04390
DM: Uh-
c04391
Unknown: 16
c04392
DM: ... that fails
c04393
Unknown: I'll roll a ki
c04394
DM: Probably-
c04395
Kenzo: Or actually, I'll, I'll hold weapons. I- I'll, uh, I...
c04396
Kenzo: It'd be better to do bardic with that, right?
c04397
Unknown: 16.
c04398
Delwath: Uh, yeah. Well, bardics are less...
c04399
Delwath: Oh, no. We can short... If we get a short rest everything comes back.
c04400
DM: Your ki and your bardic comes back
c04401
Unknown: Your ki and your bardic and your heroic comes back
c04402
DM: I mean, you're probably running relativ- you're running a bit low on ki at the moment, but-
c04403
Kenzo: Yeah. No, no, I'm not.
c04404
Kenzo: I still have, like, more than 10.
c04405
Kenzo: Um, I will-
c04406
DM: No
c04407
Kenzo: ... I will bard-
c04408
DM: N- no, you can't have more than... Well
c04409
Wellby: Do you get two D12 on the bardic first aid or just one?
c04410
DM: No, it's just one D12, but you get temp HP equal to the...
c04411
Kenzo: I think bardic
c04412
Wellby: So you think it's probably-
c04413
DM: I don't know
c04414
Wellby: ... a DC 20 kind of thing?
c04415
Kenzo: Yeah, I mean, I've got 16 right now
c04416
Wellby: Still got a two in three chance of...
c04417
Kenzo: Yeah, I will, I will do some bardic.
c04418
Wellby: Yeah, that's good.
c04419
Unknown: Yeah, that's great
c04420
DM: Yeah, that succeeds
c04421
Kenzo: And I get hit points back?
c04422
DM: You get seven temp hit HP.
c04423
DM: Um,
c04424
DM: uh, okay. Then,
c04425
DM: um,
c04426
DM: it's going to
c04427
DM: attack the ladder.
c04428
Unknown: [laughs] Naturally.
c04429
DM: Uh-
c04430
Kenzo: So heavy my staff now
c04431
DM: [laughs] Um, all of those hit
c04432
Delwath: Oof. The ladder might be in for it
c04433
DM: The ladder takes,
c04434
DM: uh,
c04435
DM: 30-
c04436
Unknown: Not good
c04437
DM: ... 37-
c04438
Unknown: That's not so bad
c04439
DM: ... piercing plus-
c04440
Unknown: Yeah
c04441
DM: ... 15 slashing
c04442
Delwath: 37 plus 15, 40 something
c04443
DM: 52
c04444
DM: plus 25 necrotic
c04445
Seeker: 72. How many hit points does the ladder have
c04446
Seeker: Uh, 10 plus five times your bard level.
c04447
Seeker: My bard level is 19, right?
c04448
Unknown: So-
c04449
Seeker: 50, 40, 90, 100.
c04450
Seeker: It has 100
c04451
Delwath: And just took 87, so it has 13
c04452
DM: 13 hit points left.
c04453
DM: Um,
c04454
DM: and then...
c04455
DM: Oh, can it do that too? Yes.
c04456
DM: Um-
c04457
Wellby: It surrenders?
c04458
Unknown: [laughs]
c04459
DM: Uh, the-
c04460
Unknown: I yield
c04461
DM: ... the-
c04462
Wellby: I'm made out of wood. I don't like it
c04463
Wellby: [laughs]
c04464
DM: Wellby and
c04465
DM: Seeker both made constitution saving throws.
c04466
DM: I didn't realize I could do this. Oh, well.
c04467
DM: It's fine. It would have attacked the ladder anyways, angry, and you might succeed
c04468
Unknown: 14
c04469
Unknown: Five
c04470
DM: Um-
c04471
Unknown: [laughs]
c04472
Delwath: Boston's never been-
c04473
Unknown: Oh my God
c04474
Unknown: ... like this.
c04475
Delwath: From dumping tea in the harbor-
c04476
Unknown: What the hell?
c04477
Unknown: ... to the taxage-
c04478
Kenzo: That was crazy. Where the hell did that guy come from?
c04479
DM: You, you both take 15 points of necrotic damage
c04480
Unknown: That's-
c04481
DM: Uh, and it is going to teleport right next to Wellby
c04482
Unknown: 15 you said?
c04483
Unknown: Oh
c04484
DM: That ends its turn
c04485
Unknown: Seeing how we killed it
c04486
Wellby: I will use my reaction to move away from it
c04487
DM: Okay
c04488
Unknown: You're up
c04489
Wellby: Uh, Kenzo's up
c04490
DM: Kenzo's up
c04491
Unknown: Kenzo, you're up.
c04492
Kenzo: It is over here now?
c04493
DM: Yeah
c04494
DM: It teleported.
c04495
Kenzo: Okay. I will engage it.
c04496
Kenzo: And do I have no advantage or anything?
c04497
DM: No advantage
c04498
Unknown: Damn it.
c04499
Unknown: Okay.
c04500
Kenzo: That hits. Uh, oh s-
c04501
DM: 11
c04502
Kenzo: Uh, no, but I think... Sorry, I have to check
c04503
Unknown: on my computer.
c04504
Kenzo: Um,
c04505
Kenzo: uh, no. My staff is plus seven.
c04506
Kenzo: Okay, yeah. So that's, uh, 13
c04507
DM: 13 damage
c04508
Kenzo: 13 damage first attack.
c04509
Kenzo: Second attack, 23
c04510
DM: Uh, 23 damage or 23 to hit?
c04511
Unknown: 23 hits
c04512
DM: 23 hits, yep
c04513
Kenzo: And that's, uh, 12.
c04514
Kenzo: I'm gonna roll another D12.
c04515
Kenzo: Ooh, 22.
c04516
Kenzo: Uh, first unarmed strike,
c04517
Kenzo: 29 hits
c04518
DM: Yep
c04519
Kenzo: Um, 11 damage.
c04520
Kenzo: Second unarmed strike,
c04521
Kenzo: 21, hits
c04522
DM: 21 hits, yep
c04523
Unknown: 16 damage.
c04524
Kenzo: Last unarmed strike. Oh, crit fail.
c04525
Kenzo: Or yeah, fail one.
c04526
DM: Uh, sorry, 16 was the last one.
c04527
Unknown: Yeah
c04528
DM: Um, so-
c04529
Unknown: And that's
c04530
Unknown: it
c04531
DM: Okay. It has a, it has a few hit points left
c04532
Unknown: Oh, God
c04533
DM: Seeker.
c04534
DM: Sorry, Wellby
c04535
Wellby: Uh, all right. I'm gonna try and trip it again.
c04536
Wellby: That's, uh, 26
c04537
DM: That hits
c04538
Wellby: DC 19 dex
c04539
DM: Well, let me see what damage you do, 'cause it might kill it
c04540
Wellby: 10-
c04541
Wellby: Uh, 10.
c04542
Unknown: Well, probably
c04543
Wellby: ... 15, 21, 26
c04544
DM: Oh, that kills it. It had 24 left.
c04545
DM: So your arrow flies into it as you're aiming to trip it, and it just slumps onto the ground
c04546
Unknown: Phew.
c04547
Unknown: Short rest?
c04548
Seeker: Yeah, I, I need to heal up too.
c04549
Seeker: I'm at 54
c04550
Unknown: Hmm
c04551
Wellby: How short is a short rest?
c04552
Delwath: Well, a short rest is an hour, but I can cast prayer of healing, which gives us a short rest in 10 minutes
c04553
Unknown: Huh
c04554
DM: Wait, I thought I took damage
c04555
Seeker: When are we gonna do a memorial service for 0:06:15.0
c04556
Delwath: Right now
c04557
DM: Tim, didn't I take damage?
c04558
Unknown: Yeah
c04559
DM: You said you were keeping track of it
c04560
Unknown: A few minutes
c04561
DM: Oh-
c04562
Delwath: Well, a long time ago
c04563
DM: ... 25.
c04564
DM: Sorry, I-
c04565
Unknown: No, from the...
c04566
Delwath: I didn't take damage in combat. From the-
c04567
DM: Yeah, 25
c04568
Unknown: We know-
c04569
Unknown: I thought it was 11
c04570
Seeker: We remember him always
c04571
Kenzo: Well, you know what I'll remember most is, um-
c04572
DM: Didn't I... I thought I did that.
c04573
Wellby: I remember the time we went to the tower.
c04574
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c04575
Wellby: In Limbo.
c04576
Kenzo: Yeah, I remember that.
c04577
DM: Maybe it wasn't in the tower.
c04578
Unknown: I remember also when you-
c04579
DM: Let me just double check. I'm almost-
c04580
Unknown: ... climbed up that wall.
c04581
DM: I'm almost positive.
c04582
Unknown: Yeah.
c04583
Kenzo: With me. He was hiding in...
c04584
Seeker: He bravely
c04585
Seeker: pinned himself in, yeah.
c04586
Kenzo: Was in there, just-
c04587
Wellby: It probably doesn't matter. I get-
c04588
Seeker: And then bam, lightning
c04589
Wellby: ... I'm trying to see how much I get back.
c04590
Kenzo: Remember that lightning? That was great.
c04591
Unknown: Yeah.
c04592
Unknown: Getting back.
c04593
Delwath: Get 21 back.
c04594
DM: No, you're at 138 out of 153.
c04595
Unknown: [laughs]
c04596
c04597
DM: On my character sheet.
c04598
DM: Oh, it's not showing here.
c04599
Seeker: It's true. It's true.
c04600
Seeker: He found Rai with us.
c04601
Unknown: Okay, so it's 25.
c04602
Unknown: He was with us.
c04603
Unknown: Oh, he came with us.
c04604
DM: So it's 25.
c04605
Unknown: Yeah.
c04606
Unknown: Oh.
c04607
Unknown: Yeah.
c04608
Unknown: And then I healed 20.
c04609
Kenzo: Oh, we went, we went through a lot together.
c04610
Unknown: Yeah.
c04611
c04612
Unknown: We went through a lot.
c04613
Unknown: Uh-huh. Yeah.
c04614
Unknown: Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
c04615
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c04616
DM: Okay.
c04617
DM: And, uh-
c04618
Unknown: Um-
c04619
DM: I mean, think of how worse off you'd be if the ladder Seeker Six and the construct hadn't absorbed, like, 150 points of damage.
c04620
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
c04621
Unknown: Yeah.
c04622
DM: So are you gonna look around the room at all?
c04623
Unknown: Yeah.
c04624
DM: What do you wanna do?
c04625
Unknown: Yeah.
c04626
Wellby: Wait, short rest? Who needs to short rest?
c04627
Unknown: Short rest. Short rest.
c04628
Delwath: Well, so we-
c04629
DM: I mean,
c04630
DM: okay
c04631
Unknown: ...
c04632
Delwath: not, no, no, no. Prayer of healing short rest, I assume, not a real short rest.
c04633
DM: Okay. Yeah.
c04634
Delwath: That's still 10 minutes.
c04635
Seeker: And then how do I...
c04636
Unknown: I can get a lot of-
c04637
Wellby: Do we feel good about that?
c04638
DM: Do we feel like,
c04639
Delwath: do we f- I mean, I can only do this once per day.
c04640
Seeker: I, I need, in one way or another, to heal, and I could do a bunch of hit dice that way, so that's probably a good idea.
c04641
Delwath: I, I could do it. I mean, it's definitely useful for Delwath.
c04642
Delwath: I need to get back stuff.
c04643
Unknown: Yeah, that's it.
c04644
Wellby: I don't think I need to, need to.
c04645
Wellby: I can search the room-
c04646
Kenzo: I get all my ki back
c04647
Delwath: ... while you rest. You don't need to d- I mean, it's just a spell.
c04648
Delwath: I cast the spell, and then we all get a short rest.
c04649
Wellby: Oh, without doing any resting?
c04650
Unknown: Yeah, you don't have to do any-
c04651
Unknown: Just like a 10 minute-
c04652
Delwath: You have to, you have to stay within 30 feet of Delwath.
c04653
Wellby: Cast it. Oh, good. Stand in the middle of the room.
c04654
Unknown: Yeah.
c04655
Unknown: That's great.
c04656
Unknown: Let's do it.
c04657
DM: You're gonna search the room?
c04658
Wellby: Yes.
c04659
DM: Perception with advantage.
c04660
Unknown: [die rolling]
c04661
Seeker: But the rest of us are short resting.
c04662
Wellby: Uh, 33.
c04663
DM: Okay. Um, you-
c04664
Delwath: But taking 10 minutes
c04665
DM: ... you see several things.
c04666
Delwath: So you all get back 2d8 hit points-
c04667
DM: Um-
c04668
Unknown: ... to start
c04669
DM: ... well, okay, first question.
c04670
DM: What are you doing about the runic circle?
c04671
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c04672
Wellby: I am leaving that to Seeker, is what I'm doing.
c04673
DM: Okay, so you're not, you're avoiding it.
c04674
Unknown: Nobody's going inside.
c04675
DM: You're not crossing the r- okay.
c04676
Wellby: No.
c04677
DM: Um,
c04678
DM: you,
c04679
DM: uh, so you find, um,
c04680
DM: there's nothing in the room.
c04681
DM: However, in the desks
c04682
DM: you find several things.
c04683
DM: Um,
c04684
DM: in one of the two stone desks, you find there's a,
c04685
DM: there's a door, like a drawer that slides out.
c04686
DM: Um,
c04687
DM: and the, the bottom of the drawer as you pull it out look, looks like stone, but it's actually water.
c04688
DM: And you put your hand, you, like, search through it a little bit, and there's a key in the stone water.
c04689
Unknown: Awesome.
c04690
DM: Um, about that long, and, uh,
c04691
DM: made of a, a metal that looks like the same metal as the outside of the tower.
c04692
Unknown: Awesome.
c04693
DM: Hmm.
c04694
Kenzo: Wonder if we open that door again, it, it does something else.
c04695
Wellby: Is it, uh, is it magical?
c04696
Wellby: Someone can probably detect that.
c04697
DM: Y- yeah.
c04698
Unknown: Yeah, I can detect magic
c04699
DM: ... yeah.
c04700
DM: But you're in, Del was in the middle of casting a spell.
c04701
Unknown: Oh, yeah, sorry.
c04702
DM: So when the spell's over-
c04703
Unknown: I can't do it yet
c04704
DM: ... you can do that. Um, the,
c04705
DM: um, the other stone desk, um,
c04706
DM: has no drawers or anything, um, but as you're, as you're poking around, um,
c04707
DM: you
c04708
DM: see that, uh,
c04709
DM: so, like, the top layer is,
c04710
DM: again, is sort of illu- It's like you can feel through it, but it's...
c04711
DM: Wait, do you have true sight?
c04712
Wellby: Yeah.
c04713
DM: Okay. So you s- you can see through it, and there's, um, laid out on the top of the desk, um, a dozen, uh,
c04714
DM: like, circles about this big of different colored gemstones that each have, like, a rune carved in them.
c04715
Wellby: Huh, I'll pass those off to Seeker.
c04716
Unknown: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
c04717
Unknown: Figure it out.
c04718
DM: And in the wooden desk, you find three
c04719
DM: notebooks.
c04720
Wellby: I'll pass those off to Seeker.
c04721
DM: Okay.
c04722
Kenzo: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. I thought you said you opened up the desk drawer and there was a door inside.
c04723
Kenzo: I was like, "Whoa, that's cool," like you could, like, step into the drawer and it'd buy you someplace.
c04724
DM: But there was a key.
c04725
DM: Okay, so as the rest finishes,
c04726
DM: um-
c04727
Seeker: Um, so do I roll my own 2d8?
c04728
DM: 10.
c04729
Seeker: Oh, I get 10.
c04730
Unknown: Everybody gets 10. Everybody gets 10.
c04731
Seeker: Um, but I need to-
c04732
Delwath: You can also take hit dice if you want to get more than that.
c04733
Unknown: Yeah.
c04734
Delwath: But you get 10 plus your hit dice.
c04735
Seeker: Um, I'm gonna do I think all... I was trying to calculate it.
c04736
Seeker: I have 64 out of 174.
c04737
Seeker: Hit dice are-
c04738
Delwath: I mean, you can just roll-
c04739
Seeker: I don't know if it's 20 plus two
c04740
Delwath: ... you can roll, you don't have to, you can roll and then decide if you wanna keep going.
c04741
Delwath: You don't have to decide only one time.
c04742
Seeker: I, I'm gonna need almost all of them.
c04743
Delwath: But you should just roll a bunch of them.
c04744
Unknown: Okay.
c04745
Kenzo: All right, so there's... How many? For hit dice, is each one's, it's just each one's d8?
c04746
Delwath: Plus your con.
c04747
DM: Oh, and you also, but you also have-
c04748
Unknown: I know
c04749
DM: ... 10d10.
c04750
Kenzo: I know, I know. But I, I wanna use my hit dice first.
c04751
DM: Yeah.
c04752
Kenzo: 'Cause the, the hit dice I recover, right?
c04753
DM: Oh, after a long rest.
c04754
Unknown: Yeah.
c04755
Kenzo: Which I guess it doesn't really matter. I'll just, I'll just use hit dice for now.
c04756
Unknown: So I just roll...
c04757
Kenzo: What happens? Where's the eights?
c04758
Unknown: There.
c04759
Unknown: How...
c04760
Seeker: Do you know how I do the hit dice thing on D&D Beyond?
c04761
DM: Yes.
c04762
Unknown: How it works.
c04763
Delwath: Don't try and make it work. It never actually works.
c04764
DM: It never actually works in D&D Beyond.
c04765
Unknown: Just-
c04766
DM: Just roll
c04767
Delwath: ... just roll. Just click, uh-
c04768
Unknown: But I need to, like, roll 15d8
c04769
DM: ... click that.
c04770
Unknown: Oh. Oh.
c04771
DM: Click the number and hit roll hit dice, and then just add the amount.
c04772
Delwath: 76. Did it add 76? Oh, it did.
c04773
Unknown: It worked.
c04774
Seeker: So yeah, as you can see, I'll just use the rest of them.
c04775
Delwath: Oh, but it didn't take them away. Do you remember having to use?
c04776
Seeker: No, I just did the top row.
c04777
Unknown: Oh, great. So that's-
c04778
Kenzo: Dude, rolling with the computer is so much faster, guys
c04779
DM: We can roll with the computer. You roll your two hit, like-
c04780
Unknown: Oh. Huh?
c04781
DM: It's nicer to roll your two hit with the actual-
c04782
Unknown: All right. Three hit points
c04783
DM: ... 20.
c04784
Unknown: All right
c04785
Unknown: All right. All right, I'm gonna count-
c04786
DM: But yeah, it is faster
c04787
Seeker: ... Seeker's feeling a lot better.
c04788
Kenzo: I'm gonna count my key more closely this time too.
c04789
Kenzo: I'll let you know.
c04790
DM: Well, you get it all back, it's just shorter.
c04791
Kenzo: I know, that's why I said I'm gonna, I'm gonna count them.
c04792
DM: You have 19 total.
c04793
Unknown: Yeah, I know.
c04794
DM: Okay.
c04795
DM: Um,
c04796
DM: okay, so as you finish the rest, you hand off the key, the books, and the
c04797
DM: runic gemstones
c04798
DM: to Seeker.
c04799
Kenzo: We're not in combat anymore, so...
c04800
DM: Right. The,
c04801
DM: the, the books-
c04802
Unknown: [laughs]
c04803
Seeker: Tone it, tone it down. Tone it down
c04804
DM: ... so you have to hand them to Delwath to read them, 'cause they're written in Limbo language, which is random-
c04805
Unknown: Ah
c04806
DM: ... letters strung together.
c04807
Unknown: All right.
c04808
DM: They, they seem to be somebody, um, somebody's like
c04809
DM: research notes about, like, I don't know.
c04810
DM: You only spend a few minutes at this, I assume, 'cause I don't think you wanna spend hours.
c04811
Unknown: Yeah.
c04812
DM: Um-
c04813
Delwath: But he, they can do this while I'm casting the spell.
c04814
Wellby: But you have to translate it.
c04815
DM: You have to translate it.
c04816
Unknown: Yeah. I can read it too, right?
c04817
DM: You can only understand all languages.
c04818
Unknown: Oh.
c04819
DM: It's like you're attuned to the mi- the minds of everything that exists, so you can just-
c04820
Unknown: I can read it, but I'm stupid
c04821
DM: ... you can't read.
c04822
Unknown: Just for real.
c04823
Delwath: I mean, you're an elf, so...
c04824
Wellby: Hm? [laughs] Uh-huh, there it is.
c04825
DM: Although-
c04826
Delwath: This is easy, Kenzo, come on.
c04827
DM: No.
c04828
Unknown: Read. Look, look, Kenzo. Look, it's easy.
c04829
Unknown: Ah, fascist.
c04830
Unknown: Fascist. [laughs]
c04831
Unknown: Racist?
c04832
DM: Um, [coughs] so anyway, when the spell is o- so the-
c04833
Unknown: Oh
c04834
DM: ... the key obviously opens something, but what, you have no idea.
c04835
DM: I mean, there's the,
c04836
DM: there's the circle that you could investigate.
c04837
Unknown: Yeah.
c04838
Delwath: Seeker should be investigating the circle of runes while-
c04839
DM: Okay
c04840
Kenzo: ... the healing spell is being cast.
c04841
Seeker: I investigate the circle of runes.
c04842
Wellby: While the healing spell is being cast.
c04843
Seeker: While healing is being cast.
c04844
DM: Um,
c04845
DM: m- make a, go ahead and make an arcana check.
c04846
Unknown: 50.
c04847
Wellby: [laughs] 27.
c04848
Unknown: [laughs]
c04849
Unknown: Goddamnit, 27.
c04850
Unknown: [laughs]
c04851
Seeker: 993. Um-
c04852
DM: 40.
c04853
Unknown: No, I have glasses.
c04854
Unknown: That's, um, that's a 32.
c04855
DM: Don't you have advantage?
c04856
Unknown: Oh.
c04857
DM: Yeah, goggles.
c04858
Unknown: So it's 32.
c04859
DM: Um,
c04860
DM: y- y- you can't make out mu- I mean,
c04861
DM: honestly, the first thing that comes to mind is that you're studying these runes is it's, like,
c04862
DM: caution tape. Like, not in the, not in the there's danger on the other side, but in the, like,
c04863
DM: don't bonk your head.
c04864
DM: Like, the runes are like the little stickers people put in glass windows so that birds-
c04865
Unknown: Hm
c04866
DM: ... don't crash into buildings.
c04867
Unknown: Hm.
c04868
Wellby: Can I perceive anything about what's behind the runes?
c04869
DM: I mean, by eye, no.
c04870
Delwath: By true sight?
c04871
DM: No.
c04872
Seeker: So then in- inside the ring is just blank floor?
c04873
DM: S- apparently, but s- as far as I'm aware, nobody's stepped inside the ring.
c04874
Wellby: I'm gonna pull a bat out of my hat.
c04875
Unknown: I was gonna make an arcana die.
c04876
DM: Okay.
c04877
Seeker: I was gonna mage hand something in there.
c04878
DM: [laughs]
c04879
Unknown: [laughs]
c04880
Unknown: Well-
c04881
Unknown: All three of them
c04882
Unknown: ... well-
c04883
Unknown: Out of 17. [laughs]
c04884
Seeker: Let's, let's do Wellby first.
c04885
DM: The bat just crashes into a solid wall.
c04886
Seeker: What is it, floor, right?
c04887
DM: No, it's trying to fly past the r- runes-
c04888
Unknown: Oh
c04889
DM: ... and it just crashes into a solid wall.
c04890
Unknown: So there's-
c04891
Wellby: But lives?
c04892
DM: Yeah, like-
c04893
Wellby: This is without precedent. [laughs]
c04894
DM: Like boun- it's like, it's stunned.
c04895
DM: It does the little thing where it, like, lies on the ground and you, like, coast it back, and it, it looks at you, confused-
c04896
Unknown: Why's it alive?
c04897
DM: ... 'cause it expected to die.
c04898
DM: [laughs]
c04899
Seeker: So there's an invisible cylinder?
c04900
DM: Well, it's not invisible.
c04901
Delwath: If it was invisible, we could see it with true sight.
c04902
DM: If it was invisible, you could see with true sight.
c04903
DM: The air is just solid.
c04904
Unknown: Ah.
c04905
Delwath: So I'm gonna make an arcana inside it.
c04906
DM: It, it doesn't look any different from the inside.
c04907
Delwath: Right. It's literally just solid air.
c04908
Wellby: What if it isn't solid air?
c04909
Unknown: Meaning?
c04910
Wellby: What if we just think really hard that it's not solid air?
c04911
Unknown: Ah.
c04912
Unknown: What if it wasn't?
c04913
Delwath: Wait, what do the books say?
c04914
Delwath: Well, Seeker's off trying to convince the world to-
c04915
DM: The, the books... So in a few m- in the few minutes you have to glance at the books, um, each one seems to be as much as
c04916
DM: somebody could decipher about a bunch of
c04917
DM: y- you don't know what. It seems to be the deeds of warriors.
c04918
DM: You recognize a couple of the names from that.
c04919
DM: Like, there's a long section on, um, Pelosa the Chalk Storm,
c04920
DM: and it's talk-
c04921
Delwath: It seems like a war between Limbo and Mechanis or something like that
c04922
DM: ... it's talking about their, it, the way it's describing things, it seems to almost be describing something before
c04923
DM: time existed.
c04924
Wellby: Long before time had a name.
c04925
DM: Right? And it's like a ve- it's, and it's not, it's not describing Limbo.
c04926
DM: It's like trying to
c04927
DM: pull out memories of something that happened before Limbo was even created.
c04928
Delwath: I mean, let's keep these books.
c04929
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c04930
Delwath: We'll put them in, you know,
c04931
Unknown: our-
c04932
Seeker: So wait.
c04933
DM: Right.
c04934
Unknown: What, the war between Limbo and-
c04935
Unknown: Well, I should s-
c04936
Unknown: ... and what?
c04937
DM: The, the Plane of Order.
c04938
Unknown: Mechanis.
c04939
DM: Mechanis.
c04940
Seeker: Mechanis is the Plane of Order.
c04941
DM: Yeah.
c04942
Seeker: What's on Mechanis?
c04943
DM: As far as anybody knows, giant gears.
c04944
DM: Clockwork automaton.
c04945
Unknown: Clockwork centaurs?
c04946
DM: Well, these weren't clockwork, although actually in the mosaic there was-
c04947
Unknown: Yeah
c04948
DM: ... like, chaos elementals fighting clockwork creatures.
c04949
Seeker: Yeah, right.
c04950
Kenzo: Uh, the books will be good things we can trade for the Philosopher, the Philosopher's Guild.
c04951
Delwath: They're Seeker's entrance fee.
c04952
Kenzo: Yeah, to the Philosopher's Guild.
c04953
Unknown: Priceless.
c04954
Kenzo: Fucking books from Limbo?
c04955
Unknown: Hm.
c04956
Unknown: Man.
c04957
DM: But anyway, it seems to be describing-
c04958
Unknown: Before time
c04959
DM: ... some very, very ancient war between order and chaos,
c04960
DM: but the way it's talking about it, it's not like it's about Limbo.
c04961
DM: It's like a war for the primordial cosmos to determine whether order or chaos
c04962
DM: ruled.
c04963
Kenzo: We keep finding about wars that happened before the earlier wars.
c04964
Unknown: Like what's the war before this one?
c04965
DM: Well, this is before time so there is no before or after
c04966
Unknown: No before or after
c04967
DM: There's no linear order of events.
c04968
Kenzo: But this is before the time, then what's the thing before the thing before the time,
c04969
Unknown: Tristan?
c04970
Wellby: If we could turn back time to the good old days.
c04971
DM: Yeah. [laughs] When order and chaos-
c04972
Wellby: When order and chaos
c04973
DM: ... fought across the material plane for dominance.
c04974
Unknown: Mm.
c04975
Unknown: Uh,
c04976
Seeker: does anybody wanna like
c04977
Unknown: probe this-
c04978
Wellby: Take-
c04979
Unknown: ... solitaire?
c04980
Delwath: Take the key and turn it in the solitaire?
c04981
Wellby: Oh, it's a great idea.
c04982
Delwath: No, it's a terrible idea. [laughs]
c04983
Wellby: No, yeah, yeah, yeah.
c04984
Seeker: Okay, but the mage hand. Throw a sack of flour against it
c04985
Unknown: to see its shape.
c04986
Unknown: That's a good idea.
c04987
Wellby: Yeah.
c04988
Unknown: Pat, pat around it with the mage hand.
c04989
Unknown: I actually was gonna...
c04990
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Let's feel the hole.
c04991
Wellby: Let's find the keyhole in there. Where's the keyhole?
c04992
DM: The, there's a keyhole like right in the middle.
c04993
Wellby: Oh, there-
c04994
DM: Straight, as if like where you walk in straight across the room, when you walk from the purple glowing thing to this, there's a keyhole.
c04995
Unknown: Like, let's just do it.
c04996
Wellby: It's like an invisible keyhole in the invisible...
c04997
DM: Well, it's not invisible, the air is just solid.
c04998
Wellby: Yeah.
c04999
DM: But yeah, it's a keyhole in the solid air.
c05000
Unknown: Mage hand the key. Yeah.
c05001
Seeker: Over to the keyhole.
c05002
DM: Okay.
c05003
DM: The key turns and the key moves like this.
c05004
Wellby: Awesome.
c05005
Delwath: Wait, so let's walk in?
c05006
Wellby: No, I send the bat in.
c05007
Delwath: We got bat, time to die.
c05008
DM: [laughs] Uh, the bat vanishes.
c05009
DM: I assume you're l- you're looking through its eye.
c05010
DM: Yes. He's sense it.
c05011
DM: Um,
c05012
DM: the,
c05013
DM: uh, you emerg- the bat emerges into a room,
c05014
DM: um,
c05015
DM: that has another
c05016
DM: circle, like, uh...
c05017
DM: Let's see. Let's just say what's everything in the room.
c05018
DM: There's, um,
c05019
DM: there's another circle.
c05020
DM: Um,
c05021
DM: the,
c05022
DM: uh...
c05023
DM: At the far end across from where you appear,
c05024
DM: where the bat appears, um, there are two statues.
c05025
DM: Um, one
c05026
DM: a,
c05027
DM: uh...
c05028
DM: How to describe it? Um, a humanoid made of flames that seem to clump and blend together like mud, becoming darker as they become denser, so the interior of the statue
c05029
DM: is barely visible, but the outside is illuminated like in flames.
c05030
DM: And the other is a human or humanoid form of ash bound by a core of blazing ice wearing a crown.
c05031
DM: They clearly aren't l- designed to be displayed together.
c05032
DM: In fact, the
c05033
DM: s- the
c05034
DM: dark fire one looks like it belongs with the three big statues a couple floors down.
c05035
Wellby: Mm.
c05036
DM: Um, but they've been pushed close together so that they can, um,
c05037
DM: be next to each other. The dark fire statue carries a wide bladed scimitar, while the other statue is, wears like a simple crown of
c05038
DM: jaggedly shaped ash.
c05039
DM: Um,
c05040
DM: other than that, um, the bat sees a,
c05041
DM: uh...
c05042
DM: So the bat sees a door in the ceiling.
c05043
Wellby: And the circle that you described at the start is the circle that it's come out of.
c05044
DM: That it came out of. Yeah, yeah.
c05045
Unknown: Two statues, door on the ceiling.
c05046
DM: Yep.
c05047
Wellby: This is great, right?
c05048
Seeker: So we should just go through?
c05049
Seeker: Uh, the gemstone circle's on the desk.
c05050
DM: Um,
c05051
DM: uh, each...
c05052
DM: Your best guess is each one of these runes represents a name.
c05053
Wellby: Hmm. Controlling the statues?
c05054
DM: Possibly somehow involved with animating the statues, yes.
c05055
Delwath: Wait, the statues upstairs. Wait, the gemstone is on this floor.
c05056
Wellby: Do the number of gemstones correspond to the number of statues?
c05057
DM: Um,
c05058
DM: yes. The number of st- uh, minus, there is no gemstone that would corres- well, it's the number of statues, so the total number of statues you've seen, which is two in
c05059
DM: this floor-
c05060
Wellby: Mm
c05061
DM: ... then three big ones in the statue room with the, with the-
c05062
Unknown: Right.
c05063
Wellby: Yep
c05064
DM: ... and then there was eight smaller ones in that statue room.
c05065
DM: There's 11 total.
c05066
Wellby: Gems?
c05067
DM: Gems.
c05068
Wellby: All right. Do the two on this floor have their gems in them?
c05069
Wellby: Like have we seen any that have gems in them somehow?
c05070
DM: None that have gems in them, no.
c05071
Seeker: So I don't necessarily know how to correlate desk gems to statues.
c05072
Wellby: Wait, how many desk gems and how many statues altogether?
c05073
Unknown: 11.
c05074
DM: 11 desk gems, 13 statues, including the two upstairs.
c05075
Wellby: Oh.
c05076
DM: I mean, if you...
c05077
DM: I mean, how long do you wanna spend studying them?
c05078
Seeker: Well, not super long.
c05079
Unknown: Are these rocks?
c05080
Wellby: Door's open.
c05081
Seeker: But it looks like they somehow, they might like awaken the statue.
c05082
DM: Possibly.
c05083
Seeker: Don't think we wanna do that.
c05084
Unknown: Wow.
c05085
DM: That seems like it could be a bad idea.
c05086
Delwath: Yeah, unless they also have some control of the statue.
c05087
Wellby: Let's, let's see if we can just speed run this next room and go through the door on the ceiling.
c05088
Wellby: Right?
c05089
Unknown: Yep.
c05090
DM: Uh,
c05091
DM: okay.
c05092
Seeker: So we go through the circle of runes.
c05093
DM: You step through the circle of runes, and you
c05094
DM: teleport to the circle on the up, other floor.
c05095
DM: You step through. The ceiling is about 20 feet up.
c05096
DM: There's a round door in the ceiling.
c05097
Seeker: Well, we happen to have a friend here named Ladder
c05098
Kenzo: Well, we can also just fly because Limbo.
c05099
Unknown: Yeah.
c05100
Wellby: Yeah.
c05101
Unknown: We just run upwards.
c05102
Wellby: We walk over to the door and open it.
c05103
DM: Uh, so you're just-
c05104
Unknown: Check, check, check
c05105
DM: ... you just start drifting up?
c05106
Unknown: Check for traps.
c05107
Wellby: Yeah, check for traps.
c05108
DM: Um.
c05109
Wellby: Also check for statues coming to wake to kill us.
c05110
DM: Wait, wait, no, no, no. Just tell me what y- so you're...
c05111
DM: You can't do all these things at once.
c05112
Wellby: I think as soon as Wellby steps through, it's like check for traps, situational awareness.
c05113
DM: Okay.
c05114
Wellby: Are the statues on the move?
c05115
DM: The statues are not moving.
c05116
DM: Go ahead and make investigation.
c05117
Wellby: Uh,
c05118
Wellby: something. I think a 23.
c05119
Wellby: No, no, no, uh, that would be 22.
c05120
DM: Um, nothing,
c05121
DM: nothing trap-like that you notice.
c05122
Unknown: I,
c05123
Delwath: I think the Limbo, um...
c05124
Delwath: Hey, does my, my sword glows if anybody, if any native of Limbo is within 120 feet.
c05125
Unknown: Ooh.
c05126
DM: Um,
c05127
DM: it's, it's not glowing right now, but from your experience of the outside of the tower, the distance between floors in this tower is-
c05128
Unknown: Ca- quite weird
c05129
DM: ... quite weird.
c05130
Unknown: Okay, yeah.
c05131
DM: So it doesn't mean there's nothing on the other side of the door, there's just nothing in this room.
c05132
Unknown: Sure, yeah, yeah.
c05133
Wellby: What, what if we do take the ladder and we don't think our way through this room at all?
c05134
Seeker: Yeah, let's do it.
c05135
Wellby: What if there's like a, a thinking in Limbo trap here?
c05136
Delwath: Let's just climb... Yeah, let's climb the ladder.
c05137
DM: Um, who's going first?
c05138
Unknown: Kenzo.
c05139
Wellby: Yeah. [laughs]
c05140
Seeker: We just volunteered you.
c05141
Unknown: [laughs] You're going.
c05142
DM: Kong.
c05143
Unknown: Yo.
c05144
DM: Kenzo is climbing the ladder first.
c05145
Kenzo: All right. Where are we climbing to?
c05146
DM: To the v-
c05147
Delwath: Your death
c05148
DM: ... to the-
c05149
Unknown: The ladder
c05150
DM: ... to the door in the ceiling
c05151
Kenzo: Uh, first thing, any, uh, consciousness or beings around?
c05152
DM: Not in this room.
c05153
Kenzo: Okay. Climbing.
c05154
DM: Make a strength saving throw.
c05155
Kenzo: Why? [laughs]
c05156
Wellby: [laughs] We, we don't respond as often that way as we should.
c05157
Unknown: [laughs]
c05158
DM: [laughs]
c05159
Delwath: Wait, I, I reject your strength saving throw.
c05160
Delwath: I'll offer you a, a dexterity saving throw instead.
c05161
DM: Halfway up to the ceiling, the gravity reverses and becomes extremely strong, pulling you down towards the door.
c05162
Kenzo: D'oh. Seven, but I'm gonna spend a ki and roll that.
c05163
Unknown: Oh, wait, wait, wait, hold on, hold on.
c05164
Unknown: What?
c05165
Unknown: Wait, do you care?
c05166
DM: Why would you care? You can't take falling damage.
c05167
Kenzo: Oh, okay. Okay.
c05168
DM: So Kenzo gracefully slams into the ceiling-
c05169
Unknown: Okay
c05170
DM: ... taking zero damage.
c05171
Unknown: Cool.
c05172
Wellby: It's a good thing we sent Kenzo first.
c05173
Unknown: Smart.
c05174
Delwath: Wait, it-
c05175
DM: The ceiling is, is like 30 feet high.
c05176
DM: When you get up about 10 feet, gravity inverts-
c05177
Unknown: Right
c05178
DM: ... and pulls you slam, pulls you up to the ceiling very strongly.
c05179
Unknown: Right.
c05180
DM: So unless you are strong enough to hold onto the ladder, you get, it gets yanked out of your grip.
c05181
Kenzo: Can I now try climbing up this way?
c05182
DM: Um, it's really hard.
c05183
DM: It's like at least two or three times normal gravity.
c05184
Wellby: Give me like a Caroline re- I'm gonna rig a rope to the ladder
c05185
Wellby: so that I can only fall five feet.
c05186
DM: Okay.
c05187
Wellby: Uh-
c05188
Unknown: Yeah
c05189
Wellby: ... and then-
c05190
Unknown: That
c05191
Unknown: sounds good
c05192
Wellby: ... do that.
c05193
DM: Okay.
c05194
Wellby: Yeah.
c05195
DM: So yeah, that works.
c05196
Delwath: Can we all do that?
c05197
DM: Yeah.
c05198
Kenzo: Can somebody send me down a rope or something so I can-
c05199
Unknown: No, you're at the ceiling.
c05200
DM: You're at the ceiling.
c05201
Delwath: You fell to the ceiling.
c05202
DM: You fell.
c05203
Unknown: Oh. I thought there was a door.
c05204
DM: There is a door in the ceiling.
c05205
Unknown: It's in the ceiling.
c05206
Unknown: Oh.
c05207
Wellby: No, it's in the floor.
c05208
Unknown: But now it's on my floor.
c05209
DM: Now it's on your floor, yes.
c05210
Kenzo: Oh, got it. Okay, great.
c05211
Wellby: Uh, traps on the door?
c05212
Seeker: And the ladder is delighted to serve in its...
c05213
DM: [laughs]
c05214
Wellby: Yeah, I think all things-
c05215
DM: No
c05216
Wellby: ... that have ever served
c05217
DM: I know, right?
c05218
Wellby: [laughs]
c05219
DM: No, no, no, that's not true.
c05220
Wellby: Hm?
c05221
DM: Um-
c05222
Unknown: Was there another one?
c05223
DM: Wasn't the first time you, part of the reason you animated it the very first time-
c05224
Unknown: Was to use it as a ladder
c05225
DM: ... was to use it as a ladder.
c05226
Unknown: I, I think that-
c05227
DM: And then it got in combat and you were like, "Wow, this is actually really useful."
c05228
DM: [laughs]
c05229
Unknown: Yeah, it's familiar.
c05230
Wellby: Like this is a complete character arc for the ladder.
c05231
Unknown: Amazing.
c05232
Unknown: Wow.
c05233
Kenzo: Has this cam- campaign about us or Apollyon or any of these things?
c05234
Kenzo: I feel like this is the ladder's story.
c05235
Delwath: That's what we could do, ask ChatGPT to rewrite the session notes from the perspective of the ladder.
c05236
Seeker: I was just walking by my computer to do that specific thing.
c05237
Wellby: [laughs]
c05238
DM: [laughs]
c05239
Unknown: [laughs]
c05240
Wellby: Uh, traps on the door?
c05241
Wellby: Locked door?
c05242
DM: Um,
c05243
DM: the door is locked.
c05244
Wellby: I will un-
c05245
DM: Make an investigation check.
c05246
Wellby: I will investigate.
c05247
Delwath: Um, I'm gonna make an arcane eye appear on the other side of the door.
c05248
DM: Um, arcane eyes cannot go through the walls or floors of the tower.
c05249
Wellby: 26.
c05250
Delwath: Yeah, right, because of divination antis.
c05251
DM: Yep.
c05252
DM: Uh, 26? Um, the,
c05253
DM: uh, you notice a, um,
c05254
DM: sort of etched into the side of the, of the,
c05255
DM: where the lock mechanism is, there's a small rune.
c05256
Wellby: I will point this out to our local rune expert.
c05257
Seeker: I read the rune.
c05258
Delwath: No, no, no. You have to investigate the rune without reading it.
c05259
Unknown: Oh.
c05260
Delwath: It probably explodes when you read it.
c05261
Kenzo: I, I knew that.
c05262
Wellby: Oh, this is cool.
c05263
DM: I mean, you could just cast Dispel Magic.
c05264
Kenzo: You just rotate the head and it gives a different...
c05265
Unknown: Is that what I should do?
c05266
Wellby: Yes.
c05267
Kenzo: So I was totally awake, but, um, what happened with the other runes that were in the other room?
c05268
Unknown: Did we get any treasure?
c05269
DM: Uh, the air was...
c05270
DM: The, the runes were a war- were like a warning sticker, so you-
c05271
Kenzo: Yeah, so, um, we set the key in and then, and then we jo- we walked in, and then what happened?
c05272
DM: It just teleported you to this room.
c05273
Unknown: Oh. Oh.
c05274
Kenzo: So I didn't miss anything.
c05275
DM: No.
c05276
Unknown: You didn't miss anything.
c05277
Wellby: No.
c05278
Delwath: Except us te- sending Kenzo first.
c05279
Unknown: Did I fall to my death?
c05280
Unknown: But that was a good, that was a good move.
c05281
DM: It's fine. You can't take fall damage.
c05282
Unknown: I always live for everything.
c05283
Unknown: Yeah.
c05284
Delwath: I, I would suggest you cast Dispel Magic.
c05285
Seeker: I cast Dispel Magic.
c05286
DM: Okay.
c05287
Unknown: Um.
c05288
DM: The rune vanishes.
c05289
Unknown: Okay.
c05290
Wellby: Is it still locked?
c05291
DM: Yeah, it's still locked
c05292
Delwath: Can you pick a lock? Have you ever picked a lock in this game?
c05293
Wellby: I have. I also do have a Charm of Opening in case it goes poorly.
c05294
Wellby: But, um,
c05295
Wellby: what is this, sleight of hand? No.
c05296
Wellby: Thieves' tools proficiency?
c05297
DM: S- sleight of hand th- th- thieves', thieves', uh,
c05298
DM: sleight of hand, but if you have thieves' tools proficiency you have advantage.
c05299
Unknown: Ooh, awesome.
c05300
Wellby: Uh, 26.
c05301
DM: Yeah. You manage to
c05302
DM: get the lock so that it is ready to open when you want to lift up the door.
c05303
Wellby: See, I'm a legit rogue.
c05304
Delwath: Yeah, good job.
c05305
DM: Mm.
c05306
Delwath: We're using a ladder to climb.
c05307
Delwath: We're using a rogue to open a lock.
c05308
DM: [laughs] I know, right?
c05309
Unknown: Like, what's happening here?
c05310
Unknown: We're using a rogue to open a lock.
c05311
DM: [laughs]
c05312
Unknown: [coughs]
c05313
Wellby: Uh, um, so Kenzo opens the door?
c05314
Delwath: I mean, sure.
c05315
Unknown: Sure.
c05316
DM: Uh, okay.
c05317
DM: So as you,
c05318
DM: as you open the door you are looking, um, from the ceiling down to
c05319
DM: a floor.
c05320
DM: You do- It at least...
c05321
DM: Well,
c05322
DM: those of you with Truesight, so Kenzo you see there's, there's no walls.
c05323
DM: This is just a vast vis- a floating platform with a vast vista expanse, a panoramic view showing an endless, um,
c05324
DM: expanse of shifting land more solid than the formless void of Limbo, but unfixed, shifting at a whim, just kind of,
c05325
DM: um, every moment. Like, it's, it looks like a, it looks like the Earth, right?
c05326
DM: It looks like, you know, a landscape of,
c05327
DM: you know,
c05328
DM: a, a, you know, a river valley or something, but it's, everything is just constantly changing.
c05329
DM: Like,
c05330
DM: trees will grow and then blossom and then split and turn into legs, and begin walking across the landscape.
c05331
DM: Um, and striding through this you can see, um, several
c05332
DM: of these
c05333
DM: kinda like the ash statue you saw before.
c05334
DM: Um, one of which is walking through holding hands with a
c05335
DM: dark fire creature.
c05336
Kenzo: Limbo is psychedelic as fuck.
c05337
Kenzo: Like, everything you're describing is, like, I can't even...
c05338
Kenzo: It's hard for me to, like, even, like, picture it all.
c05339
Unknown: Yeah.
c05340
Kenzo: It sounds so crazy.
c05341
DM: Uh,
c05342
DM: also,
c05343
DM: um,
c05344
DM: standing
c05345
DM: on the,
c05346
DM: on the ground,
c05347
DM: um, [coughs] you see
c05348
DM: the person depicted by the statue, the Queen of Ash,
c05349
DM: the, the creature that was shown in the statue in the floor below,
c05350
DM: standing in what looks like prayer or a vigil of some kind.
c05351
DM: Um,
c05352
DM: next to her is another one of those,
c05353
DM: uh, metallic blood things you just fought.
c05354
DM: Um, another one of the-
c05355
Unknown: Fuck, man
c05356
DM: ... centaur creatures.
c05357
Unknown: Fuck.
c05358
Unknown: Jesus, like two creatures.
c05359
DM: And,
c05360
DM: uh,
c05361
DM: about almost two dozen, um-
c05362
Unknown: Fuck
c05363
DM: ... uh, small little puffs-
c05364
Unknown: I'm not fighting two creatures
c05365
DM: ... of cloud.
c05366
DM: These are minions.
c05367
Delwath: Wait, and there's this queen creature?
c05368
DM: And the queen creature, yes.
c05369
Delwath: Is the queen creature, like, the entity here or something else?
c05370
DM: The-
c05371
Delwath: What, what do we know about this queen creature?
c05372
Unknown: What does she look like?
c05373
Seeker: We're just trying to get the relic.
c05374
Wellby: Do you see the relic?
c05375
DM: You don't see the relic.
c05376
Seeker: No cheating.
c05377
DM: Mm.
c05378
Delwath: Can we, like, close the door and just quietly retreat?
c05379
Unknown: [laughs]
c05380
Wellby: [laughs] Back out of this dimension.
c05381
Seeker: So wait, sorry. I mean-
c05382
Delwath: Is it really worth fixing this?
c05383
Seeker: ... just a vast open space?
c05384
DM: Uh, except that those of you with Truesight can see that the walls are illusionary and it's actually about a 40-foot diameter room.
c05385
Kenzo: [laughs] Feels like a lot of work, guys.
c05386
Unknown: Kinda does. Like-
c05387
Unknown: Oh, it is work
c05388
Unknown: ... is it really worth closing the...
c05389
Unknown: Like, why are we doing this again exactly?
c05390
Seeker: Like, we're not gonna clean this room out easily.
c05391
Kenzo: Yeah, that's gonna take forever.
c05392
Wellby: Those of us with Truesight don't see this thing that we're supposed to steal hanging around in here?
c05393
DM: No. Oh, and actually, those of you with Truesight also see a,
c05394
DM: a sort of
c05395
DM: dusty silhouette of a human
c05396
DM: Noid-ish kind of creature lurking, um,
c05397
DM: u- un- just direct- right underneath, like right at the bottom of the floor, invisible.
c05398
DM: But with Truesight you can see it.
c05399
Wellby: Is it- Like the thing that was out front?
c05400
DM: K- kinda like the...
c05401
DM: Possibly, yes, similar to the thing that was out front.
c05402
Kenzo: So wait, which we never saw.
c05403
Delwath: What is the... Wait, what, so there's this queen creature.
c05404
DM: The queen. There's another one of the metallic blood things.
c05405
DM: Another one of the centaur, iron centaur things.
c05406
DM: About two dozen cloudy minions that seem to be made of clouds of dust.
c05407
DM: And then, uh,
c05408
DM: a sort of invisible, like, hunched, not underneath the floor, but like-
c05409
Unknown: Okay
c05410
DM: ... crouched down sort of actually keeping watch on the door, looking actually straight up at you as the door opens.
c05411
Unknown: Fuck.
c05412
DM: Um-
c05413
Wellby: Uh, Kenzo.
c05414
DM: Straight up at Kenzo as the door opens.
c05415
Kenzo: But Kenzo's an astral shadow.
c05416
Kenzo: Like, nobody sees me. [laughs]
c05417
Unknown: Kenzo just quietly closes the door
c05418
Unknown: Put on your most door-like expression
c05419
Unknown: ... waves goodbye. [laughs]
c05420
Unknown: [laughs]
c05421
Unknown: This, this never happens.
c05422
DM: Kenzo can't see this because it's a, this creature, 'cause it's invisible.
c05423
Unknown: Nice. And...
c05424
Kenzo: You can sit... You can move the computer.
c05425
Delwath: Are we, like, fighting or talking?
c05426
Delwath: I mean, talking might not be a choice, but this seems like a lot of things to fight.
c05427
Kenzo: Yeah, that's what I'm saying. Yeah.
c05428
Kenzo: Is there another option? You can move your computer, Eric, over there.
c05429
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. I'll, I'll move-
c05430
Wellby: Has talking ever not led to fighting?
c05431
Unknown: Yeah. Remember one time we talked the bandits into joining us, and then they all got killed by, uh-
c05432
Wellby: I do remember that
c05433
Unknown: ... by what's his name?
c05434
Wellby: Yeah.
c05435
Unknown: Apollyon?
c05436
Wellby: Yeah.
c05437
DM: No, you, like-
c05438
Wellby: It was Wizard too, right?
c05439
DM: You, you managed to make your way almost through the entire giant,
c05440
DM: stone giant
c05441
DM: ch- chaelight lair without fighting much.
c05442
Wellby: Oh, that's true.
c05443
Wellby: That's working better for us.
c05444
DM: I don't know if you can talk your way out of this one.
c05445
DM: You can always try.
c05446
Unknown: All right. Strategy, strategy huddle?
c05447
Kenzo: Do we not see the... We don't see the entity.
c05448
Kenzo: This is not the entity.
c05449
DM: Oh, no. This is... The queen is the entity.
c05450
Unknown: Oh. Oh, good. Oh, great.
c05451
Kenzo: Okay. All right. All right, so we're here.
c05452
Unknown: We're here.
c05453
Unknown: I can get buffed enough for this.
c05454
Kenzo: All right. Now we... Now, now we do all the things.
c05455
Wellby: What are we?
c05456
Unknown: Um...
c05457
Seeker: We need a minute here 'cause I've already depleted...
c05458
Seeker: The ladder's almost dead.
c05459
Wellby: Can the ladder be healed?
c05460
Unknown: No.
c05461
Delwath: What slots do you have left, Seeker?
c05462
Seeker: Oh, the ladder can't be healed.
c05463
Unknown: It can be healed or can't?
c05464
Unknown: I don't know.
c05465
DM: Uh...
c05466
Unknown: Good question.
c05467
Delwath: Do you have... You have an eighth and a ninth?
c05468
Seeker: I do. I have one six, one seven, one eight, one nine.
c05469
Unknown: Yeah, that's not so bad.
c05470
Unknown: So you're barely depleted at all.
c05471
Seeker: Yeah, that's true, and I can gold dragon it with Wish.
c05472
DM: No, that's a shape change.
c05473
Seeker: That's a Chupatmorph. Oh.
c05474
DM: Shape change.
c05475
Seeker: Shape change, but that's also ninth.
c05476
DM: It's your ninth out of slot, but um, I don't see any reason why the
c05477
DM: ladder can't be healed.
c05478
DM: It just can't drink potions, so you'd only have to heal it with a spell.
c05479
Wellby: I'm doing my poor potion over the-
c05480
Delwath: Well, can it, can it at least get-
c05481
Unknown: [laughs]
c05482
Wellby: I'm working into the-
c05483
Unknown: Can it, like, at least-
c05484
Delwath: Can it get hit points from Prayer of Healing, then?
c05485
DM: Yeah. But also it's only costs you a third level spell to reanimate it at full health.
c05486
Kenzo: I like this pour a potion over the ladder thing.
c05487
Seeker: Um, I've burned all my thirds, but I could use a fourth.
c05488
Unknown: And w-
c05489
Wellby: So we could have a ladder, a dragon, a triceratops
c05490
Unknown: If we're gonna, like, go in here, I'm gonna drink my potion of invulnerability.
c05491
Unknown: Yeah. They're both the same.
c05492
Wellby: Are we just... Are we just gonna run in and start-
c05493
Unknown: Yeah, I-
c05494
Wellby: ... swinging into places?
c05495
Unknown: Yeah. This is the, this is the...
c05496
DM: I mean, you have, like, a second.
c05497
DM: It's... This invisible thing is staring right at you as you open the door.
c05498
Delwath: You don't have, like, time to prepare.
c05499
DM: I'm just giving you a minute in case you decide you wanna run.
c05500
DM: You can't, like, all drink potions and summon things and do stuff.
c05501
Seeker: If we run away, was there something that we noticed before that was a different avenue to explore that might be a better way to find the relic thing?
c05502
Unknown: 'Cause...
c05503
Wellby: I think this felt very linear for as non-linear as it was to get here.
c05504
Seeker: It's, it's an interesting-
c05505
Wellby: Like, it's, uh-
c05506
Unknown: ... kind of,
c05507
Unknown: you know,
c05508
Unknown: paradoxically
c05509
Seeker: very twisted s- non-Euclidean space, but a very linear path through it.
c05510
Kenzo: No, but we're inside the stable realm.
c05511
Unknown: This is all...
c05512
DM: Right.
c05513
Wellby: Are there any exits from this room?
c05514
DM: Uh, just the door that you're standing on.
c05515
Delwath: But the exits have also been, in general,
c05516
Delwath: not too obvious.
c05517
Unknown: What's the queen look like?
c05518
DM: Um,
c05519
DM: like a,
c05520
DM: a sort of swirling ash held together by, um, a core of blazing ice.
c05521
Wellby: W- what if the queen doesn't have a vested interest in Limbo having a vortex that draws it to the material plane?
c05522
Wellby: Do we know that she cares one way or the other?
c05523
DM: I mean, according to Rai, she is actively trying to use the vortex to crash Limbo further into the material plane.
c05524
Delwath: She does like the fact that she lost the war against Order and Before Time and wants to undo her loss.
c05525
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah.
c05526
Kenzo: I, I don't think there's a way we talk ourselves out of this equation.
c05527
Unknown: Yeah.
c05528
DM: No. Attack.
c05529
Wellby: Let's do it.
c05530
DM: Okay.
c05531
DM: So...
c05532
Delwath: Wait, what's the deal? Uh, potion's a bonus action?
c05533
DM: Potion's a bonus action.
c05534
Unknown: Are these glasses, uh, time piece?
c05535
Kenzo: Potions a bonus... Yeah.
c05536
Unknown: All right.
c05537
Delwath: Like, do we have a chance to, like, drink one potion before we get into...
c05538
DM: Uh, on your first turn in combat, yeah.
c05539
Unknown: Awesome.
c05540
Delwath: Right. But it's actually not...
c05541
Delwath: Well, resistance to all damage is kind of worth...
c05542
DM: Okay. So the room itself is 40 feet across.
c05543
Unknown: Uh, actually-
c05544
Unknown: So it's on now
c05545
Unknown: ... 20.
c05546
Unknown: Tim,
c05547
Delwath: after a short rest... Sorry.
c05548
Delwath: I, I took a potion of heroism which lasts for an hour.
c05549
DM: Okay.
c05550
Delwath: I meant to, to use that when we got into...
c05551
Delwath: Can I have drunk that after a short rest?
c05552
DM: Yeah, that's fine.
c05553
DM: Why can't I do math?
c05554
DM: 20 feet is five squares, right?
c05555
Wellby: Four squares.
c05556
Wellby: Four.
c05557
DM: Four squares.
c05558
DM: Yeah.
c05559
Unknown: One, two.
c05560
Kenzo: I really like how when you rotate the heads they have different expressions.
c05561
DM: Yeah. [laughs]
c05562
Unknown: That's pretty awesome.
c05563
Kenzo: Angry Kenzo. [laughs] All right, I'm happy with this Kenzo now.
c05564
Wellby: This is a big room.
c05565
Seeker: Yeah, this is gonna be... This, this is real tight quarter stuff we're doing.
c05566
DM: So-
c05567
Kenzo: I feel like this is gonna be-
c05568
DM: Um,
c05569
DM: yes, this is fairly tight quarters.
c05570
DM: Uh, the, the door is at the top here, and it's a 20-foot drop down.
c05571
Wellby: That's real tight
c05572
DM: And standing in here,
c05573
DM: um...
c05574
DM: So it's gonna be actually, it's rather...
c05575
DM: The map is gonna be pretty tricky, 'cause the clouds are, the cloud minions are all just flying around.
c05576
Delwath: Ah. You said there's 20 of them?
c05577
Seeker: Do you wanna make a second-
c05578
DM: Yeah
c05579
Seeker: ... entire circle? No, that would be confusing
c05580
Kenzo: for, like, the upper level.
c05581
DM: Yeah, no.
c05582
Unknown: [laughs]
c05583
DM: Let's, let's make an upper...
c05584
Unknown: Yeah.
c05585
DM: No, that's gonna be confusing.
c05586
Seeker: Yeah, 'cause you have to tell what's above what
c05587
Seeker: without them being actually on top of each other.
c05588
DM: I'll just-
c05589
Unknown: No, no. Don't, don't, uh...
c05590
Wellby: That's okay. That... It'll...
c05591
Wellby: This looks pretty good.
c05592
DM: Okay. Let's make a second circle.
c05593
Unknown: Yeah. Here.
c05594
DM: Here.
c05595
Wellby: Uh, let me make it over...
c05596
DM: Yeah.
c05597
Wellby: Make it at an angle.
c05598
Wellby: Uh, so if we, uh,
c05599
Wellby: move this forward.
c05600
Kenzo: Oh, is there a second layer?
c05601
Unknown: Yeah.
c05602
Wellby: Four.
c05603
DM: Oh.
c05604
Seeker: Just line them up so that you can say, like-
c05605
Wellby: Four. Yeah
c05606
Wellby: ... the minions and the-
c05607
Wellby: And then we can just dot 'em. Yep.
c05608
Unknown: Oh, yeah
c05609
Wellby: To show the perspective, like the-
c05610
DM: So this is... So most of the, the minions are actually in the upper circle.
c05611
DM: They're flying around.
c05612
Unknown: There you go.
c05613
Unknown: Nice.
c05614
Seeker: They're also just everywhere, so [laughs] it wouldn't matter that much.
c05615
Wellby: Hang on. Let me, let me add some more dots.
c05616
DM: Okay.
c05617
DM: It'll be a little easier that way.
c05618
DM: Uh, then we have,
c05619
DM: uh, this thing in the lower.
c05620
DM: Uh, we have
c05621
DM: one of the...
c05622
DM: I'll use... What happened to Goldie?
c05623
Delwath: Now's the time to
c05624
Unknown: use your Wingus claw.
c05625
Kenzo: Yeah. I'm gonna use it... Or I'm gonna use one of them.
c05626
DM: Um,
c05627
DM: okay. This, this is the, like, invisible
c05628
DM: mist thing.
c05629
Wellby: Oh, that's gonna be hard.
c05630
DM: Um...
c05631
DM: Uh, what happened to, um...
c05632
DM: Oh, here they are.
c05633
DM: Here's, here's Goldie, the weird center.
c05634
DM: And then,
c05635
DM: um...
c05636
DM: Where is my...
c05637
DM: Okay.
c05638
DM: Uh, then this is the...
c05639
DM: So the Queen of, the Queen of Ash and the Metallic Blood are, um,
c05640
DM: are, are looking out at the vista.
c05641
DM: This thing is watching,
c05642
Delwath: which that's the Queen of Ash.
c05643
Unknown: Queen of Ash?
c05644
DM: That's the Queen of Ash. That's the Metallic Blood.
c05645
Wellby: Metallic Blood again.
c05646
DM: Again. This is the Goldie center.
c05647
Wellby: Center again.
c05648
Unknown: That's the mist thing that's invisible.
c05649
DM: And then the,
c05650
DM: these things-
c05651
Wellby: Yeah
c05652
DM: ... are all just around in the second layer,
c05653
DM: so they're in between you and the ground.
c05654
DM: Um,
c05655
DM: and you are all...
c05656
DM: So I will,
c05657
DM: um, the only one...
c05658
DM: If you're just leaping to attack, the only one that's seen you is, is that.
c05659
DM: So everybody else will have disadvantage on initiative.
c05660
Unknown: What?
c05661
DM: No, no.
c05662
Delwath: Oh, we, them. Bad guys.
c05663
DM: Not you.
c05664
Unknown: Good.
c05665
DM: So let me just get all their stat blocks.
c05666
Seeker: That's funny. [laughs] If I gold dragon up,
c05667
Seeker: I will fill a quarter of the entire grid.
c05668
Wellby: You should definitely do that.
c05669
Unknown: I... Yeah. Gold drag- okay.
c05670
Delwath: Gold dragon-ing up is probably the best
c05671
Unknown: move here.
c05672
Delwath: You won't... Wait. You have an eighth level, but animal shapes won't do us that much good.
c05673
DM: The eighth level would just be if you wanna, if you wanna summon another construct.
c05674
DM: Eighth level construct is pretty good.
c05675
Seeker: Right. And it's like ideally I would do that first, but it's not clear.
c05676
Seeker: Oh, I could do that while I'm after I dragon.
c05677
Unknown: No, 'cause you can't cast.
c05678
DM: Yeah, no. Shape change lets you keep your spell casting.
c05679
Delwath: Yeah, you keep your spell casting.
c05680
Delwath: You don't get their spell casting.
c05681
DM: You keep your spell casting.
c05682
DM: Okay. So,
c05683
DM: so-
c05684
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Go ahead.
c05685
DM: Yeah, yeah. Go ahead. I'm just rolling initiative.
c05686
DM: So I'm gonna
c05687
DM: make
c05688
DM: three groups of minions.
c05689
Wellby: Do you want to do a cluster this time?
c05690
DM: No, I'll just, I'll just pick ones that...
c05691
DM: Actually, we have...
c05692
Unknown: Oh, shit.
c05693
DM: You okay?
c05694
Wellby: Yeah.
c05695
DM: So I'm gonna actually do green,
c05696
DM: green, red, and, like, blue-ish purple.
c05697
DM: Perfect.
c05698
Unknown: Is this the epithet thing?
c05699
DM: No. Which one?
c05700
Unknown: The ginger?
c05701
DM: No.
c05702
DM: So that's
c05703
DM: nine-
c05704
Unknown: More hot water
c05705
DM: ...
c05706
DM: seven
c05707
DM: and 15.
c05708
Unknown: Hey, do you have more hot water?
c05709
DM: What?
c05710
Unknown: Do you want any more hot water?
c05711
DM: Yes. I'll have more tea, actually.
c05712
Unknown: Okay. I'll make you some.
c05713
Unknown: Do you want... What kind of tea you want?
c05714
DM: M- the ginger is good.
c05715
Unknown: Okay.
c05716
DM: Um,
c05717
DM: okay. Then oof
c05718
Unknown: [dramatic music] So that's a...
c05719
Unknown: [dice clattering]
c05720
DM: Oh, and then straight roll for the
c05721
DM: Essence of Mist.
c05722
Delwath: So the 30-foot radius do fill the, fill the whole room?
c05723
DM: Yeah.
c05724
DM: Uh, plus 5, so 10.
c05725
DM: [dramatic music] Okay.
c05726
DM: I'm also gonna go pee and then you guys can all roll initiative.
c05727
DM: Well, you guys can all roll initiative now.
c05728
Delwath: [grunts] [dice clattering] Tch, that one's going last.
c05729
Seeker: Too bad I'm not already a dragon-
c05730
Unknown: But actually-
c05731
Seeker: ... which has, like, a plus 14 to initiative
c05732
Delwath: ... yeah, it might be worth swapping.
c05733
Unknown: Okay.
c05734
Kenzo: Ooh, there's, like, a little bug in here.
c05735
Unknown: [dice clattering] 27.
c05736
Delwath: Um, we might want...
c05737
Delwath: I'm... So I'm thinking of casting Second Radiance.
c05738
Delwath: It'll fill the entire room.
c05739
Unknown: [die rolling]
c05740
Unknown: So we just stay out?
c05741
Delwath: We, we'll be immune to it.
c05742
Kenzo: Oh, cool. Oh, you should definitely do that.
c05743
Delwath: But can we swap? 'Cause I rolled a two for initiative.
c05744
DM: Yeah, sure.
c05745
Delwath: Which it's gonna be better if they all get it on their-
c05746
DM: Yeah.
c05747
Delwath: Plus it'll make... If this guy fails his save, he becomes un-invisible.
c05748
Unknown: Totally.
c05749
Seeker: So wait, what are the things again?
c05750
Delwath: Queen of a- a queen of a...
c05751
Unknown: No.
c05752
DM: I actually think even though the adding things up is slower, like just not having to click, like, six different buttons everywhere-
c05753
Unknown: I know
c05754
DM: ... actually speeds up combat-
c05755
Unknown: Which one's the Queen of Mist?
c05756
DM: This is the Queen of Mist
c05757
Unknown: ... a lot compared to playing online.
c05758
Unknown: Really?
c05759
DM: Yeah. That one's the Queen of Mist. I, I expected this to be,
c05760
DM: I expected it to be, like, 11:30 when we started this combat.
c05761
Delwath: Yeah.
c05762
Delwath: I think it does-
c05763
DM: Oh, well you also managed to sneak through the statue room without anything triggering, so that was useful.
c05764
Delwath: I also do think combat runs a little bit more smoothly not on Zoom, 'cause people are more engaged with themselves.
c05765
DM: Yeah.
c05766
Delwath: And so you're, like, planning ahead a little bit more.
c05767
DM: Right.
c05768
Delwath: You're, like, rolling dice a little bit more.
c05769
Unknown: Yeah. It's, it's-
c05770
Delwath: I mean, I f- 'cause I run my game in person, I feel like combat runs a lot smoother.
c05771
DM: It's definitely snappier.
c05772
DM: There's something about... I, I, I think it's just the, like-
c05773
Unknown: Dude
c05774
DM: ... like-
c05775
Unknown: [laughs]
c05776
DM: There's, there's a [laughs] there's always, like, a little second delay-
c05777
Unknown: Yeah
c05778
DM: ... before the roll shows up on Roll20.
c05779
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c05780
DM: It's just, like-
c05781
Unknown: Yeah
c05782
DM: ... everything kind of-
c05783
Unknown: Ah
c05784
DM: ... has little delays.
c05785
Delwath: So I think the plan here,
c05786
Delwath: if Kenzo and Delwath switch-
c05787
DM: What, sorry, what were your initiatives?
c05788
Delwath: Four and 27.
c05789
Kenzo: But, but let's see what-
c05790
DM: Delwath's four?
c05791
Kenzo: ... let's see what, um, Schwartz rolls.
c05792
DM: Okay.
c05793
Kenzo: So we can always switch, switch with him.
c05794
Unknown: Yeah.
c05795
Unknown: Let's, let's do that.
c05796
Delwath: Yeah. But I actually don't know that going last is necessarily bad for Kenzo.
c05797
Unknown: No, it's not.
c05798
Unknown: Right?
c05799
DM: What did Seeker roll?
c05800
Seeker: Uh, two plus two, four.
c05801
Delwath: Ah, Seeker is also last.
c05802
DM: So [laughs]
c05803
DM: So you're going first and last.
c05804
Unknown: Uh,
c05805
Wellby: poorly. 20 all together.
c05806
DM: So you've got 27, 20, four, four.
c05807
Unknown: Yeah.
c05808
Kenzo: All right, yeah. So definitely. So you and I swap.
c05809
Unknown: Wait. I-
c05810
Kenzo: So that way, so that way, I, uh, Wellby can go second.
c05811
DM: So Delwath first, Wellby second.
c05812
Delwath: I think that's... Actually, that's perfect because Delwath will get advantage.
c05813
Unknown: If you...
c05814
Delwath: Delwath will get advantage on your, off your start of combat on my turn.
c05815
DM: 'Cause it lasts till the start of Wellby's turn.
c05816
Delwath: 'Cause it lasts till the start of... Yeah, that's perfect.
c05817
Delwath: So we all get advantage.
c05818
Delwath: And I can also cast... So I'm gonna cast Second Radiance.
c05819
Unknown: Awesome.
c05820
Delwath: Make us immune.
c05821
Unknown: Awesome.
c05822
Delwath: It'll fill the entire room, top to bottom.
c05823
Unknown: Awesome.
c05824
Delwath: So I mean, that's not ama- but it's, like, 4 d10 if they fail the save every single turn.
c05825
DM: You're mostly hoping to clean up minions.
c05826
Delwath: Yes. Well, c- but also it's repeated every turn.
c05827
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah. So it-
c05828
Unknown: There's no immunity
c05829
DM: ... it, although every single one of these has been immune to exhaust...
c05830
DM: Oh, but it does radiant damage.
c05831
Unknown: It does 4 d10.
c05832
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c05833
Delwath: And it makes the invisible guy not invisible.
c05834
DM: Right. Very right.
c05835
Delwath: It's not the exhaustion that I care about.
c05836
DM: Yeah.
c05837
Delwath: It's the 4 d10... DC 20 Con save for 14 damage-
c05838
DM: It's pretty good. Yeah
c05839
Unknown: ... is actually pretty good every turn.
c05840
Delwath: Plus, it should hopefully be off of immune.
c05841
DM: If you get out two thirds of the minions, that'll make a big difference.
c05842
Unknown: Exactly. Yeah.
c05843
Unknown: So I...
c05844
Seeker: Just to review what I can do as a golden dragon.
c05845
DM: You can use, you can use legendary resistance, you can use,
c05846
DM: you can use-
c05847
Unknown: As a golden dragon
c05848
DM: ... legendary actions.
c05849
Unknown: [laughs]
c05850
Unknown: Freaky.
c05851
DM: You just can't use lair effects.
c05852
Seeker: So I can do the Banish, I can do the Pounce.
c05853
Delwath: But you can't do the Spellcast.
c05854
DM: Oh, you can't do the Spellcast.
c05855
Delwath: You can't do Guiding Bolt.
c05856
Seeker: But Banish is not a spell.
c05857
DM: That's not a spell.
c05858
Unknown: It's just an effect.
c05859
DM: So you can do that.
c05860
Seeker: And I have the Fire Breath also.
c05861
DM: And you have the Fire Breath. That's pretty bonkers.
c05862
Delwath: But you should breathe.
c05863
Delwath: First move is breathe.
c05864
Seeker: Fire Breath?
c05865
Delwath: Yeah, definitely. Do Fire Breath your first round.
c05866
Delwath: 'Cause it also recharges if you roll...
c05867
Unknown: Every turn you roll a five or-
c05868
DM: You roll a five or a six
c05869
Delwath: ... roll a d6, and if you get a five or six, you get it back.
c05870
DM: Right.
c05871
Wellby: Are you a... You're an adult gold dragon?
c05872
DM: Adult gold dragon.
c05873
DM: [laughs]
c05874
Unknown: Adult gold dragon.
c05875
Unknown: Holy shit.
c05876
Unknown: 243 HP.
c05877
Delwath: We, we don't, we don't mess around anymore.
c05878
Unknown: Look, every-
c05879
DM: Oh, that's... So you get 243 temp HP on top of your regular hit points.
c05880
Unknown: Yeah.
c05881
Kenzo: That's insane. This is wa- this is more powerful than my silver dragon.
c05882
DM: It is.
c05883
Unknown: Yes.
c05884
DM: It's-
c05885
Seeker: That's 'cause it's a gold dragon.
c05886
DM: 'Cause it's a gold dragon.
c05887
DM: [laughs]
c05888
Unknown: [laughs]
c05889
Unknown: That's why we're here.
c05890
Unknown: It's how it works.
c05891
DM: But I... Your silver dragon was slightly reduced in effectiveness because the thing was immune to cold, and you did cold damage.
c05892
Unknown: Yeah.
c05893
DM: Although your Rend was very effective.
c05894
Delwath: And the lair actions.
c05895
Unknown: The lair was awesome.
c05896
DM: And the lair actions were very good.
c05897
Unknown: Lair was good.
c05898
Delwath: So okay, but so-
c05899
Wellby: You can Banish every, after every single turn?
c05900
Unknown: But it's only-
c05901
DM: You can only use that once per round.
c05902
DM: Yeah.
c05903
Unknown: All right.
c05904
Kenzo: You can only use that once per round.
c05905
Unknown: That's pretty, uh-
c05906
Unknown: But
c05907
Delwath: I think... So okay, Delwath will go first.
c05908
Delwath: I could, in theory...
c05909
Delwath: Oh, no, I can't bonus action
c05910
Delwath: do... We can all move.
c05911
Delwath: No, there's no reason to scatter, 'cause we can all move.
c05912
Unknown: We all have good mood.
c05913
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c05914
Delwath: Yeah, I'm gonna save.
c05915
Unknown: Okay.
c05916
Unknown: What?
c05917
Wellby: Fire breath is 12d10?
c05918
Unknown: Yes.
c05919
DM: That's a lot. [laughs]
c05920
Delwath: Gold dragons are powerful.
c05921
Unknown: Wow.
c05922
DM: See this with wish?
c05923
Unknown: No.
c05924
c05925
Seeker: It's his shape change.
c05926
DM: Shape change.
c05927
Unknown: So-
c05928
DM: That's the new-
c05929
Unknown: Other than
c05930
DM: ... ninth level spell that he has.
c05931
Kenzo: Holy fuck, so he can do this every battle?
c05932
Unknown: We can like-
c05933
DM: Every time
c05934
Unknown: You only get one ninth level spell
c05935
DM: You only get one ninth level spell slot.
c05936
Unknown: A day.
c05937
DM: A day.
c05938
Unknown: Yeah. But, but each day-
c05939
DM: Yes
c05940
Unknown: ... we can do this
c05941
DM: Every day he could do this.
c05942
DM: Oh, and also, remember
c05943
DM: when you transform with your glove, you can make yourself bigger or smaller if you wanna be bigger or smaller.
c05944
Seeker: I did not remember that.
c05945
DM: That's the new thing that your glove gives you.
c05946
Unknown: your glove does.
c05947
Kenzo: Is it... Do you wanna be...
c05948
Kenzo: Do you wanna take up the entire room or be a smaller gold dragon?
c05949
Unknown: Well, it's...
c05950
Seeker: The huge is 15 by 15-
c05951
Unknown: Can you-
c05952
Seeker: ... so three by three. So it's not clear that I can even really fit here.
c05953
DM: You probably can't fit if you go bigger than your current size.
c05954
Unknown: Are you already huge?
c05955
Unknown: No, the, the dragon-
c05956
DM: No, you're gargantuan
c05957
Unknown: ... is huge.
c05958
Delwath: Yeah. So getting bigger-
c05959
DM: Right
c05960
Unknown: ... would make you gargantuan.
c05961
DM: Bigger would make you gargantuan.
c05962
DM: It's not clear you would fit if you were bigger.
c05963
DM: But if you-
c05964
DM: But if you wanna be more maneuverable, you can be smaller.
c05965
Seeker: Is that better for any particular reason?
c05966
Delwath: No, you should just... No, we want you like a giant dragon blocking everything.
c05967
Delwath: Delwath can attack from 20 feet.
c05968
Delwath: Kenzo can attack from 50 feet.
c05969
Delwath: We can just stay on your back and stab through you.
c05970
Unknown: Ah,
c05971
Unknown: okay.
c05972
DM: So you're gonna stay normal size.
c05973
Seeker: In other words, huge.
c05974
DM: Yeah, huge.
c05975
Unknown: Yeah.
c05976
c05977
Delwath: That's three by three.
c05978
Delwath: Oh, wait, wait, wait.
c05979
DM: Hold on.
c05980
Delwath: Wait, why didn't you buy the dragon Lego set?
c05981
Unknown: [laughs]
c05982
Kenzo: Should've bought the dragon Lego set. I, I literally...
c05983
Unknown: [laughs]
c05984
Seeker: That's so funny.
c05985
Delwath: Tim probably has a dragon set.
c05986
Seeker: That was, like, at the pharmacy?
c05987
Unknown: Yeah.
c05988
Kenzo: That's so funny.
c05989
Unknown: But-
c05990
Delwath: I'm almost positive there's a dragon in here.
c05991
Unknown: [upbeat music]
c05992
Seeker: Crystal of growth, right?
c05993
Kenzo: Start another video or another, um...
c05994
Delwath: So the, from the door to the floor is 20 feet?
c05995
Unknown: 30 feet?
c05996
DM: 30 feet from the door to the floor.
c05997
Delwath: And we still think we can stand just in the air?
c05998
Delwath: I mean, like, we have any reason to believe that...
c05999
Seeker: Ah, sweet.
c06000
DM: I don't know which one you want.
c06001
Seeker: The gold one.
c06002
DM: I don't know if there is a gold one.
c06003
Delwath: Like, is there any advantage to actually flying?
c06004
DM: I don't know what that outright is. There's a little gold on it.
c06005
Unknown: Yeah.
c06006
DM: Okay.
c06007
Unknown: Yeah.
c06008
Kenzo: Dude, when are you guys gonna become dragons, huh?
c06009
Kenzo: Join the dragon club.
c06010
Seeker: We're all dragons on the inside.
c06011
Unknown: Or at least-
c06012
Delwath: I'm already a dragon
c06013
Kenzo: ... it's really just all about the dragons that we made along the way.
c06014
DM: Okay.
c06015
Kenzo: That we became along the way.
c06016
DM: So this is a little bit smaller than you actually are, so just, you know, remember you extend further than...
c06017
DM: But this is the only base I have for this style.
c06018
Seeker: Oh, and did I... I burned a s- a slot to re-summon the ladder, right?
c06019
DM: You burned a fourth level slot to re-summon the ladder.
c06020
Unknown: Yes, yes. Okay.
c06021
DM: So it's full hit points.
c06022
Wellby: Do we have, uh, fireballs left?
c06023
Unknown: Yeah.
c06024
DM: Yeah.
c06025
Delwath: That's a good thing to use.
c06026
Unknown: Can we still have fireballs?
c06027
Unknown: Why do you have fireballs?
c06028
Unknown: Who's got fireballs?
c06029
Unknown: I, I, I have a necklace of fireballs.
c06030
DM: Kenzo has the fireballs.
c06031
Unknown: Yeah.
c06032
DM: Delwath is up. What are you doing?
c06033
Delwath: I'm casting seeking radiance.
c06034
DM: Okay.
c06035
Unknown: Give me the necklace.
c06036
Unknown: I'm using a thingy-
c06037
Wellby: Use potion of speed so I'll have an extra action
c06038
Unknown: ... to make us all immune
c06039
Unknown: ... to get fireballs everywhere.
c06040
Unknown: I'll just give you... Just take all the beads.
c06041
Unknown: And then-
c06042
Unknown: And then I gotta-
c06043
Unknown: Yeah
c06044
Kenzo: ... keep track of that. Although I probably have them leveraged out, but...
c06045
DM: I don't know. I think you have, like, six left.
c06046
Unknown: I have six fireballs?
c06047
DM: Beads, yeah.
c06048
Kenzo: Check on the necklace.
c06049
DM: I mean, you can just gra- You can, you can just rush past and grab some beads off his neck if you want to.
c06050
Kenzo: Yeah. I, I have five charges left.
c06051
DM: Five left. Okay.
c06052
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. I'm drinking a potion of speed, too.
c06053
DM: That's a bonus action.
c06054
Unknown: Yeah.
c06055
DM: But wait till your turn.
c06056
Delwath: That's nice. Okay. I'm gonna drink as my bonus action...
c06057
Delwath: So I'm gonna cast a spell.
c06058
DM: Okay.
c06059
Unknown: Uh,
c06060
Delwath: and I will, um...
c06061
Delwath: I'm just trying to find it on here.
c06062
Delwath: Uh, height- uh, not height.
c06063
Unknown: An extra action from haste is separate from the bonus action.
c06064
Seeker: It's like, once I'm a dragon, I don't need that potion of invulnerability.
c06065
Unknown: Yeah.
c06066
Seeker: Lightening resistance-
c06067
Delwath: And then I'll-
c06068
Unknown: ... when you have-
c06069
Delwath: I'll drink my potion... As my bonus action-
c06070
Unknown: No
c06071
Delwath: ... I'll drink my potion of invulnerability.
c06072
DM: Okay.
c06073
Delwath: And then I'll, like...
c06074
Delwath: That's it. There's... I'm not even going through the door.
c06075
DM: Okay.
c06076
Delwath: What's the... It's 20...
c06077
Delwath: I mean, it's f-
c06078
DM: 30 feet to the ground.
c06079
Delwath: Yeah. So to attack these people, I only need to move 10 feet into the room.
c06080
DM: Yes.
c06081
DM: Okay.
c06082
DM: That ends Delwath's turn.
c06083
Unknown: Yeah.
c06084
DM: Okay. Wellby.
c06085
Wellby: All right. I, uh, bonus action, drink a potion of-
c06086
DM: Oh, wait, sorry. Before...
c06087
DM: At the end of your turn, um,
c06088
DM: the Queen of Ash looks up through the door at...
c06089
DM: I guess Kenzo is in the front.
c06090
DM: Um, and you, you...
c06091
DM: There's this wave of
c06092
DM: just deep regret that washes through you, and you see these images of chaos losing on the battlefield.
c06093
DM: Everyone make a wisdom saving throw.
c06094
DM: [dice rolling]
c06095
Unknown: 23.
c06096
Unknown: 21.
c06097
Unknown: Uh...
c06098
DM: Kenzo's okay.
c06099
Unknown: 12.
c06100
Unknown: 17
c06101
Seeker: plus zero. 17.
c06102
DM: Uh, Kenzo's okay.
c06103
DM: Um...
c06104
Unknown: 21.
c06105
DM: 21 fails.
c06106
Wellby: 21 fails?
c06107
Unknown: Damn.
c06108
Unknown: Um, Gwardia...
c06109
Unknown: Yeah.
c06110
Kenzo: Um, Gar, do you want...
c06111
DM: And-
c06112
Kenzo: Feels like we wanna, we wanna-
c06113
Unknown: It's too early for this
c06114
DM: ... make these saves.
c06115
Wellby: Yeah, I think so.
c06116
Delwath: No, no, I don't think it's too early. I'm just thinking,
c06117
Delwath: uh, there's no point in Gwarding on a 12.
c06118
Unknown: Oh, for you.
c06119
DM: That's probably not gonna work, but-
c06120
Unknown: It's like a heroic
c06121
Unknown: 23.
c06122
DM: That saves. That's what Kenzo rolled.
c06123
DM: You know that passes
c06124
Seeker: Now, oh, I, I used my-
c06125
DM: You used yours
c06126
Seeker: ... restoration for Seeker Six
c06127
DM: So you're out
c06128
Seeker: So I failed my save
c06129
DM: Oh, no, no, no wait. Seeker Six's last move before he died was gonna give you another bardic, so you have one more bardic.
c06130
DM: But-
c06131
Unknown: I'll use that
c06132
DM: ... you might wanna consider saving it to pass the impossible arcana check
c06133
Seeker: That, that was the original plan.
c06134
Unknown: Yeah.
c06135
Delwath: But do we have any reason to think we have to make the impossible arcana check urgently?
c06136
DM: Uh, there's a chance.
c06137
DM: I mean, urgently as in-
c06138
Unknown: Uh
c06139
DM: ... within five minutes?
c06140
DM: No. Urgently as before you long rest, possibly.
c06141
Unknown: Um.
c06142
DM: It's up to you.
c06143
Seeker: I have heroic still.
c06144
DM: Yeah.
c06145
Seeker: But that's not helpful for this at all.
c06146
DM: But you can't beat a 20...
c06147
DM: You can't roll... You need to...
c06148
DM: It's obviously-
c06149
Unknown: Yeah
c06150
DM: ... the DC is 22.
c06151
Unknown: Uh, I, I-
c06152
DM: 'Cause a 21 failed at a 23 plus
c06153
Seeker: ... it's still only 50/50 if I use the bardic, so...
c06154
Kenzo: Yeah, but the thing is, like we haven't even started yet.
c06155
Unknown: I don't know. You haven't even... You're not a dragon yet.
c06156
DM: You don't know what's gonna happen
c06157
Kenzo: ... you're not a dragon yet either, right?
c06158
Wellby: Maybe it helps you.
c06159
Kenzo: No, I mean, I feel like we should all make the save.
c06160
Kenzo: I feel like-
c06161
Wellby: It's-
c06162
Kenzo: ... 'cause we don't wanna get like, like knocked off our shit like at the start.
c06163
Wellby: 'Cause once you're a dragon you can legend or is...
c06164
Unknown: Exactly.
c06165
Unknown: True.
c06166
Kenzo: Exactly. You can do a whole bunch of shit.
c06167
Seeker: Let me use it.
c06168
Kenzo: Yeah, u- use it and turn into a dragon.
c06169
Unknown: It's a 12.
c06170
Kenzo: Like we gotta... I feel like we get fucked early on-
c06171
Delwath: Wait, what did I get?
c06172
Unknown: ... you know what I mean?
c06173
Seeker: So s- I rolled 17.
c06174
Unknown: Okay.
c06175
Wellby: Which was the... What's the roll?
c06176
Seeker: It's, yeah.
c06177
Unknown: Yeah.
c06178
Unknown: Okay.
c06179
Kenzo: So it's, it's 50/50.
c06180
Unknown: 17.
c06181
Seeker: So I need a six or higher?
c06182
Wellby: Yeah.
c06183
Kenzo: Six or higher.
c06184
Wellby: Yes.
c06185
Unknown: Yes. [claps]
c06186
DM: No, it's not 20... You need a 22, but you still succeed, yeah.
c06187
Delwath: 22. So I would need to roll a...
c06188
Delwath: I should roll a heroic
c06189
Unknown: I think.
c06190
Delwath: I'll use my heroic. [die rolling] That's worse.
c06191
Wellby: Oh.
c06192
Unknown: No.
c06193
DM: Delwath is dazed as the wave of sorrow str- s- washes over you.
c06194
DM: You may choose to move, do an action, or do a bonus action on your turn.
c06195
DM: Only one.
c06196
Unknown: Okay.
c06197
Kenzo: Oh, 'cause he can still cast your spell.
c06198
Unknown: I did.
c06199
DM: He already did.
c06200
Unknown: Oh.
c06201
DM: That's his next turn.
c06202
Unknown: Oh, good. Okay.
c06203
Wellby: Great.
c06204
Unknown: Okay. All right.
c06205
DM: You get another save at the end of every turn.
c06206
Delwath: That's just an, really annoying.
c06207
Kenzo: Uh, I can maybe bonus action cleanse you and remove your condition.
c06208
DM: That would be helpful.
c06209
DM: Uh, you won't be able to cleanse that.
c06210
DM: You could bonus action drag him into the room
c06211
DM: so that he could do something.
c06212
Kenzo: Huh?
c06213
Kenzo: What do you mean drag him into the room so you can do something?
c06214
Delwath: Nah, it's just I need my bonus action to cur- cast like curse at this person.
c06215
DM: Ah.
c06216
Unknown: That's what's annoying about it.
c06217
DM: When he's dazed he can either move, use an action, or use a bonus action.
c06218
Unknown: Mm.
c06219
DM: So right now he just can't do anything, but if he was in combat range he could at least attack.
c06220
Delwath: You can drag me in your turn.
c06221
DM: But it's a long tu-
c06222
Unknown: If you have a bonus action
c06223
DM: ... it's not Wellby's turn.
c06224
Unknown: Yeah.
c06225
Kenzo: I go last, so I can step with the wind and bring you into the-
c06226
Unknown: Yeah
c06227
Kenzo: ... into the room.
c06228
Wellby: Bonus action drink potion of haste.
c06229
DM: Okay.
c06230
Wellby: Uh,
c06231
Wellby: tell me about the mechanics for sneak attack with a extra action from haste.
c06232
Unknown: It's still your turn.
c06233
DM: The only action you c- the only action you can take with the extra action from haste is...
c06234
DM: So you can ready an action, and then you can trigger the sneak attack off your turn.
c06235
DM: So you can get three sneak attacks in that way.
c06236
Wellby: Great.
c06237
DM: But using the attack won't get you an extra standard.
c06238
Delwath: You can, you can like ready with haste.
c06239
DM: Oh, sorry. You ready with your, you ready with your normal action.
c06240
DM: You use the haste extra attack-
c06241
Delwath: But you only get one attack if you do that
c06242
DM: ... but he only ever gets one attack.
c06243
DM: He uses a bo-
c06244
Wellby: No
c06245
DM: ... you won't get your other attack this turn 'cause you bonus actioned.
c06246
Wellby: No, no, I understand. But if I-
c06247
DM: Your other attack is a bonus action
c06248
Unknown: ... use a bonus action my second.
c06249
Wellby: If I readied with my main action, I bonus action the second attack.
c06250
DM: No, you can't bo- you bonus action drank the potion.
c06251
Wellby: No, no, no, but in future rounds.
c06252
DM: Oh, yes. You can ready with your main action, bonus action attack.
c06253
Wellby: Got it.
c06254
DM: Haste attack.
c06255
Wellby: Okay. But this round though, uh, who do we wanna kill first?
c06256
Delwath: The queen. We should all focus all fire on the queen.
c06257
Wellby: Yeah?
c06258
Unknown: I think so.
c06259
Unknown: Okay.
c06260
Delwath: The second radiance will hopefully take out the minions pretty quickly.
c06261
Wellby: Yep.
c06262
Delwath: I mean, maybe Kenzo should cl- I mean, last time we actually clearing the minions would've been valuable, so possibly Kenzo should focus on...
c06263
Wellby: Is the queen wearing armor?
c06264
DM: Nope.
c06265
Wellby: Hmm.
c06266
Wellby: Do you think 24 hits the queen?
c06267
Unknown: Yeah.
c06268
c06269
Wellby: Awesome. Uh, because I feel like it would be insult to injury to use the clockwork amulet to take that first shot against the queen.
c06270
Wellby: [laughs]
c06271
DM: [laughs] Yes, it would be.
c06272
Kenzo: Um, what's the clockwork amulet do?
c06273
Wellby: It's an amulet from Machanis, the people who defeated her-
c06274
Unknown: Oh
c06275
Wellby: ... centuries ago.
c06276
Unknown: Love it.
c06277
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
c06278
DM: You don't roll, you just get a 10.
c06279
Unknown: Wait, you get a plus 14?
c06280
Wellby: Yep.
c06281
Delwath: Oh, 'cause haste. How do you get a plus 14?
c06282
Wellby: I don't know. It's your weapon.
c06283
DM: The Wayfarer bow is a plus two.
c06284
Kenzo: So but what happens with the clockwork amulet?
c06285
Wellby: Uh, it automatically rolls a 10.
c06286
DM: Oh, wait. Is that including any of your...
c06287
DM: Are your arrows equipped?
c06288
Kenzo: But then what happens that, that-
c06289
DM: No, I think it's-
c06290
Wellby: I think it's straight plus 14
c06291
DM: ... I think it's right. Yeah, yeah, yeah
c06292
Wellby: ... plus arrows.
c06293
Seeker: It just represents the-
c06294
Kenzo: Oh, you're just doing this for, for-
c06295
Delwath: Oh, it's a plus three
c06296
Delwath: ... symbolic.
c06297
DM: It's a, it must be a plus three bow.
c06298
Unknown: Symbolic.
c06299
Unknown: It must be plus three. Yeah.
c06300
Unknown: I love that.
c06301
Wellby: Yeah, exactly.
c06302
Unknown: I love that.
c06303
Unknown: Just a, just a piss one.
c06304
DM: I think it started as a plus
c06305
DM: two and I gave everybody an extra plus.
c06306
Wellby: Has she been soul sighted yet?
c06307
Unknown: Not now.
c06308
DM: No.
c06309
Delwath: That's the one downside of Kenza going last.
c06310
Unknown: Mm.
c06311
Kenzo: Uh, yeah.
c06312
Unknown: Bunch of downsides actually.
c06313
Wellby: Uh, I'll try and...
c06314
Wellby: I don't know, I'll try and trip her. Why not?
c06315
Wellby: It's a DC19 dex save.
c06316
Delwath: I, I assume 24 does in fact hit.
c06317
DM: Yeah, yeah. 24 hits.
c06318
Unknown: 17, 18.
c06319
DM: Um.
c06320
Unknown: 9.
c06321
DM: Uh.
c06322
Wellby: 10, okay.
c06323
Wellby: 20.
c06324
DM: Sh-
c06325
Wellby: 20
c06326
DM: ... she's fine. She falls to the ground, the arrow s- as the arrow strikes her.
c06327
Unknown: Oh, she's tripped?
c06328
DM: She's tripped.
c06329
Wellby: Awesome. 35-
c06330
Wellby: Piercing
c06331
DM: Okay
c06332
Wellby: And then for my other action, I will toss the triceratops down.
c06333
DM: Whoa.
c06334
Kenzo: Nice.
c06335
DM: Okay.
c06336
Seeker: This is gonna be one very-
c06337
DM: Okay
c06338
Unknown: ... full room in a second.
c06339
DM: How, how... What size is the triceratops?
c06340
Wellby: It's gotta be big, right?
c06341
Unknown: It's gotta be big.
c06342
Wellby: I feel like it was two by two squares.
c06343
DM: Okay. So, so this isn't quite a triceratops, but I saved this for when you used the triceratops.
c06344
Unknown: [laughs] Okay.
c06345
Unknown: So good.
c06346
Wellby: Okay. Triceratops. No, we'll put the triceratops next to her.
c06347
DM: [coughs] Okay, so it acts on its own initiative, right?
c06348
DM: So...
c06349
Unknown: Cool little creature.
c06350
Unknown: Yeah.
c06351
DM: Or does it act on yours?
c06352
Wellby: Uh.
c06353
DM: What does it say?
c06354
Wellby: Uh, I gotta see what's...
c06355
Wellby: Uh-
c06356
DM: Okay
c06357
Wellby: ... I'm gonna queue up.
c06358
Wellby: As an action, you throw it, transforms,
c06359
Wellby: friendly, understands commands.
c06360
DM: No, maybe it acts immediately after you.
c06361
Wellby: Yeah, it's gonna be-
c06362
Unknown: Most, most-
c06363
DM: If you can order it around, it acts immediately after you.
c06364
Unknown: Yeah.
c06365
Seeker: Wait, what did you throw to make it?
c06366
Wellby: It's a little, um, statue thing.
c06367
Kenzo: Yeah, it's Wellby's items.
c06368
Wellby: Uh, does that mean it's up now?
c06369
DM: Yeah, it's up.
c06370
Wellby: With regular triceratops stats, right?
c06371
DM: Yeah.
c06372
Wellby: Cool, cool, cool. It is going to,
c06373
Wellby: uh...
c06374
Delwath: Is not immune to the sickening radiance.
c06375
Wellby: Uh.
c06376
DM: So first it makes a save for the sickening radiance.
c06377
Wellby: Uh, what's it?
c06378
Unknown: DC 20 con.
c06379
Wellby: Uh, 16, fails.
c06380
Wellby: Uh, how much damage?
c06381
Unknown: 4d10. 11.
c06382
DM: That's not gonna be great, 'cause it now has a minus two on all of its-
c06383
Unknown: Four...
c06384
Delwath: And 18.
c06385
DM: It has minus two on all its DC, on all its attack rolls, too-
c06386
Wellby: Oh
c06387
DM: ... from exhaustion.
c06388
Wellby: That's okay.
c06389
Unknown: 'Cause of what?
c06390
Delwath: 'Cause it gained a level of exhaustion.
c06391
DM: Yeah.
c06392
Kenzo: Oh, 'cause of the sickening radiance.
c06393
DM: 'Cause of the sickening radiance.
c06394
Wellby: Oh, why isn't it immune?
c06395
Delwath: It's not, it's a triceratops, it's not immune to exhaustion.
c06396
Wellby: But what-
c06397
Delwath: Oh, it, it wasn't there when I cast the spell.
c06398
Wellby: Ah.
c06399
Unknown: Yeah.
c06400
DM: Plus, how many creatures can you do?
c06401
Delwath: Uh, I think it's by proficiency bonus.
c06402
DM: I think-
c06403
Unknown: It might only be-
c06404
DM: I thought-
c06405
Seeker: The dragon will be immune to me, right?
c06406
Unknown: Yeah.
c06407
DM: Yeah, the dragon's you, so it's immune.
c06408
Wellby: Uh, but I have advantage on attacks against the queen because she's prone and within five feet.
c06409
DM: Yeah. So straight rolls against the queen.
c06410
Delwath: Why straight rolls?
c06411
Wellby: Why would there be-
c06412
DM: Oh, sorry, sorry. Advantage, but minus two.
c06413
DM: I was thinking disadvantage, not minus two.
c06414
Wellby: Uh, okay. Triceratops attack with a plus nine to-
c06415
DM: Five creatures
c06416
Wellby: ... hit.
c06417
Unknown: It's might.
c06418
Wellby: That's a one and a three.
c06419
Unknown: Whoa.
c06420
Delwath: It's, um-
c06421
DM: Nope, that misses
c06422
Delwath: ... it's your-
c06423
DM: Charisma
c06424
Unknown: ... monster's-
c06425
DM: So it's five. So you couldn't...
c06426
DM: You've got the four of you plus the ladder anyway, so-
c06427
Delwath: That's true
c06428
DM: ... you couldn't have done the triceratops.
c06429
Wellby: When this lists gore and stomp, does that mean I choose one of these two for the action or both of these for, are the action?
c06430
Unknown: Usually it says-
c06431
Wellby: So it's two attacks
c06432
Unknown: ... when you attack if you-
c06433
Wellby: Okay, I would assume that also
c06434
Unknown: ...
c06435
Unknown: can do both.
c06436
DM: Uh-
c06437
Wellby: No, if the target is prone, the triceratops can make one stomp attack as a bonus action.
c06438
Unknown: I think my stamp attack is a bonus action.
c06439
Wellby: So bonus-
c06440
DM: Wait. Wait, wait, wait, hold on. Before you do that, um, so I would suggest, I would say you should just use the,
c06441
DM: the, there's a new tri- there's a, the other, the new triceratops, not the old triceratops, which has a multi-attack that says it can do
c06442
DM: two gore attacks,
c06443
DM: um, and it knocks people prone.
c06444
DM: It's better than the old one because the old one only gets the second attack-
c06445
Unknown: Triceratops
c06446
DM: ... if it's already prone.
c06447
Unknown: Triceratops
c06448
DM: So it's fiddly.
c06449
Wellby: Yeah.
c06450
Unknown: So you get a second attack.
c06451
DM: So you always-
c06452
Wellby: Yes
c06453
DM: ... you get to make two gore attacks.
c06454
Wellby: Good.
c06455
Wellby: Uh, still-
c06456
Unknown: Wow
c06457
Wellby: ... that's failure.
c06458
Wellby: A five and a nine on that.
c06459
DM: The triceratops is confused about the nature of limbo [laughs] and just misses completely.
c06460
DM: Um,
c06461
DM: the,
c06462
DM: uh,
c06463
DM: blood thing, metal blood thing, um, is going to first, uh-
c06464
Wellby: First save against-
c06465
DM: Save against sickening radiance.
c06466
DM: Uh, con, that's a 22.
c06467
Unknown: That makes it.
c06468
DM: And it is then going to...
c06469
DM: Let's see, Kenzo is in the doorway.
c06470
DM: Kenzo, um, make a constitution saving throw.
c06471
Unknown: Ooh, nice. 26.
c06472
DM: Okay. So nothing happens to you.
c06473
DM: Um,
c06474
DM: but then it is going to form out of its hand a, uh,
c06475
DM: like a spear of, of this molten blood that it's gonna throw up into the doorway straight at you three times.
c06476
Unknown: Molten blood?
c06477
Wellby: Three times?
c06478
DM: Uh-
c06479
Unknown: Spear back
c06480
DM: ... so that's going to be, ooh, okay, um-
c06481
Unknown: [laughs]
c06482
Unknown: Sounds good to me
c06483
DM: ... uh-
c06484
Wellby: Good
c06485
DM: ... 16, a 17, and a 19.
c06486
Kenzo: They all miss, thank God.
c06487
DM: Kenzo dodges out of the way of the-
c06488
Unknown: What's AC? 20.
c06489
Delwath: Yeah, when'd you get to 20 AC? That's nice.
c06490
Unknown: Yeah.
c06491
Unknown: I don't know.
c06492
Wellby: Uh, you're hasted, so your-
c06493
Unknown: Yeah. Hold on
c06494
Wellby: ... plus two to your AC.
c06495
DM: He hasn't drank his haste potion yet.
c06496
Unknown: Oh.
c06497
Kenzo: Oh, I haven't yet. Other reasons why I'm going last, actually.
c06498
Wellby: Mm, mm, mm, mm.
c06499
DM: Uh, that ends its turn.
c06500
DM: The queen now is going to turn,
c06501
DM: um,
c06502
DM: and look at you.
c06503
Unknown: Who's you?
c06504
DM: Up the d- up the door. You're the only one who's in s- sight at the moment.
c06505
Wellby: And that's not like a partial cover kind of situation?
c06506
DM: Uh, you're standing in an open door.
c06507
Wellby: [laughs] Yeah.
c06508
DM: Um,
c06509
DM: uh-
c06510
Kenzo: People starting to take damage from the sickening radiant too
c06511
DM: Uh, the queen's gonna make her save 'cause it's the beginning of her turn.
c06512
DM: Um, that is a 20.
c06513
Unknown: The DC is 20.
c06514
DM: So it succeeds.
c06515
Unknown: Mm.
c06516
DM: Um, the
c06517
DM: first thing she's going to do
c06518
DM: is... We need a, we need a, the, the fl- we need a third one for the...
c06519
DM: This is the,
c06520
DM: the room that you're all in.
c06521
Unknown: Oh.
c06522
DM: Where the door is on the floor.
c06523
Unknown: Right.
c06524
Seeker: But it's otherwise empty.
c06525
DM: It's otherwise empty.
c06526
DM: That's terrible. The door is right here.
c06527
DM: So where are you all?
c06528
DM: Kenzo's standing by the door.
c06529
Wellby: Um, right next to it.
c06530
DM: Uh, what is her move?
c06531
DM: Okay.
c06532
DM: Um,
c06533
DM: she is going to turn into a cloud of ash
c06534
DM: and
c06535
DM: appear,
c06536
DM: uh, right here.
c06537
DM: Sorry.
c06538
DM: Kenzo, you're [laughs]-
c06539
Seeker: Your staff's a little impractical
c06540
DM: ... your staff is slightly impractical.
c06541
DM: [laughs]
c06542
Unknown: Everybody's gonna have to live with it.
c06543
DM: [laughs]
c06544
Unknown: [laughs]
c06545
c06546
DM: Well, I guess Mike- Wellby is standing like right next to the door there.
c06547
Unknown: [laughs]
c06548
DM: So she's gonna appear right there.
c06549
Unknown: [laughs] Sorry, guys.
c06550
DM: Um.
c06551
Unknown: She's having-
c06552
DM: And then is going to, um,
c06553
DM: make
c06554
DM: an attack
c06555
DM: with a pale flame that s- um, s- appears from her hand.
c06556
DM: That's a 20... Sorry, against Wellby.
c06557
DM: That's a 27 to hit Wellby.
c06558
Unknown: Yeah, it's good.
c06559
Unknown: That hits.
c06560
DM: Okay, you take 20 points of radiant damage and 11 points of fire damage.
c06561
Wellby: Good.
c06562
DM: Second attack against Wellby.
c06563
DM: That's a 20 to hit.
c06564
Wellby: Uh, that's a hit.
c06565
Unknown: Did I thought you have plus 2 to AC?
c06566
Wellby: Uh, I do, but that only bring it 18.
c06567
DM: Uh, you have a n- take 19 points of radiant damage plus 13 points of fire damage.
c06568
Wellby: Are these attacks I can see?
c06569
DM: Yeah.
c06570
Wellby: Uh, I'll uncanny dodge that 19, I guess.
c06571
DM: Okay. So you can uncanny dodge both the 19 and the, what did I say for fire damage?
c06572
DM: 14.
c06573
Unknown: Yes.
c06574
DM: So you can uncanny... You can halve the total.
c06575
Unknown: So, so 34, 17.
c06576
Unknown: Yeah.
c06577
DM: So 17. And then, um, she is going to look at Kenzo.
c06578
DM: Uh, Kenzo or Seeker?
c06579
DM: Kenzo or Seeker? Who looks more threatening?
c06580
Wellby: Kenzo's such a big staff.
c06581
Delwath: Yeah, that staff. [laughs]
c06582
Unknown: So big.
c06583
DM: Okay, Kenzo, make it...
c06584
DM: Kenzo transforms into ash.
c06585
Kenzo: What? Now I don't even get to make a save?
c06586
DM: You can make a save at the start of your turn.
c06587
DM: At the moment, you are ash.
c06588
DM: Uh, and then she is going to jump back through the
c06589
DM: door. If she can.
c06590
Unknown: Do we get two attacks?
c06591
Unknown: No opportunity attacks?
c06592
DM: Uh, you used your reaction.
c06593
Unknown: I haven't.
c06594
Unknown: You can use your opportunity attack.
c06595
DM: Kenzo is ash.
c06596
Unknown: Uh,
c06597
Delwath: yeah. What am I gonna use my reaction for?
c06598
Kenzo: Say it like that. Kenzo is ash.
c06599
Wellby: Did she teleport up there?
c06600
DM: I mean, she teleported up there.
c06601
Wellby: Okay. So no opportunity for the triceratops.
c06602
DM: Um, yeah.
c06603
Delwath: I might wanna save my reaction.
c06604
DM: I mean, if you...
c06605
DM: You know, it might be useful for shield.
c06606
Unknown: Yeah.
c06607
DM: But other than shield-
c06608
Kenzo: Well, you know I don't have these actions.
c06609
DM: Or-
c06610
Unknown: Does it do anything
c06611
Unknown: else?
c06612
DM: At the moment you are currently immune to damage.
c06613
Wellby: I hope we all become ash.
c06614
Delwath: I don't think you want to stay ash though.
c06615
Kenzo: No, at the start of my turn, I'm not gonna be ash anymore.
c06616
DM: I'm going to attack.
c06617
DM: 17.
c06618
Unknown: 17 to hit?
c06619
Unknown: No, no, no, no, 30.
c06620
DM: Okay. Yeah, yeah, that hits.
c06621
Delwath: I rolled a 17. I need some d4s.
c06622
DM: Uh, should I just smite her?
c06623
DM: Why not? Like, jump-
c06624
Delwath: Why would I not smite her?
c06625
DM: Jump damage
c06626
Unknown: Right?
c06627
DM: Can you smite on an opportunity attack?
c06628
Unknown: It's a free action.
c06629
DM: Oh, it's not a bonus. Oh, right.
c06630
Unknown: It's not a bonus.
c06631
DM: It's only the... Yeah, yeah.
c06632
Wellby: You have, uh, advantage to hit her also.
c06633
Wellby: You should roll again just in case you crit.
c06634
Unknown: Ah. No.
c06635
Unknown: That'd be cool.
c06636
Delwath: Yeah, I think, why would I not smite, right?
c06637
Delwath: Like, I should just smite her.
c06638
DM: Yeah.
c06639
Unknown: I need some eights.
c06640
Unknown: Actually, you know what?
c06641
Unknown: Uh,
c06642
Unknown: one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10.
c06643
Delwath: 41 damage plus five, 46 damage.
c06644
DM: 46 damage?
c06645
Unknown: Yeah.
c06646
DM: Okay.
c06647
Kenzo: If you, if you, when you bonus action drink your, your potion of speed, you get, you now get the bonus action back 'cause you just-
c06648
DM: You don't get the bonus action back
c06649
Unknown: ... on the next turn
c06650
DM: ... you get the extra-
c06651
Kenzo: On the ne- on the next turn
c06652
Wellby: On the same
c06653
Unknown: ... on that same turn.
c06654
Unknown: Okay.
c06655
Kenzo: So it's effectively like you just drank a potion and now you can do your normal stuff.
c06656
DM: You get an action...
c06657
DM: You just don't get your bonus action back.
c06658
Unknown: Okay.
c06659
Unknown: You get an action and a-
c06660
Unknown: Extra
c06661
DM: ... an extra action you can only use to do a few limited things.
c06662
Unknown: Yeah.
c06663
DM: But one of those is make an attack.
c06664
Unknown: Right. But only one attack.
c06665
DM: Only one attack.
c06666
Wellby: So I would use two of my attacks.
c06667
DM: Yes.
c06668
Unknown: Uh-
c06669
Wellby: Three of my attacks
c06670
Wellby: ... but another could be you throw a fireball.
c06671
Delwath: You could.
c06672
Wellby: Hence the divining the beads.
c06673
Unknown: Right.
c06674
DM: Okay. She, she's dropped now through the floor, so can you put her back in the middle of the room?
c06675
DM: The middle of the bottom room.
c06676
Seeker: Let's get some... Why, why are you coming over here?
c06677
Unknown: Yeah, Kenzo.
c06678
DM: Uh, and that ends her turn.
c06679
DM: Um,
c06680
DM: okay. Green air sparks.
c06681
Unknown: Saves.
c06682
DM: All make saves.
c06683
DM: Uh, how many greens are there?
c06684
Unknown: Oh, you only need-
c06685
Unknown: One, two, three, four, five, six
c06686
Seeker: ... one green. Depends how you count greenness, but
c06687
DM: Six
c06688
Unknown: ... yeah.
c06689
DM: Yeah, those six. Those six is good Uh, what's the D-
c06690
Unknown: 20
c06691
DM: ... okay. Uh, and it's con?
c06692
Unknown: Yeah.
c06693
DM: Uh, none of those succeed.
c06694
DM: That's five.
c06695
Delwath: So one, two, three, four, five have gone.
c06696
DM: Mm, six. None of them succeed.
c06697
Wellby: All right.
c06698
Wellby: Then six, right?
c06699
Unknown: Well,
c06700
Seeker: oh yeah, six. Wait, is that six?
c06701
DM: That's five there.
c06702
Unknown: Six.
c06703
DM: So there sh- are there 14 left?
c06704
Delwath: Three, six, nine, 10, 11, 12, 15, wait.
c06705
Kenzo: Three, six, nine,
c06706
Unknown: 10. There's 15 of
c06707
Unknown: them, so minus one.
c06708
DM: Oh yeah, yeah. There are 21, that's fine.
c06709
Unknown: Yeah.
c06710
DM: Um,
c06711
DM: uh, okay, that ends their turn.
c06712
DM: Now the,
c06713
DM: the mist thing-
c06714
Unknown: Save?
c06715
DM: Just gonna make a save.
c06716
DM: Uh, that's a fail.
c06717
Unknown: It's visible?
c06718
DM: It's visible, yep.
c06719
DM: Um-
c06720
Unknown: Damage. Hold on.
c06721
Delwath: Uh, 16 plus...
c06722
Unknown: Ooh, now I'm rolling good rolls.
c06723
DM: [laughs]
c06724
Delwath: 16 plus 18, so-
c06725
Unknown: 34?
c06726
Unknown: 34, yeah.
c06727
Delwath: 34 damage.
c06728
DM: Okay.
c06729
DM: Uh...
c06730
Delwath: I assume they're all immune to exhaustion.
c06731
DM: Yes, they're all immune to exhaustion.
c06732
DM: Um, this thing is going to-
c06733
Unknown: Kenzo can see it now
c06734
DM: ... can see it now, yep.
c06735
DM: Um...
c06736
Wellby: The minions?
c06737
Delwath: Uh, no. This-
c06738
Unknown: Oh
c06739
Delwath: ... the invisible guy-
c06740
Wellby: Okay
c06741
Delwath: ... who you couldn't see before is now glowing with a pale green light.
c06742
Wellby: Cool.
c06743
DM: Um, it's gonna fly up,
c06744
DM: uh, to be through the door.
c06745
Delwath: It's this guy, right?
c06746
DM: Yep.
c06747
DM: Um, it is-
c06748
Kenzo: Playing as Ash right now, I'm just gonna be-
c06749
Unknown: Hey, buddy
c06750
DM: ... yeah. It is going to, um, attack
c06751
DM: Delwath.
c06752
DM: Um,
c06753
DM: with two attacks.
c06754
DM: Uh, that's a 14 and a 26.
c06755
Unknown: 26 hits.
c06756
DM: Um, you take
c06757
DM: 14 points of slashing plus 19 points of psychic.
c06758
Delwath: Uh, okay, so seven.
c06759
Delwath: I'm in, I'm invulner- I'm, I'm, uh, uh, resistant to all damage.
c06760
DM: So you take 16 points of damage and make a con-
c06761
DM: a concentration check.
c06762
Unknown: Uh,
c06763
Unknown: 12.
c06764
DM: 12 is fine. And then Seeker, make a constitution saving throw.
c06765
Seeker: Wait, what? Uh-oh.
c06766
Unknown: [die rolling]
c06767
Delwath: Uh, sorry, you said 16 damage?
c06768
DM: 16 damage, yeah.
c06769
Seeker: That's a nine total.
c06770
DM: Um, this creature disappears inside you.
c06771
Unknown: It what?
c06772
DM: Slides down your mouth.
c06773
Delwath: Oh, Jesus. Um, that 16 was halved, right?
c06774
DM: Yes, that was already halved.
c06775
Unknown: [laughs] Have you look at-
c06776
DM: Uh, it is now hiding inside Seeker.
c06777
Delwath: Uh, awesome.
c06778
Kenzo: Wait, is this sort of like a-
c06779
Kenzo: So what happens when you become a dragon?
c06780
Kenzo: Exactly. Can it take you over?
c06781
Delwath: Is it gonna eat you from the inside out?
c06782
Unknown: Or can it take you over and be something-
c06783
Delwath: Is it gonna do something really bad?
c06784
DM: Uh, more air sparks being ready to get wiped out by-
c06785
Unknown: What do I do?
c06786
Unknown: I think you just, just breathe out really hard.
c06787
Wellby: [die rolling]
c06788
DM: Uh, one.
c06789
Kenzo: Do this one at the end of your turn.
c06790
Unknown: At the end of your turn.
c06791
DM: Two succeed.
c06792
Delwath: Wait, halfway through the business.
c06793
Unknown: Which group is this?
c06794
DM: Uh, this is blue.
c06795
DM: I rolled seven and-
c06796
Delwath: One, two, three, four, five.
c06797
Unknown: We'll finish this combat-
c06798
Kenzo: There isn't-
c06799
Kenzo: We'll finish this combat by the end
c06800
Delwath: ... there isn't really a group of seven, but-
c06801
DM: Okay.
c06802
Wellby: Tell us, tell us how many are out.
c06803
DM: Uh, five are out.
c06804
Delwath: Three, four, five.
c06805
DM: Okay. So-
c06806
Delwath: There's, there's like...
c06807
Unknown: That was good
c06808
DM: I'll change these into-
c06809
Unknown: Yes. Whoops
c06810
Unknown: Yes
c06811
DM: ... I'll change those into red ones.
c06812
Unknown: Got it.
c06813
DM: So we'll say th- these two are the blue ones, and they fly out through the door,
c06814
DM: and they are going to,
c06815
DM: um,
c06816
DM: fly towards Delwath
c06817
DM: and attack you.
c06818
Delwath: 'Cause like, remember when I said you could save your reaction for shields?
c06819
Wellby: Ah, I was just doing the same thing. Like, I saved myself [laughs] a few points of damage, but,
c06820
Unknown: eh.
c06821
DM: Uh, that's a 25.
c06822
Unknown: That hits.
c06823
DM: Um, you take 16 points of slashing damage.
c06824
Delwath: Is that already halved?
c06825
DM: No. So halved to eight.
c06826
DM: Um, and it is going to push you up against the wall.
c06827
DM: Wait, sorry, who was...
c06828
DM: Somebody was, failed the save against days.
c06829
DM: That was Delwath, right?
c06830
DM: Okay.
c06831
DM: Um-
c06832
Delwath: But I forgot I have bless.
c06833
Unknown: I have potion of heroism.
c06834
Delwath: Oh, from... But you were
c06835
DM: quite far away.
c06836
Delwath: I was far away. But actually-
c06837
DM: Um-
c06838
Delwath: ... thinking about it, the 12 plus the bless-
c06839
DM: My-
c06840
Unknown: ... plus the bardic
c06841
DM: ... might've been worth a try
c06842
Unknown: ... might've been worth a try.
c06843
Delwath: The six plus the bless might've been worth a try,
c06844
Unknown: but.
c06845
DM: That ends their turn.
c06846
DM: How many are left? One, two, three.
c06847
DM: Eight are left?
c06848
Unknown: Yep.
c06849
DM: Uh...
c06850
Kenzo: I like being Ash, not getting attacked by anything right now.
c06851
Unknown: [laughs] That's pretty, that's pretty great.
c06852
DM: Um-
c06853
Wellby: Unusual for you
c06854
Unknown: ... and not soaking up all the damage.
c06855
DM: Five-
c06856
Unknown: I literally was in the doorway
c06857
DM: ... five of those eight die.
c06858
DM: I rolled six
c06859
Delwath: ... and all the monsters and everybody's looking up at me, and I was like, "I'm taking the majority of the-"
c06860
DM: Uh, seven of those eight die
c06861
Wellby: ... several combats.
c06862
DM: The last one will fly off and merge with this group-
c06863
Unknown: Oh, they die
c06864
DM: ... but make its own individual attack.
c06865
Unknown: This is great.
c06866
Unknown: Good strategy.
c06867
DM: Uh, and that's a one, so it misses.
c06868
Unknown: Perfect.
c06869
Unknown: That's great.
c06870
DM: Um, that ends the minions.
c06871
DM: Uh, one-
c06872
Delwath: There's still the centaur
c06873
DM: ... the centaur-
c06874
Delwath: Then, then Seeker and Kenzo finally
c06875
DM: ... yep, is going to...
c06876
DM: That's a 22 for its save.
c06877
DM: Um, and then-
c06878
Kenzo: Which one's the centaur?
c06879
DM: [coughs]
c06880
Kenzo: And this is the queen
c06881
Kenzo: Yeah. And did that thing attack yet?
c06882
Delwath: No. No, it threw something at you.
c06883
Unknown: It threw-
c06884
DM: Yeah, you've missed
c06885
Unknown: ... all three of its attacks.
c06886
DM: It, you dodged all three of them.
c06887
Unknown: Got it.
c06888
DM: Um, the, uh-
c06889
Unknown: This thing does the same thing
c06890
DM: ... this thing is gonna do its iron skin thing.
c06891
DM: Its skin toughens.
c06892
Unknown: [laughs]
c06893
DM: Um, and then, uh, its arm is gonna change into, like, a spike that is gonna
c06894
DM: shoot up through the
c06895
DM: door at Wellby.
c06896
DM: You have half cover.
c06897
DM: It's g-
c06898
Wellby: What, uh, what does that do mechanically?
c06899
DM: Plus two to your AC.
c06900
Wellby: Yeah. All right. That brings me to 20.
c06901
Unknown: 20
c06902
DM: So it's gonna make three attacks against you.
c06903
Wellby: That's a lot of attacks.
c06904
DM: So that's a 21, a 18,
c06905
DM: and a
c06906
DM: 27.
c06907
Wellby: All right, two hits.
c06908
DM: Um, and that's going to be 26 plus 23 points of slashing damage.
c06909
Unknown: All right, 49.
c06910
Wellby: Got it.
c06911
DM: That ends its turn.
c06912
DM: Your Seeker is up.
c06913
Unknown: Oh my God.
c06914
Delwath: Just dragon it up.
c06915
Seeker: I will, um...
c06916
Kenzo: Wait, wait, wait. Hold on, hold on. Do we know what the thing that, that went inside it, what, what is that doing?
c06917
Unknown: We have no idea.
c06918
DM: No idea.
c06919
Kenzo: 'Cause worst case scenario it takes over Seeker and now all of a sudden they've got a gold dragon.
c06920
DM: That's true.
c06921
Kenzo: That would be really bad.
c06922
Unknown: That would be really bad.
c06923
Kenzo: Like, literally bad. Like, probably worst case scenario really bad.
c06924
Kenzo: Like, we're all gonna die if that's, if that's what that thing-
c06925
DM: That is true.
c06926
Delwath: But, but
c06927
Delwath: here's the thing. Mechanically in D&D it can't without a save, and once he's a dragon he'll have legendary-
c06928
DM: He has legendary resistances
c06929
Unknown: Yes.
c06930
Unknown: Which do what?
c06931
Unknown: I just-
c06932
Wellby: And the frame is like it's-
c06933
DM: Automatic succeed on the save
c06934
Unknown: ... automatic succeed the save.
c06935
Unknown: Oh.
c06936
Delwath: So you should become a dragon to protect yourself from the evil inside you.
c06937
DM: Yeah.
c06938
Seeker: I like it.
c06939
DM: That's a good vibe.
c06940
Seeker: What about the potion of invulnerability? Is that worth doing?
c06941
Delwath: Nah. No. Well, you could bonus ac- can you do anything else with your bonus action?
c06942
Unknown: Wait, wait.
c06943
DM: You can pass out.
c06944
Wellby: When you dragon, though, you wanna jump through the hole first, right?
c06945
Unknown: Because once you're a dragon you won't be able to-
c06946
DM: Yeah
c06947
Wellby: ... fit through the door.
c06948
DM: You wanna jump through the hole, drink, cast the spell while you're in midair, and bonus action bardic before you turn into a dragon.
c06949
Unknown: Why bonus action bardic?
c06950
Seeker: Well, I'm glad you mentioned the size of the door-
c06951
DM: So somebody has an inspiration
c06952
Unknown: ... and
c06953
Unknown: the size, because I didn't think of that
c06954
Unknown: You want me to stick my head in? Ah. [laughs]
c06955
Unknown: You could still stick your head in and breathe fire.
c06956
Seeker: That would be funny and good, but I should probably be on the other side of the door.
c06957
Seeker: Yeah. Okay.
c06958
Delwath: So I, I would do that.
c06959
Wellby: Yeah.
c06960
DM: Although you guess you can still pass out bardic in dragon form.
c06961
Unknown: As a dragon, right?
c06962
Unknown: Yeah.
c06963
Delwath: So I mean, you may as well pass out a bardic with your bonus action.
c06964
Seeker: Who, who should it go to? Probably-
c06965
Delwath: Who still has... I mean, I still have one.
c06966
Kenzo: I, I used mine. Give it to me-
c06967
Unknown: You used it all?
c06968
Kenzo: ... 'cause I need to, I need to pass a save to-
c06969
Unknown: Ah, yeah, to become the Kenzo
c06970
Kenzo: ... to, to become that again.
c06971
DM: All right. Yeah, yeah.
c06972
Unknown: So
c06973
Seeker: Seeker uncharacteristically r- reaches jogging speed and [laughs]
c06974
Unknown: [laughs] Really?
c06975
Delwath: ... points over to Kenzo [laughs]
c06976
Kenzo: Well, c- c- points it over to a pile of ash on the ground.
c06977
DM: Yeah.
c06978
Seeker: Shooting a s- little glowing rune in the air.
c06979
Unknown: [laughs]
c06980
Seeker: And then leaps, um,
c06981
Seeker: s- uh, feet first, uh-
c06982
DM: Yeah
c06983
Seeker: ... through the door in the floor while-
c06984
Unknown: He wishes he was no powers now
c06985
Seeker: ... gesturing vaguely in the air, uh, and muttering about dragons.
c06986
Unknown: Um-
c06987
DM: And he has a counter spell.
c06988
Unknown: Oh, boy.
c06989
Unknown: No, neither does him.
c06990
Seeker: And casts-
c06991
DM: She's not a spell caster
c06992
Seeker: ... shape change, becoming an adult gold dragon.
c06993
Unknown: Sweet.
c06994
Unknown: All right.
c06995
Kenzo: There's gotta be a... At some point, there's gonna be some AI thing-
c06996
Unknown: Yeah
c06997
Kenzo: ... that'll be cool that can, like, live transcribe us as we're talking, and then there's, like, a video of it showing-
c06998
DM: [laughs] Yeah
c06999
Unknown: ... the, you know?
c07000
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
c07001
DM: So gold dragon-
c07002
Kenzo: That's gotta hap- that can't be too far away.
c07003
Delwath: You, you're on th- how about you're on this one?
c07004
DM: You're in the... You're probably in the middle circle there.
c07005
Unknown: Yeah.
c07006
Seeker: Yeah. So-
c07007
DM: Just breathing straight down.
c07008
Unknown: Yeah. But you can't act.
c07009
DM: You're gonna-
c07010
Unknown: Yeah
c07011
DM: ... you're gonna toast...
c07012
DM: Not, that'll have to be your next turn 'cause you used your action for shape change.
c07013
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c07014
Delwath: The triceratops is not-
c07015
Seeker: Three by, three by three
c07016
Unknown: ... I'm three by three
c07017
Wellby: ... in a larger sense the triceratops can't die.
c07018
Unknown: It can only turn-
c07019
DM: Right, it can only turn back into stone
c07020
Unknown: ... to stone. Yeah.
c07021
DM: Um, so Kenzo's up.
c07022
Unknown: Oh my God.
c07023
DM: Make a constitution saving throw.
c07024
Unknown: Thank God. [laughs] Okay.
c07025
Seeker: Okay, okay, okay, okay.
c07026
Seeker: Wait, after Kenzo's turn can I take a legendary action?
c07027
DM: Yep.
c07028
Unknown: Yep.
c07029
Unknown: Oh, fuck.
c07030
Unknown: [laughs]
c07031
Kenzo: Um, that's an 11.
c07032
Unknown: Uh-
c07033
DM: 11 total?
c07034
Kenzo: Yeah, I rolled a three. So I think I'm gonna spend a ki and re-roll that.
c07035
DM: Yeah, you really wanna spend a ki to re-roll that.
c07036
Unknown: I'm gonna spend-
c07037
DM: Like, really, really.
c07038
Kenzo: Yeah, I really, really spend a ki to re-roll that.
c07039
Unknown: There we go.
c07040
DM: Oh, much better.
c07041
Unknown: Thank you.
c07042
DM: 28. Great.
c07043
Kenzo: Uh, 26.
c07044
Unknown: 26.
c07045
DM: So you take 55 points of necrotic damage.
c07046
Delwath: You turn back to Kenzo?
c07047
DM: You turn back into Kenzo.
c07048
DM: The alternative was to be reduced to one hit point.
c07049
Wellby: Whoa.
c07050
Kenzo: But that actually wouldn't have been too bad.
c07051
Unknown: [laughs]
c07052
Kenzo: Um, 'cause then I could have, uh, uh, recovery boomed myself, I think.
c07053
DM: That's true, ac- no, no, you have to be reduced to zero-
c07054
Unknown: Go to zero. Yeah, yeah
c07055
DM: ... to recover. That's-
c07056
Kenzo: So then I, I stab myself and go to zero and then-
c07057
DM: That actually-
c07058
Delwath: Wait, can Kenzo grab Delwath even though I'm pushed back against the wall?
c07059
DM: I mean, it depends on how much movement Kenzo's got.
c07060
Kenzo: Yeah, I've got 70 move.
c07061
Delwath: Where is Kenzo? Wait, Kenzo...
c07062
Kenzo: I was-
c07063
DM: Oh, he was ash, but now he's not.
c07064
DM: He's right there.
c07065
Unknown: Yeah.
c07066
DM: So you've got 55.
c07067
DM: It's reduced your r-
c07068
Unknown: Five
c07069
Delwath: ... oh, no, you haven't activated your thing because you haven't done your turn yet.
c07070
Unknown: I haven't done my turn yet.
c07071
DM: Yeah, yeah.
c07072
Kenzo: Okay. So now I spend-
c07073
Delwath: Oh, but if you get ha- if you drink your potion of haste you speed doubles.
c07074
Seeker: Yeah, yeah. But, okay.
c07075
DM: So-
c07076
Unknown: Hold on. H- h- h- h-
c07077
DM: Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
c07078
Kenzo: So okay, first thing Kenzo does is I activate my, um, my, uh, superior defense,
c07079
Kenzo: which I do at the start of my turn.
c07080
Kenzo: So now I'm resistant to d-
c07081
DM: Yeah
c07082
Kenzo: ... resistant to all damage.
c07083
Kenzo: Now, um, I'll bonus action drink the potion of haste.
c07084
DM: Uh,
c07085
DM: yeah, so it's compli- so if you're gonna grab Delwath you need to-
c07086
Unknown: Do that first
c07087
DM: ... bonus action
c07088
DM: step of the wind.
c07089
Unknown: Oh, and then I gotta-
c07090
Unknown: And so you get nothing
c07091
DM: ... so you have to action drink the potion, so then you can't...
c07092
DM: You won't be able to attack if you drink the potion and grab Delwath.
c07093
Delwath: Well, you could still attack with the hasted attack.
c07094
DM: You can still, you can make one attack with your haste.
c07095
Unknown: Well, okay
c07096
Wellby: Why can't you grab Delweth with the hasted action?
c07097
Wellby: And so like-
c07098
DM: It's only a bonus action. He has to use Step of the Wind if he wants to carry Delweth-
c07099
Unknown: Which has to be haste
c07100
DM: ... which has to be a bonus action
c07101
Unknown: ... or
c07102
Unknown: something like that.
c07103
Kenzo: But why do I, why do I wanna do that, for you?
c07104
Delwath: Because I can't move and-
c07105
DM: Oh, so Delweth can't move and take an action
c07106
Kenzo: But Garen, do you want to just kill these guys in front of you?
c07107
Wellby: Or do you want me to first...
c07108
DM: I think that's a
c07109
DM: waste, but...
c07110
Kenzo: 'Cause the other thing I need to do is I need, also need a bonus action to activate Lae'zel's Claw.
c07111
DM: You can't do two bonus actions.
c07112
Kenzo: That's what I'm saying. So... But can, I can also do that as an action, right?
c07113
DM: That should, that should just... That, you should...
c07114
DM: That shouldn't be a bonus action attack.
c07115
DM: Or no.
c07116
DM: Yeah, no, that is... Actually, yes, that is a bonus action, right?
c07117
DM: So you have a lot of bonus actions.
c07118
Kenzo: That, that's how, that's how it's structured currently, as a bonus action.
c07119
Kenzo: So... But I think I need a bonus action haste.
c07120
Kenzo: That's the most important bonus action, to just get that extra-
c07121
Wellby: Yeah
c07122
Unknown: ... action for this.
c07123
Wellby: I think so.
c07124
Kenzo: So if I bonus action to do that, now I've got, I've got my two normal actions and now I've got my haste action, so I've got three actions.
c07125
DM: No, you o- normally only have one action.
c07126
Unknown: Okay.
c07127
DM: So you bonus action to drink the potion.
c07128
DM: You've got an action-
c07129
Unknown: Right, right
c07130
DM: ... and you've got your haste action. But then Delweth has less strength.
c07131
Delwath: I don't know. I think this is a weak strategy 'cause if Delweth doesn't make a fairly high save, I will basically not be in the combat.
c07132
Seeker: We didn't do, um, ladder turn.
c07133
DM: Oh, right.
c07134
Unknown: Did we do ladder?
c07135
DM: Ladder gets a turn after Seeker.
c07136
DM: So that's right now.
c07137
Unknown: Go ahead.
c07138
Wellby: This is good. The timing's good.
c07139
Unknown: Well-
c07140
Delwath: Ladder should go kill the minions.
c07141
Kenzo: Yeah. There you go.
c07142
Wellby: Yep.
c07143
Seeker: Yeah. Ladder has a move of-
c07144
DM: I, I don't think haste is gonna do as much for you as it does for Wellby because it-
c07145
Unknown: 'Cause it's only one
c07146
DM: ... it lets Wellby get an extra sneak attack.
c07147
Unknown: There you go
c07148
DM: ... but it lets you make one extra attack, which isn't that strong.
c07149
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c07150
DM: And your staff lets you make...
c07151
DM: I mean, your staff is...
c07152
DM: You can make two extra attacks, only the first one round.
c07153
DM: But-
c07154
Unknown: Yeah
c07155
DM: ... I think you're gonna be better off getting Delweth through the door-
c07156
Unknown: Okay
c07157
DM: ... so he can do stuff even if he doesn't beat the save for the days.
c07158
Unknown: Okay.
c07159
Unknown: Okay. And then-
c07160
DM: 'Cause it's much, it's much better for Delweth to be able to-
c07161
Delwath: Make three attacks
c07162
DM: ... make three attacks even if he can't use a bonus action, than for Delweth to have to waste his whole turn moving and do nothing else.
c07163
Kenzo: All right. Well, clear out these minions and then I'll make it easier for me to get the-
c07164
Seeker: Ladder just has the one attack.
c07165
Unknown: That hits.
c07166
Unknown: Um,
c07167
Seeker: so 20 night.
c07168
Unknown: Yeah.
c07169
Seeker: Um, and it does a D10 plus six.
c07170
DM: Yeah, it's not gonna fully kill it, but it knocks out one minion.
c07171
DM: But you're not gonna overkill.
c07172
Delwath: That's 12. Right. So one minion's gone.
c07173
DM: Yep.
c07174
Unknown: Good job, Ladder.
c07175
DM: So now Kenzo.
c07176
Kenzo: Okay. Then, uh,
c07177
Kenzo: sh- if I get you through the door...
c07178
Kenzo: But then once that you're through the door, I still can't attack.
c07179
Delwath: No, you can. You-
c07180
Kenzo: But what can I attack?
c07181
DM: You just drop down to the ground.
c07182
Delwath: You drop down, you attack the Queen of Ash who landed on the ground.
c07183
Unknown: With advantage.
c07184
Unknown: And you'll have advantage.
c07185
Unknown: All right. Okay. All right.
c07186
Delwath: I mean, you could use two attacks to kill the two minions.
c07187
Kenzo: Nah, [censored] that.
c07188
Unknown: But-
c07189
DM: 'Cause your bonus action's Step of the Wind, so you only ha- have...
c07190
DM: Well, you could use your staff to make four attacks.
c07191
Delwath: Uh, you only get two attacks, right, 'cause you don't get your bonus action to get extra attacks.
c07192
Kenzo: I'm so confused.
c07193
Delwath: But just do it.
c07194
Kenzo: All right. So I'm gonna Step of the Winds.
c07195
Unknown: Like, here.
c07196
Kenzo: Go over here, grab Delweth, and then go over here,
c07197
Kenzo: drop you through the door. So now you're, like, here.
c07198
Unknown: Well, down here.
c07199
DM: You've fallen... You fall.
c07200
Unknown: Oh.
c07201
DM: There's gravity here.
c07202
Kenzo: Okay. Oh, so we all fall, we all fall to the ground.
c07203
Delwath: Wow. Wait.
c07204
Delwath: Ah, okay. Can I just fly?
c07205
Delwath: Does it take a bonus action to blow the raven's whistle?
c07206
Delwath: I thought we just walked in the room.
c07207
DM: Oh, no, no, no. You...
c07208
DM: Well, not in this...
c07209
Unknown: Okay.
c07210
DM: Some rooms have gravity.
c07211
Unknown: Ah.
c07212
DM: Not every room has gravity.
c07213
DM: This one is pulling you down.
c07214
DM: Um,
c07215
DM: no, n- n- only enclosed spaces can have gravity.
c07216
Kenzo: Do we not want to be on the ground so that he can shoot fire at everybody?
c07217
Kenzo: 'Cause we're not, like, immune to his fire, his breath weapon, right?
c07218
DM: That's an issue.
c07219
Delwath: Oh, that's true.
c07220
Unknown: But I can do it.
c07221
Unknown: So we want to be here 'cause we're-
c07222
DM: But it's not an action at all to blow the raven's whistle.
c07223
DM: You just have to blow it.
c07224
Unknown: Right.
c07225
DM: It's just if you fail a-
c07226
Kenzo: We, we wanna be here. We want to be up here.
c07227
Delwath: Can't save. I fail. [laughs]
c07228
Seeker: The 60-foot cone thing means I can aim it-
c07229
Unknown: Wait, can we just land on the dragon's back?
c07230
Delwath: ... and just put it on like the way down.
c07231
Unknown: Yeah.
c07232
Unknown: There you go.
c07233
Seeker: There you go.
c07234
DM: Uh-
c07235
Delwath: Oh, but you won't be able to attack 'cause you don't have Lae'zel's Claw.
c07236
Kenzo: Yeah, but that's fine. Then what I'll do is I'm gonna attack these two guys-
c07237
Unknown: Yeah
c07238
Kenzo: ... and then grab you-
c07239
Unknown: Yeah
c07240
Unknown: ... drop down the way on the back.
c07241
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c07242
Wellby: Let's do it.
c07243
Unknown: Okay. So make a-
c07244
DM: Um, make acrobatics checks DC 12 to land on the back.
c07245
Delwath: Can Kenzo just carry me?
c07246
Kenzo: No, I have to... Yeah.
c07247
DM: Oh, yeah. Kenzo's carrying you with Step of the Wind.
c07248
Unknown: I'm light as a feather.
c07249
DM: So...
c07250
Kenzo: All right. Perfect.
c07251
DM: Right.
c07252
Delwath: Oh, I rolled a 20. [laughs]
c07253
DM: Okay. [laughs]
c07254
Unknown: All right. Well, let me first-
c07255
Delwath: Can I use that for my save?
c07256
DM: No.
c07257
Kenzo: So I'm gonna kill these guys.
c07258
DM: Okay.
c07259
Kenzo: Uh, 'cause I, 'cause I, 'cause I get two staff attacks.
c07260
Unknown: Yes.
c07261
DM: You get two staff attacks. Yeah.
c07262
Unknown: Just hit.
c07263
Kenzo: With advantage or just regular?
c07264
DM: Just regular.
c07265
Unknown: Okay.
c07266
Kenzo: That's fine. 21.
c07267
DM: That hits.
c07268
Wellby: It's only on the first person that I hit in the first round.
c07269
Unknown: Uh...
c07270
DM: You don't need it.
c07271
Unknown: Wow.
c07272
Unknown: Okay.
c07273
DM: Oh, wait, no. Do you roll...
c07274
DM: Yeah, 12 kills one.
c07275
Unknown: Okay.
c07276
DM: They're minions, so...
c07277
Unknown: Yeah, that killed that attack.
c07278
DM: Yeah, it kills the other.
c07279
Unknown: Okay.
c07280
DM: Okay. So you kill the two minions.
c07281
Unknown: Killed, killed two minions.
c07282
DM: You grab Delweth-
c07283
Unknown: Grab Delweth
c07284
DM: ... and you drop down onto the-
c07285
Kenzo: And I land on, on, uh-
c07286
DM: On the back of the dragon
c07287
Delwath: And we're, like, from the back of the dragon, we're within 20 feet of the queen, right?
c07288
DM: Y- uh, yeah, 'cause the room is only 30 feet tall.
c07289
Seeker: So the, the dragon is hovering?
c07290
Unknown: Yes.
c07291
Delwath: Yeah, dragons can hover.
c07292
Unknown: Inside. [laughs]
c07293
Delwath: Okay, so you can take-
c07294
DM: The dragon's like [whooshing] hovering in, taking up almost...
c07295
DM: With your wings out, taking up almost the entire-
c07296
Unknown: This is huge. Yeah
c07297
DM: ... space of the room.
c07298
Delwath: So you can take a legendary action.
c07299
DM: So now you can take actions.
c07300
Unknown: And whoosh. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
c07301
Unknown: Hell yeah, legendary action.
c07302
Delwath: Banish the thing inside you.
c07303
Unknown: Yes.
c07304
c07305
Seeker: This is why you just-
c07306
Unknown: Yes
c07307
Seeker: ... what should I do? Think about what Mike just said and then do that thing.
c07308
Unknown: That's the way to play D&D.
c07309
DM: Okay. So you're trying to banish the thing inside you.
c07310
Unknown: Wow.
c07311
Unknown: Yes.
c07312
Unknown: Yes. I did nothing but that and that was it.
c07313
Kenzo: If only we could all do that for ourselves.
c07314
Unknown: [laughs]
c07315
DM: [laughs]
c07316
Delwath: Banish the demon inside.
c07317
Unknown: [laughs]
c07318
DM: I'm g- technically it has-
c07319
Wellby: Keep trying, buddy. [laughs]
c07320
Seeker: DC 21.
c07321
DM: Yeah. It has total cover against attacks and effects outside the target.
c07322
DM: But this is not an outside the target attack, it's coming from the target itself.
c07323
Delwath: [laughs] Always aiming for me.
c07324
DM: Uh, it fails. It is banished.
c07325
Unknown: Woo-hoo.
c07326
Unknown: Oh, wow. Nice.
c07327
Delwath: But wait, it takes damage too.
c07328
Delwath: It'll come back next turn but not inside you
c07329
DM: Yeah.
c07330
Seeker: Oh yeah, it takes, um, 3d6 force damage-
c07331
DM: Okay. Roll that
c07332
Seeker: ... and is incapacitated and transported to a harmless dimension.
c07333
Delwath: And then you put it back...
c07334
Delwath: Uh, it comes back at the start of-
c07335
DM: So the nearest unoccupied space
c07336
Delwath: No, it's where you want it
c07337
DM: Oh, where you want it?
c07338
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c07339
DM: That's even better. How much damage?
c07340
Unknown: Nine. [sighs] Shit.
c07341
Delwath: Wait, do I save for the thing at the beginning or end of my turn?
c07342
DM: End of your turn.
c07343
Seeker: Oh, I see. I can
c07344
DM: So it guarantees you have at least one turn under its effect.
c07345
Kenzo: Okay. Oh, so you just like generic action vanish.
c07346
Unknown: Okay.
c07347
Seeker: Sure did.
c07348
Unknown: Yeah. That was
c07349
DM: So now Delwath's up.
c07350
Unknown: Okay. I will attack the queen.
c07351
Unknown: Legendary action to get-
c07352
DM: Okay
c07353
Unknown: ... three.
c07354
Delwath: You can't bonus action to-
c07355
Kenzo: So you can legendary action after Delwath to, uh, do your breath weapon.
c07356
Unknown: No, he can't breath weapon.
c07357
Unknown: Uh, I mean it's a second pounce.
c07358
Unknown: Oh, you can't?
c07359
Unknown: It's the only other one you have.
c07360
Delwath: Okay. Wait, bad advantage.
c07361
Seeker: It's the only other one you rend attack.
c07362
DM: Yes, you have advantage against the queen.
c07363
Delwath: Yes. Uh, 26.
c07364
DM: That hits.
c07365
Unknown: Uh,
c07366
Unknown: 18.
c07367
DM: That misses.
c07368
Unknown: Oh, wait, wait, hold on.
c07369
Unknown: 19.
c07370
DM: That misses.
c07371
Delwath: Uh, okay. And then, yeah, that hits down to all the...
c07372
DM: So two of your attacks hit
c07373
DM: as you-
c07374
Unknown: Um, I'm gonna smite another time
c07375
DM: ... reach through.
c07376
Delwath: I'll use up my...
c07377
Delwath: I don't know. I still have one more.
c07378
Delwath: No, that'll use up my... But I may as well, right?
c07379
Unknown: Like it's not worth-
c07380
Unknown: If only we
c07381
Unknown: ... it's not worth saving.
c07382
Unknown: What are you gonna save it for?
c07383
Unknown: Well, to try and get a crit but it's not worth it.
c07384
DM: If only what?
c07385
Unknown: We'll need Seeker 6 for 8.
c07386
Delwath: I know, right? [laughs]
c07387
Unknown: [laughs] Uh, wait.
c07388
Kenzo: You know, actually in this moment I kind of miss Seeker 5.
c07389
Unknown: Seeker 5, you know, is...
c07390
Seeker: You know, Seekers 2 through 5 like I really honestly have almost no memory of.
c07391
Unknown: 7
c07392
DM: Seeker 5 was in the...
c07393
DM: Seeker 5 was, was in the E- Empress of Chaos fight.
c07394
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c07395
Delwath: 89 damage.
c07396
Seeker: Then Seeker 2-
c07397
DM: 89 damage?
c07398
Delwath: I smited.
c07399
DM: Oh, okay.
c07400
Unknown: Wow.
c07401
Unknown: How much damage?
c07402
DM: 89.
c07403
Unknown: Wow.
c07404
Delwath: 14 D8, two hits plus a smite.
c07405
DM: So Delwath's two strikes stagger her back slightly.
c07406
Delwath: And I'm... My sword is appearing on the-
c07407
DM: Right
c07408
Delwath: ... other side of the dragon.
c07409
DM: Make a, make-
c07410
Seeker: How is that a thing? That's insane
c07411
DM: ... make a save.
c07412
Unknown: Oh, right.
c07413
Delwath: Uh, 23.
c07414
DM: That succeeds. No longer dazed.
c07415
Delwath: I don't even have to u... Well, actually I do.
c07416
Delwath: Need to remember to roll D4 'cause I have blast, like at a D4 on all-
c07417
Unknown: Uh, yeah
c07418
Unknown: ... for my potion.
c07419
Unknown: Nice
c07420
DM: Does that the end of your turn?
c07421
Unknown: Yeah.
c07422
DM: Legendary action.
c07423
Seeker: I can legendary action pounce.
c07424
Seeker: The dragon moves up to half its speed and makes one rend attack, uh, which is a plus 14 [laughs]
c07425
Wellby: So, uh, with advantage
c07426
Seeker: ... hit by bowl. Why is it with advantage?
c07427
Unknown: 'Cause it's not See, it's not...
c07428
Unknown: It's not
c07429
DM: That's just before Wellby's turn.
c07430
Delwath: Just before Wellby's turn.
c07431
Unknown: One roll 2d20.
c07432
Seeker: And that's the, um, on the queen-
c07433
DM: Yeah
c07434
Seeker: ... here?
c07435
DM: Yeah.
c07436
Unknown: So I'm just
c07437
Seeker: striking out with my claw straight down.
c07438
Unknown: 28.
c07439
Unknown: That's-
c07440
DM: 28 hits.
c07441
Seeker: 28 hits. That's, uh, 2d8 plus 8 slashing damage plus 1d8 fire damage.
c07442
Unknown: So 3d8.
c07443
DM: Uh, don't roll the fire damage.
c07444
DM: She is immune to fire.
c07445
Unknown: Ah.
c07446
Unknown: All right.
c07447
Delwath: So is your breath weapon fire?
c07448
Unknown: No, this is a...
c07449
DM: I know, but your breath weapon's fire, right?
c07450
Wellby: There's also a weakening breath though.
c07451
Unknown: Oh, crap.
c07452
Kenzo: Well, it does a little help pretty much
c07453
Seeker: So 2d8 plus 8-
c07454
Unknown: Yeah
c07455
Seeker: ... is what I get here, and that's a total of-
c07456
DM: 15
c07457
Unknown: ... 15.
c07458
Unknown: 15.
c07459
DM: Okay.
c07460
Seeker: So that's two legendary actions.
c07461
Delwath: Yep, you got one more. Okay, Wellby, you're up.
c07462
Wellby: Yes, I am. Uh, I'm gonna start by-
c07463
DM: Can you just move that thing that was inside Seeker like off the map until it's back?
c07464
Wellby: Uh, let's start by shooting the queen and-
c07465
DM: Okay.
c07466
Unknown: Have we told him?
c07467
DM: She's gonna have three quarters cover from you.
c07468
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah. It's still inside the thing. Okay.
c07469
Wellby: Uh, ignore that because I have sharpshooter.
c07470
DM: Right. Uh, immune to fire damage, resistant to
c07471
DM: cold, necrotic, poison, psychic...
c07472
DM: Oh, wait. Do you do force or radiant damage?
c07473
Unknown: Force.
c07474
DM: Okay.
c07475
Unknown: Limbo.
c07476
DM: Right, right.
c07477
Unknown: You specifically made-
c07478
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Radiant. Actually, this is exactly why I made it force-
c07479
Unknown: Ah, force
c07480
DM: ... because she is resistant to radiant
c07481
Delwath: But sickening radiance is radiant.
c07482
DM: Yes. So far she hasn't failed a sickening radiance.
c07483
Kenzo: She has to make another one though.
c07484
Kenzo: What, what's her, what's her, uh-
c07485
DM: It's not her turn. It's Wellby's turn
c07486
Delwath: ... save, save situation for her?
c07487
DM: Um,
c07488
DM: uh, basically what Rai said.
c07489
DM: A- all the mental saves are extremely high.
c07490
DM: Um-
c07491
Unknown: Is there any weakness?
c07492
DM: ... strength is her weakest.
c07493
Wellby: Yes.
c07494
Kenzo: What's her CR?
c07495
DM: 23.
c07496
Unknown: That's not even that high.
c07497
DM: That's why she has a whole pack of allies.
c07498
Unknown: Right.
c07499
Unknown: Uh,
c07500
Wellby: do we think she has blind sight?
c07501
Unknown: Probably.
c07502
c07503
Unknown: Probably.
c07504
Kenzo: I mean, you did trip her last turn.
c07505
Delwath: Oh, she's prone by the way.
c07506
Wellby: No, 'cause she teleported away.
c07507
Delwath: No, she's prone. My smite makes her prone.
c07508
DM: Oh, so Wellby has disadvantage on his attack.
c07509
Unknown: I don't have to make her prone. She's not prone.
c07510
Wellby: Not prone.
c07511
Delwath: It's up to me whether the smite makes her prone.
c07512
DM: Okay.
c07513
DM: [laughs]
c07514
Wellby: Uh, uh, do we want her to be prone?
c07515
Wellby: Should I try and trip her?
c07516
Delwath: Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. Was she moving?
c07517
Delwath: It doesn't matter, but technically she would've fallen prone.
c07518
Wellby: I don't know. I'm, uh, I'm gonna daze. All right, daze is-
c07519
DM: Oh, she can, she can fly.
c07520
Delwath: Right. No, no, no, no. When she was fleeing, she would've been tripped.
c07521
Delwath: She would've fallen prone from my smite 'cause I hit her with an opportunity attack, but it wouldn't actually practically-
c07522
DM: I mean, she just fell through the thing-
c07523
Unknown: Yeah
c07524
DM: ... and then she's flying, so.
c07525
Unknown: Right.
c07526
Wellby: Uh,
c07527
Wellby: 20, uh, 30.
c07528
DM: 30 hits.
c07529
Wellby: 30 hits. Okay. Um,
c07530
Wellby: this is a DC19, um,
c07531
Wellby: uh, con save for daze.
c07532
Unknown: Oh, throwing her thing back at her.
c07533
Unknown: Yeah.
c07534
Wellby: Uh-huh.
c07535
DM: Uh, that's a 23.
c07536
Unknown: 20.
c07537
Delwath: Uh, and then it'll be a long stretch of out, of...
c07538
Delwath: We have, we're like weirdly paired.
c07539
DM: Yeah, you are. That is gonna be them for a long time-
c07540
Unknown: Yeah
c07541
DM: ... with only one legendary action to break it up.
c07542
Wellby: Saving procedure's, uh, 36.
c07543
Unknown: Oh, wait.
c07544
DM: 36 damage?
c07545
Kenzo: Wait a little bit, see what happens. Yep
c07546
Kenzo: Do you save the, save one more legendary action
c07547
Delwath: I mean, all you can do is another rend.
c07548
DM: I would just-
c07549
Unknown: Yeah
c07550
DM: ... do it.
c07551
Wellby: Is anybody within five feet of the dragon?
c07552
DM: Any
c07553
DM: monsters?
c07554
Wellby: Yeah.
c07555
DM: No, they're all 10 feet.
c07556
Unknown: [clears throat]
c07557
DM: The dragon's 15 feet up, so
c07558
DM: they're all 10 feet away.
c07559
Wellby: They're all around. This guy is right next to my triceratops.
c07560
DM: Oh, yeah. Okay.
c07561
Wellby: So, uh, sneak attack, but not with advantage.
c07562
Wellby: 25.
c07563
DM: That hits.
c07564
Unknown: Triceratops is at 14.
c07565
Unknown: Second
c07566
DM: No, that's-
c07567
Kenzo: That's all of you
c07568
DM: ... this one hasn't taken any damage yet
c07569
Wellby: This guy also has blind sight, right?
c07570
DM: This one is the one that had-
c07571
Unknown: Yeah
c07572
DM: ... that you knew had blind sight from last time.
c07573
DM: The centaur you could definitely blind.
c07574
Kenzo: That's really good, 'cause you're like literally-
c07575
Unknown: You blinded the centaur
c07576
DM: You blinded the centaur, the metal centaur thing lots of times
c07577
Unknown: ... from this guy.
c07578
DM: Okay.
c07579
Unknown: Uh-
c07580
Wellby: We're partial cover
c07581
Delwath: Yeah, we probably have partial cover.
c07582
Wellby: Yeah.
c07583
DM: You guys have half cover-
c07584
Wellby: From being on the dragon's back
c07585
DM: ... from being on the dragon's back.
c07586
Wellby: Uh, 45 on the blood guy.
c07587
Unknown: This is your-
c07588
Delwath: Seeker, this is really-
c07589
DM: Okay
c07590
Delwath: ... you're coming into your own here.
c07591
Unknown: I know, yeah. This is, this is-
c07592
DM: Facing your fears.
c07593
Unknown: Yeah
c07594
Delwath: Like taking the lead in a combat situation.
c07595
Unknown: Oh, dear.
c07596
DM: [laughs]
c07597
Wellby: And then I'm gonna, I'm gonna rend this-
c07598
Kenzo: You're banishing the fear inside yourself now
c07599
Wellby: ... with my wasted action, already in action to shoot the queen.
c07600
Unknown: This is like in the journey.
c07601
Wellby: Uh,
c07602
Wellby: what are the options for heroes? Like as soon as the next-
c07603
Unknown: These situations are like too complicated
c07604
Wellby: ... as soon as the triceratops attacks
c07605
DM: Okay. There you go
c07606
Delwath: ... triceratops attacks [laughs].
c07607
Seeker: That's brilliant. Like I try to make the images of something where it's like, oh, there's this whole thing happening
c07608
Unknown: Okay. So triceratops is up?
c07609
DM: Yep.
c07610
Wellby: Oh, shit. I'll also...
c07611
Wellby: Uh, wait.
c07612
DM: Triceratops needs to make a save for-
c07613
Unknown: Can you use your bonus action?
c07614
Wellby: Triceratops needs to save against sickening radiance?
c07615
DM: Yep.
c07616
DM: Yeah.
c07617
Wellby: Uh, then fails it.
c07618
DM: Triceratops is gonna be killed by the sickening radiance.
c07619
Unknown: Now I'm sickened.
c07620
Wellby: Uh, whiteboard pen.
c07621
Wellby: Oh my God, actually worked. Oh my God.
c07622
Wellby: How much damage?
c07623
Unknown: That didn't...
c07624
Seeker: I was set up right.
c07625
Unknown: 18 in the world already.
c07626
Unknown: We-
c07627
DM: It's now at minus four
c07628
Unknown: ... that's nuts.
c07629
DM: Yeah, minus four to all attacks
c07630
Wellby: ... attacks.
c07631
DM: Yeah.
c07632
Unknown: Yeah. So right in the
c07633
DM: Yeah. Exhaustion's... I mean-
c07634
DM: It's really strong against things that aren't immune to exhaustion
c07635
Delwath: ... sickening radiance totally kill, 'cause you get six level exhaustion, you die-
c07636
DM: Right
c07637
DM: ... instantly.
c07638
Wellby: All right. Two gore attacks.
c07639
Wellby: Each of these are gonna be plus five.
c07640
Wellby: Once you net at the minus, both of those miss wildly.
c07641
DM: But Wellby gets his attack.
c07642
DM: That's the whole point.
c07643
Wellby: Yeah.
c07644
DM: Right. Now Wellby gets-
c07645
Delwath: Triceratops is honestly just guiding your arrow.
c07646
Wellby: Shit, can that bat be, uh...
c07647
Wellby: Can that bat be an ally within five feet?
c07648
DM: No, it doesn't... It's not threatening.
c07649
DM: It's weak. It's too weak.
c07650
DM: It doesn't threaten anybody.
c07651
Wellby: Right.
c07652
DM: The triceratops though-
c07653
DM: Wait, wait, wait. Hold on, hold on, hold on.
c07654
Delwath: The dragon's rend,
c07655
Delwath: you can move half your move.
c07656
Unknown: Why is the dragon-
c07657
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah. So the dragon can-
c07658
Unknown: ... just half
c07659
DM: ... the dragon can move half your move when you rend.
c07660
DM: So you can drop down so you're within five feet of anybody.
c07661
Unknown: Yeah.
c07662
Wellby: All right. It doesn't matter at this point.
c07663
Wellby: Okay. So I'm attacking again the queen with advantage.
c07664
Wellby: It's gonna be the same thing again, uh, with the, uh, that is a DC19 con save for gaze.
c07665
DM: 25.
c07666
Wellby: Assuming I hit with a 23.
c07667
DM: That hits.
c07668
Wellby: Uh, she passed, so that's 8d6.
c07669
Wellby: So that is eight, 10,
c07670
Wellby: uh,
c07671
Wellby: uh, 23, uh, 31.
c07672
Delwath: How's she doing?
c07673
Delwath: Does she look hurt yet?
c07674
DM: Sorry, how much was that?
c07675
Wellby: 31.
c07676
DM: She's bloodied.
c07677
Wellby: All
c07678
Wellby: right.
c07679
DM: Uh-
c07680
Delwath: Well, you wanna do your last now you're saving your rend
c07681
Wellby: Uh, I'm gonna move out of the
c07682
Wellby: line of fire.
c07683
DM: Okay.
c07684
Wellby: Through the door.
c07685
Kenzo: Let's, let's, uh, make sure we grab an item or for something for her 'cause we wanna show that to the mirror.
c07686
Kenzo: I wanna see the fucking origins of the, the, uh, the chaos-
c07687
Wellby: Yeah
c07688
Kenzo: ... that emanate.
c07689
Wellby: Definitely.
c07690
Unknown: Yeah.
c07691
DM: Uh, okay. That ends...
c07692
DM: Okay.
c07693
Wellby: Errors at the mirror. Like what if they do do a test case of objects from before time?
c07694
Seeker: [laughs] Right. The mirror just shit.
c07695
Delwath: It might just like get stuck in a loop of like-
c07696
DM: Um-
c07697
Delwath: Maybe it'll just show us-
c07698
DM: ... uh
c07699
Delwath: ... random images from the future
c07700
Seeker: Although, have we tried to show it itself?
c07701
Delwath: No. But how would you do that?
c07702
Wellby: It dumps all the images it's ever shown anyone.
c07703
DM: Delwath, make a constitution saving throw.
c07704
Unknown: I don't like making saving throws.
c07705
Delwath: Uh, 14 plus t- two.
c07706
Unknown: 16.
c07707
DM: Um,
c07708
DM: you can choose...
c07709
DM: Your blood boils.
c07710
Unknown: Maybe I don't want this to happen.
c07711
Delwath: [laughs] I have, I have, I can still use two different abilities-
c07712
DM: Yep
c07713
Delwath: ... to increase... Okay.
c07714
DM: Go ahead and use them.
c07715
Delwath: I'm not... I don't like your blood boils.
c07716
Unknown: [laughs]
c07717
Unknown: Yeah, that's... That's
c07718
Delwath: I'm gonna trade that for a bardic inspiration.
c07719
Unknown: Uh, 20.
c07720
DM: That succeeds.
c07721
Unknown: Hm.
c07722
DM: Your blood does not boil.
c07723
Kenzo: Thank goodness.
c07724
DM: Um-
c07725
DM: Now I'm done with my bardic though.
c07726
DM: And then-
c07727
Kenzo: I didn't use my bardic 'cause I got...
c07728
Kenzo: I was able to turn myself into ash with that.
c07729
Unknown: Oh, nice.
c07730
Unknown: ... rolled 26.
c07731
Unknown: Yeah.
c07732
DM: Uh-
c07733
Unknown: Bardic
c07734
DM: ... I guess we're gonna attack the dragon.
c07735
DM: It's kind of in the way.
c07736
DM: Um-
c07737
Unknown: Good job, Seeker.
c07738
Unknown: Come in.
c07739
Wellby: Do you have one more legendary?
c07740
Unknown: I do.
c07741
DM: 30. That hits, right?
c07742
Unknown: Yeah. What's your AC?
c07743
DM: It's like 20.
c07744
DM: Uh, you take a total of...
c07745
DM: Wait.
c07746
Delwath: 19. Oh, it's only 19. That's not so good, but that's okay.
c07747
Unknown: You have 10 hit points.
c07748
DM: You take
c07749
DM: 39, uh,
c07750
DM: 13 points of slashing damage and 26 points of necrotic damage, so 39 total, so you have to make a concentration check.
c07751
Unknown: Oh, shit.
c07752
Unknown: What?
c07753
DM: It's concentration.
c07754
Kenzo: For the dragon.
c07755
Unknown: This is a spell.
c07756
DM: The dragon is a spell. It is concentration.
c07757
Seeker: This whole thing is gonna unfold in like a second
c07758
DM: But you have your dragon's con modifier.
c07759
Unknown: Oh, so that's plus seven
c07760
DM: And you have legendary resistances if you fail.
c07761
Delwath: Don't you have advantage on-
c07762
Seeker: Oh, right. Okay
c07763
Seeker: Con 25
c07764
Unknown: So plus seven
c07765
Unknown: So that's the-
c07766
Wellby: Plus seven save.
c07767
Seeker: Oh my God. Okay, that's good.
c07768
Delwath: But do you have, do you have something that gives you advantage on con checks to maintain-
c07769
DM: Uh, does y- do you keep all of your class abil- Like-
c07770
Unknown: I don't know
c07771
DM: ... let me just look at the...
c07772
Unknown: Well, just roll one to start-
c07773
DM: Yeah
c07774
Unknown: ... and see.
c07775
Unknown: So 17.
c07776
Unknown: It might fail save.
c07777
Wellby: Use your, use your-
c07778
DM: No, you, you don't
c07779
Wellby: ... heroic thing
c07780
Delwath: You don't keep any of your class-
c07781
DM: You don't keep any of your class abilities except spell casting.
c07782
Unknown: Okay.
c07783
Seeker: So I rolled a two, plus seven is nine.
c07784
DM: Yeah.
c07785
Unknown: I have a-
c07786
Wellby: Do you still have heroic?
c07787
Seeker: I do
c07788
Delwath: But you could just use a legendary resistance.
c07789
DM: You need to, you need to beat, uh, half of 39, so you need to beat, uh-
c07790
Unknown: Beat a 19
c07791
DM: ... 19.
c07792
Wellby: So 12 on the die.
c07793
Delwath: Wait, did you roll for sickening radiance?
c07794
DM: For the force of blood, yeah.
c07795
Unknown: Okay.
c07796
DM: It's still its turn. [laughs]
c07797
Unknown: So-
c07798
Unknown: It made it
c07799
DM: ... it made it.
c07800
Unknown: I-
c07801
DM: It rolled a 25 or something.
c07802
Delwath: You should use a legendary resistance.
c07803
Unknown: Yeah. Why not?
c07804
Unknown: How many do you have?
c07805
Unknown: Three.
c07806
Kenzo: Every, every time he gets, takes any damage, he has to do a concentration check?
c07807
DM: Yeah, but not all of them are gonna be that much damage.
c07808
Unknown: Yeah.
c07809
DM: That was its strongest attack.
c07810
Kenzo: But I mean, how much damage does it-
c07811
DM: That, that's a one
c07812
Seeker: ... any damage.
c07813
DM: The third spear is a 29, so that hits.
c07814
DM: That does 13 points of piercing damage, so that's only a DC 10.
c07815
Kenzo: Yeah. Oh, the DC is, is-
c07816
Unknown: Uh-
c07817
DM: The DC is half the damage or a 10, whichever is higher
c07818
Unknown: ... exactly. Okay
c07819
DM: So it has one strong attack and two weaker attacks.
c07820
Kenzo: So now you do this one plus seven.
c07821
Unknown: Okay.
c07822
DM: Oh.
c07823
Unknown: 17, 13. Great.
c07824
DM: Yeah. So that one's fine.
c07825
Kenzo: You still have two more legendary resistances.
c07826
DM: Yes.
c07827
Unknown: All right.
c07828
DM: Um, and it heals slightly from that last attack.
c07829
Unknown: Oh my God,
c07830
Unknown: this fucking battle.
c07831
DM: And then that ends it.
c07832
DM: The queen is up.
c07833
DM: Sickening is-
c07834
Wellby: Wait, wait, wait. The queen is up.
c07835
Wellby: Do you want to use another legendary action-
c07836
Seeker: Oh, thank you
c07837
Wellby: ... before the queen's up?
c07838
Unknown: Yes.
c07839
DM: Yes, you want to use it before the queen?
c07840
DM: Go ahead.
c07841
Seeker: So I do my rend attack.
c07842
Seeker: That's a 20, 8 plus 14-
c07843
Unknown: 22
c07844
Unknown: ... is 22.
c07845
DM: 22 hits.
c07846
Seeker: And then it's, um-
c07847
Unknown: 2d8 plus
c07848
Seeker: ... so 2d8 plus 8.
c07849
Seeker: Yeah, no fire damage
c07850
Unknown: for these.
c07851
DM: Uh, there's one.
c07852
Unknown: Oh.
c07853
Wellby: Oh, here's, here's, here's.
c07854
Seeker: So that's 13-
c07855
Unknown: 21
c07856
Seeker: ... plus 8 is 21.
c07857
DM: Uh, okay.
c07858
Wellby: It's nice and solid.
c07859
DM: Um-
c07860
Unknown: It's gonna live. It's gonna live. It's gonna live.
c07861
DM: Yeah.
c07862
Unknown: Yeah.
c07863
DM: I mean, she was past...
c07864
DM: The sneak attack put her past bloodied.
c07865
DM: Uh, that ends your, [laughs] not your turn, your legendary.
c07866
DM: Now she gets to go.
c07867
Unknown: Yeah.
c07868
DM: Um-
c07869
Unknown: Save
c07870
DM: ... she failed.
c07871
DM: She's gonna burn one of her legendary resistances.
c07872
Unknown: Oh, okay.
c07873
DM: Um, although it's just chip damage, but still.
c07874
DM: And then, oh, does her ash thing recharge?
c07875
DM: No.
c07876
DM: Um,
c07877
DM: she is going to teleport-
c07878
Kenzo: Oh, shit
c07879
DM: ... onto the back of the dragon.
c07880
Unknown: Oh, shit.
c07881
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c07882
Wellby: Hey, hey, join us here.
c07883
Unknown: Hey, everybody.
c07884
DM: And then attack Delwath.
c07885
DM: She wants this sickening radiance to end.
c07886
Unknown: Okay.
c07887
DM: Uh, that's going to be three attacks.
c07888
DM: Um, that's a one.
c07889
DM: That one doesn't hit.
c07890
Seeker: This three layer thing works great, actually.
c07891
DM: That's a 16.
c07892
Unknown: Yeah.
c07893
DM: That doesn't hit, and then that's a twen- a 32.
c07894
Unknown: That hits.
c07895
DM: Um, and that's gonna do 24 plus 22, 46 reduced-
c07896
Unknown: By half
c07897
DM: ... by half, so 23.
c07898
Unknown: So 23.
c07899
Unknown: Dead.
c07900
DM: Oh, and try, the triceratops has to make a dex saving throw.
c07901
Wellby: Oh, yeah. Strong suit for triceratops.
c07902
Wellby: Uh, minus one.
c07903
Wellby: Uh, that's not, no, it truly fails.
c07904
Delwath: Oh, wait. Oops, I healed instead of...
c07905
DM: Uh, it takes nine points of fire damage.
c07906
Wellby: Awesome.
c07907
Delwath: Oops. It said it was 24?
c07908
DM: 24, yeah.
c07909
Delwath: I accidentally healed to 24 instead.
c07910
DM: Oh.
c07911
Delwath: But I think I, I think my hit points are back to normal.
c07912
DM: Okay.
c07913
Delwath: It's possible I'm a little bit off, but.
c07914
DM: Uh,
c07915
DM: that, uh, ends her turn.
c07916
DM: Um,
c07917
DM: the, uh,
c07918
DM: the essence of mist is still banished.
c07919
DM: The-
c07920
Delwath: Dragon has huge balls
c07921
DM: ... icebergs are dead, dead.
c07922
DM: Um, this centaur thing is going to send three more-
c07923
Unknown: Save
c07924
DM: ... yep.
c07925
DM: Uh, that one fails.
c07926
Kenzo: So try to get rid of the legendary resistance didn't work of the, uh, the sickening radiance?
c07927
DM: It's attacking Delwath to try and break concentration on sickening radiance.
c07928
Delwath: But I made my concentration check.
c07929
DM: Yeah.
c07930
Delwath: Thir- whoa, that was a good roll.
c07931
Unknown: 30 damage.
c07932
DM: Uh, this one has not taken any damage yet, so it takes 30 damage.
c07933
DM: Um,
c07934
DM: uh,
c07935
DM: and then it is going to, um, shoot some iron spikes into the dragon.
c07936
Unknown: Oh, cool.
c07937
DM: Um, and that's going to be three attacks.
c07938
Kenzo: Oh, 191 temporary hit points.
c07939
Unknown: That's pretty cool.
c07940
DM: Um, that's a miss.
c07941
DM: Uh, does an 18 hit?
c07942
Delwath: 19 AC.
c07943
DM: So only one of those three hits.
c07944
Unknown: Great.
c07945
DM: And you take 14 points of piercing damage, so another concentration check.
c07946
Delwath: You just gotta roll a three better.
c07947
Unknown: [die rolling]
c07948
DM: And then-
c07949
Wellby: [laughs]
c07950
Delwath: Three. Three's better than three or better.
c07951
DM: Yep.
c07952
DM: Uh-
c07953
Wellby: [laughs]
c07954
Unknown: [laughs] Sneaking by.
c07955
DM: And then-
c07956
Delwath: You can hold onto this hope even though it hurts a little bit
c07957
DM: ... before, before Seeker's turn, she's gonna use her next, um, villain action.
c07958
Unknown: Oh.
c07959
Delwath: Nice. She's making new minions, but the sickening radiance is still here.
c07960
DM: And Wellby-
c07961
Unknown: Oh, man
c07962
Wellby: No. No, Wellby doesn't
c07963
Delwath: You, you can move when something appears near you, right?
c07964
Unknown: You can
c07965
Unknown: Run down into the Sicking Radiance.
c07966
Unknown: Uh...
c07967
Unknown: Uh-oh.
c07968
Unknown: Wait, what about the ladder?
c07969
Delwath: It's still up there, I guess.
c07970
Kenzo: Yeah. It's being a rogue.
c07971
Unknown: [clears throat]
c07972
Unknown: Oh, man.
c07973
Unknown: What is that? How many is that?
c07974
Delwath: One, two, three, eight. I need two more.
c07975
DM: A bunch of minions of smoke and cloud begin to coalesce out of the
c07976
DM: mist shooting up into the, this room, and then are going to move
c07977
DM: and attack Wellby.
c07978
Unknown: Uh-
c07979
Unknown: They probably miss though.
c07980
Unknown: No, they'll probably take the damage.
c07981
Unknown: Yeah.
c07982
Kenzo: What's your AC?
c07983
Unknown: Uh, uh-
c07984
Unknown: 20
c07985
Unknown: ... one.
c07986
Unknown: Actually these-
c07987
Unknown: No, it's 18 right now
c07988
Kenzo: ... plus two with the haste.
c07989
Unknown: These-
c07990
Unknown: Yeah. I'm gonna
c07991
DM: ... these four will attack.
c07992
DM: So six are gonna attack Wellby, four are gonna attack the ladder.
c07993
Wellby: I'm at 59 hit points right now, it's kind of-
c07994
Delwath: Oh, that's not great
c07995
Unknown: ... very poorly.
c07996
Unknown: So that's-
c07997
Delwath: Wait, wait, wait. How do you only have 59 hit points?
c07998
Wellby: I got hit up by a whole bunch of things at the start of this battle.
c07999
Unknown: That's a
c08000
DM: 20... That's a 30-something to hit.
c08001
Kenzo: This is the battle right now. Like, like literally they're...
c08002
Kenzo: Like I've taken zero damage.
c08003
Unknown: Six. [laughs]
c08004
Kenzo: You've taken zero damage too, right?
c08005
Delwath: No, I've taken 50 points of damage.
c08006
Unknown: I've taken zero damage.
c08007
Delwath: But I have invulnera- I have your thing.
c08008
Unknown: Yeah.
c08009
Delwath: I took a potion of half damage.
c08010
Unknown: Yeah. It's great.
c08011
Delwath: I'm sitting here like, 40, eh, it's only 20.
c08012
Unknown: I don't mind.
c08013
Unknown: It's the best.
c08014
Unknown: It's really the best.
c08015
Kenzo: I've, I've been... I was the fucking lead guy in the door and have taken zero damage the entire fight.
c08016
Unknown: Uh, you take a-
c08017
Unknown: It's 'cause there's a giant [laughs]
c08018
DM: ... 48 points of damage
c08019
Unknown: Oh, right. [laughs]
c08020
Unknown: 48 points of damage I can take.
c08021
Unknown: And then the ladder-
c08022
Delwath: You guys have healing potions, right?
c08023
DM: The ladder gets hit also for-
c08024
Seeker: But you've got greater... You got the superior cure
c08025
Unknown: ... 32 points of damage.
c08026
Unknown: We all do.
c08027
Wellby: No, I took, uh, haste instead.
c08028
DM: He took haste, so he just has greater.
c08029
DM: Um, and that ends the new minions turn.
c08030
Wellby: Hold, hold up though. The minions turn ends, I move without provoking opportunity attack, and I come down, I don't know, on the dragon also, like on the tail.
c08031
Unknown: Everybody hop on.
c08032
Seeker: Everybody get on. Flap, flap, flap.
c08033
Unknown: Okay.
c08034
Unknown: Flap, flap.
c08035
Delwath: I mean, that's the goal, 'cause if they come down after you, they'll hit the Sicking Radiance.
c08036
Unknown: So Seeker's up. Dragon,
c08037
DM: uh, legendary actions refresh.
c08038
Unknown: You still have two legendary resistance.
c08039
Delwath: Roll a D6.
c08040
Unknown: Roll a D6 to see if you get your-
c08041
Delwath: Five or six, you get your breath back.
c08042
Unknown: No, no, no, he hasn't used his breath at all.
c08043
Unknown: He doesn't need breath back.
c08044
DM: That's what he's doing right now.
c08045
Delwath: So... Oh wait, you have not had a turn yet as the dragon?
c08046
Unknown: I have not had a single turn-
c08047
Unknown: Next
c08048
Unknown: ... as the dragon.
c08049
Unknown: Whoa.
c08050
Seeker: This is round two of the combat.
c08051
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah.
c08052
Unknown: Yeah.
c08053
Unknown: This is, this, this-
c08054
Unknown: So-
c08055
Kenzo: ... this combat is like the fucking longest combat of all time
c08056
DM: ... you've done 273 points of damage in two rounds.
c08057
Unknown: So-
c08058
Unknown: Just to the boss
c08059
Seeker: ... I could fire breath and do whatever it is.
c08060
Delwath: You can't fire breath the b- Yeah, I would fire breath those guys maybe.
c08061
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
c08062
Unknown: Sure.
c08063
Unknown: That's, uh-
c08064
Unknown: Well, the boss is immune to fire anyway-
c08065
Unknown: Right
c08066
Unknown: ... so it doesn't really matter.
c08067
Seeker: Yeah, that's 12 D10 on each of these guys.
c08068
Seeker: Or I could chain lightning the queen, which is like 8 D- 10 D8 or something.
c08069
Seeker: And then I could also-
c08070
Delwath: Wait, you could get all of them with chain lightning, couldn't you?
c08071
Kenzo: I could get all three.
c08072
Wellby: 'Cause one, two, three.
c08073
Delwath: That's probably better.
c08074
Wellby: 'Cause you're doing damage to the boss too.
c08075
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah, do damage to the boss.
c08076
Wellby: Those two, we're relatively confident about those two.
c08077
Kenzo: Yeah. The boss is, uh, already, uh, quite bloodied.
c08078
Kenzo: I think we can kill the boss-
c08079
Unknown: All right
c08080
Kenzo: ... not, not too much farther along from here.
c08081
Unknown: Nice.
c08082
Delwath: Well, I'm out of smites though, so...
c08083
Unknown: Where is Cha-
c08084
DM: But Kenza's only just starting to get up.
c08085
Unknown: Kenza's only just got-
c08086
Unknown: Kenza.
c08087
Unknown: Kenza didn't even attack last turn really.
c08088
Unknown: That's sixth level.
c08089
Kenzo: Killed two minions.
c08090
Seeker: Dex save.
c08091
Kenzo: Got turned into ash, killed two minions.
c08092
Unknown: 58.
c08093
Kenzo: Not a lot of my CV for this, uh, this, this, this, this battle yet.
c08094
Seeker: I cast chain lightning-
c08095
Unknown: Has-
c08096
Seeker: ... I should be able to hit all three
c08097
DM: ... the only one that fails is the center.
c08098
Unknown: All right, so-
c08099
Unknown: The other two pass.
c08100
Unknown: Just-
c08101
Unknown: Which I need
c08102
Delwath: ... just use a-
c08103
Delwath: 10 D8, just roll it on your computer
c08104
Unknown: ... just roll it on your computer. Do you know how to do that?
c08105
Seeker: How do I do that?
c08106
Delwath: You click the little die in the-
c08107
Unknown: Oh
c08108
Unknown: ... corner.
c08109
Unknown: Right there.
c08110
Unknown: Oh, uh...
c08111
Unknown: Nice, 50.
c08112
Delwath: Okay. Or do that.
c08113
Unknown: Yeah, 50.
c08114
Unknown: Oh, okay.
c08115
DM: 50. So that's 25 to the boss,
c08116
DM: uh, 25 to the blood thing,
c08117
Unknown: and 50
c08118
Unknown: to the iron thing.
c08119
DM: So lightning crackles through, coming out of the dragon through the chamber.
c08120
DM: That's your action, so you can move.
c08121
Unknown: Uh, this guy comes back.
c08122
Unknown: That one comes back. Where do you want to put it?
c08123
Seeker: Oh, right. Where do I want to put it?
c08124
Kenzo: Probably on the ground, right? Not like-
c08125
Seeker: Yeah, like
c08126
Seeker: down here so I can-
c08127
Kenzo: Sure
c08128
Seeker: ... put it in the fire cone.
c08129
Unknown: Okay.
c08130
Unknown: If I-
c08131
Unknown: So Kenza-
c08132
Kenzo: ... use my legendary action, a fire, a breath weapon?
c08133
DM: No, you can't breath weapon, it's legendary.
c08134
Unknown: Then banish and pounce.
c08135
Unknown: Banish and pounce on your turn.
c08136
Delwath: But you can banish again next turn.
c08137
Unknown: Yeah.
c08138
Unknown: Right.
c08139
Delwath: As soon as somebody, as soon as somebody acts, you can banish.
c08140
DM: Kenza's about to act, so you can just banish it again or banish something else.
c08141
Kenzo: Banish this guy.
c08142
Unknown: Yeah? Okay.
c08143
Kenzo: Well, we don't know. N- this, I, I think banish...
c08144
Kenzo: This, this thing's weird.
c08145
Delwath: This guy's CR 19.
c08146
Unknown: Huh?
c08147
Delwath: This one's nasty.
c08148
Unknown: Yeah.
c08149
Delwath: That blood boils con save is not something-
c08150
Unknown: Yeah
c08151
Unknown: ... I think we wanna fail.
c08152
Unknown: It's true.
c08153
Kenzo: Yeah, that's true.
c08154
Unknown: Yeah.
c08155
Kenzo: Okay. All right.
c08156
Delwath: It's been throwing this con save thing-
c08157
Unknown: I know, I know
c08158
Delwath: ... every turn. We keep making it, but Tim was like, "You can choose to have your blood boil or something."
c08159
Delwath: And it didn't sound like a choice we wanted to make.
c08160
Unknown: [laughs]
c08161
Kenzo: Okay, so I can either bonus action Longaow's Claw or bonus action, um-
c08162
Kenzo: No, you should just-
c08163
Kenzo: ... take the, take the potion and haste.
c08164
Unknown: I would just attack
c08165
Unknown: I would do nine-
c08166
Unknown: I would just attack
c08167
Delwath: ... bonus action, five attacks.
c08168
Unknown: Yeah.
c08169
Kenzo: [coughs] All right, yeah, 'cause I don't need to do, uh-
c08170
Delwath: 'Cause you're right next to the queen.
c08171
Delwath: Use your thing that lets you do one extra attack.
c08172
Unknown: Dump damage.
c08173
Unknown: Huh?
c08174
Delwath: Use your staff.
c08175
Unknown: Use my staff.
c08176
Delwath: Use your staff.
c08177
Unknown: So you, you do, uh-
c08178
Kenzo: Oh, hell yeah, the vital thing
c08179
Unknown: ... seven attacks.
c08180
Delwath: And then you take seven attacks on the queen.
c08181
Unknown: Do that.
c08182
Unknown: What?
c08183
Kenzo: Perfect. Yeah, I'll... Let's do that this round.
c08184
DM: And all attacks against you have disadvantage until the end of next turn.
c08185
Delwath: Wait, I made my save last time.
c08186
DM: So you're not dazed.
c08187
Kenzo: Okay. So I will use vital burst.
c08188
Kenzo: So you see Kenza like...
c08189
Kenzo: Oh, okay, wait. Is there a way for my staff to get even more lit?
c08190
Kenzo: I'll do that later. Anyways, my, my staff is like, is lit and it's like [laughs] fucking like,
c08191
Kenzo: like cr- So okay, yeah.
c08192
Kenzo: So now I get, uh- Yeah, I get four attacks.
c08193
Kenzo: So I have seven total attacks right now.
c08194
DM: Yep.
c08195
Unknown: Right?
c08196
Kenzo: Um, and I also get... See, the thing about Langos Claw though is that I get the plus D6 damage per attack.
c08197
DM: Yeah.
c08198
DM: That's good.
c08199
Kenzo: You know?
c08200
Delwath: But I do seven attack. I think this is better.
c08201
Kenzo: Seven attacks.
c08202
Delwath: Seven attacks is good.
c08203
Wellby: There's more chance to crit.
c08204
DM: Each... But each attack, like your attacks are better because remember you-
c08205
Delwath: You get plus five on every attack
c08206
DM: ... you're getting plus, like se- your staff should do-
c08207
Unknown: Oh, your staff-
c08208
DM: ... plus six or plus-
c08209
Unknown: ... is plus seven, right?
c08210
Seeker: Huh? Okay. Go- click on...
c08211
DM: Go up to attacks.
c08212
DM: Your staff does 1 D12 plus seven.
c08213
Delwath: Yeah, so four 1 D12 plus sevens.
c08214
DM: So seven is better than-
c08215
Delwath: It's definitely better
c08216
DM: ... the extra D6. It only adds an average of 3.5.
c08217
Kenzo: Yeah. All right. So let's do, let's do that.
c08218
Kenzo: So I'm gonna do seven attacks, right?
c08219
Unknown: Yeah.
c08220
DM: Yeah.
c08221
Unknown: So four with your staff, right?
c08222
DM: Four with your staff and three with your-
c08223
Unknown: I'll still, I'll still go for the same
c08224
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
c08225
Unknown: Right?
c08226
Unknown: Just roll four.
c08227
Kenzo: Oh, do I get advantage right now?
c08228
DM: No.
c08229
Kenzo: Oh, well that's sad.
c08230
Delwath: There's your four.
c08231
Wellby: Oh, no.
c08232
Delwath: Uh, what's, uh...
c08233
Unknown: Does that-
c08234
Wellby: Plus what?
c08235
Delwath: Plus 12. What do you have?
c08236
Unknown: Plus-
c08237
Unknown: Plus 13.
c08238
Kenzo: Plus 13. So two hit-
c08239
Wellby: Does 22 hit?
c08240
Kenzo: 22.
c08241
DM: 22... Wait, I closed the stat block.
c08242
DM: Give me one second.
c08243
Kenzo: Yeah, it, it hits. It hits. I remember a 22.
c08244
DM: 22 should hit, yes.
c08245
Kenzo: Okay. So I got three hits.
c08246
Unknown: Nice.
c08247
Kenzo: And then I do 3 D12 plus 21.
c08248
Unknown: Plus 21. [laughs]
c08249
DM: Yeah.
c08250
Unknown: Yeah.
c08251
DM: 3 D12 plus 21.
c08252
Unknown: Wow, 3 D12 plus 21.
c08253
Kenzo: Actually four, actually 4 D12 plus 21.
c08254
DM: Right, 'cause you're doing the extra.
c08255
Kenzo: So...
c08256
Kenzo: Yeah, see, this is good.
c08257
Kenzo: So this is 16,
c08258
Kenzo: 20-
c08259
Unknown: 20
c08260
Unknown: ... 28.
c08261
Unknown: Eight.
c08262
Delwath: 49.
c08263
DM: 49.
c08264
Delwath: And then you get two more attacks.
c08265
Kenzo: Yeah. Now three more attacks.
c08266
Unknown: What?
c08267
Unknown: Yeah.
c08268
DM: Yeah.
c08269
Kenzo: 29. Now three more-
c08270
Delwath: See, this is better than the different, than uh...
c08271
Kenzo: Hold on. Three punch attacks.
c08272
Unknown: Oh, no.
c08273
Delwath: And two misses.
c08274
Delwath: Uh, four... That'll hit. Four, uh, 20...
c08275
Delwath: Do you have, what, 11 with your punch attacks?
c08276
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. So only one.
c08277
DM: One hits.
c08278
Unknown: That's sad.
c08279
Unknown: Yeah.
c08280
Wellby: Uh-
c08281
Unknown: 1 D12 plus five.
c08282
Wellby: Okay, 1 D12 plus five.
c08283
Unknown: Eight.
c08284
DM: Eight more damage?
c08285
Kenzo: Yeah.
c08286
Wellby: Yeah.
c08287
DM: Okay.
c08288
Unknown: Look how the-
c08289
Wellby: 36. That's more than 300 total.
c08290
Delwath: Yeah, it's probably about 400 hit points.
c08291
Kenzo: She's bloodied around 200.
c08292
Wellby: Ladder's just alone.
c08293
DM: Yeah, or a little above that.
c08294
Unknown: It's like, I got this.
c08295
DM: Yeah. The ladder's, the ladder's gonna take out the minions, or get taken out by the minions.
c08296
Delwath: But either one works.
c08297
Wellby: Yep.
c08298
Unknown: [laughs]
c08299
DM: So wait, that ended Kenza's turn, so Delweth is up.
c08300
Unknown: Okay.
c08301
DM: Round three begins.
c08302
Delwath: I'm going-
c08303
Wellby: [laughs]
c08304
Delwath: Yeah, I'm going to bonus action-
c08305
Unknown: 12 is
c08306
Unknown: not enough, guys
c08307
Delwath: ... uh, Yazali's mark.
c08308
Unknown: Oh.
c08309
DM: Okay.
c08310
Seeker: I can, I can banish or rend, so-
c08311
Unknown: Yeah, you can banish or rend right now.
c08312
Seeker: So you're saying I should banish this guy.
c08313
Wellby: Yeah.
c08314
Unknown: I think so.
c08315
Seeker: Yeah. All right. So that's, um, DC 21.
c08316
Wellby: Legendary, legendary action first.
c08317
Unknown: Is it-
c08318
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. Oh, sorry. Go.
c08319
DM: Charisma?
c08320
Kenzo: Banish charisma.
c08321
DM: That's a 28.
c08322
Kenzo: Oh, fails.
c08323
Seeker: Uh, so they're still
c08324
Seeker: 3 D6 force damage.
c08325
Unknown: Even on a failed save?
c08326
Kenzo: Oh, that's-
c08327
DM: I think it-
c08328
Delwath: If it says on failure, that means if a-
c08329
Unknown: Fail
c08330
Delwath: ... on a successful save, nothing happens.
c08331
Unknown: Right.
c08332
Delwath: Uh, 24 I assume hits.
c08333
DM: Yep. You're attacking the queen.
c08334
Unknown: Yep.
c08335
Delwath: Uh, 15,
c08336
Delwath: uh, plus 11 is-
c08337
Unknown: 26
c08338
Unknown: ... 26, plus
c08339
Unknown: 11.
c08340
Unknown: Nice
c08341
Delwath: ... is 37 for the first attack.
c08342
Unknown: Nice.
c08343
Delwath: Uh, 22 hits, right?
c08344
Unknown: Yeah.
c08345
DM: Yep.
c08346
Unknown: Uh,
c08347
Delwath: 13, 15-
c08348
Unknown: 19
c08349
Delwath: ... 19, plus, uh, 11.
c08350
Wellby: 30.
c08351
Unknown: 30.
c08352
Unknown: Ah, miss.
c08353
DM: Okay.
c08354
Kenzo: Queen still alive?
c08355
DM: Still alive.
c08356
Delwath: Yeah. Uh, that was my bonus action and my action.
c08357
DM: So that ends your turn.
c08358
DM: Um,
c08359
DM: uh, Wellby is up, unless you want to legendary.
c08360
Unknown: Rend.
c08361
DM: Okay.
c08362
DM: Against?
c08363
Seeker: Oh, good question. Against, um-
c08364
Wellby: The queen
c08365
Unknown: ... the queen.
c08366
Wellby: Why not, right?
c08367
Kenzo: Oh, the queen's on your back. Can you-
c08368
Unknown: Can you reach the queen?
c08369
Seeker: That's an interesting question. I mean-
c08370
DM: I always let dragons attack PCs who are on their back.
c08371
Unknown: That's three squares.
c08372
Unknown: Yeah.
c08373
DM: So I think it's-
c08374
Seeker: Hey, I have a 10-foot reach.
c08375
Unknown: Yeah.
c08376
Seeker: Oh, that hits.
c08377
Seeker: That's a 32.
c08378
Unknown: Yeah.
c08379
DM: Yeah, that hits.
c08380
Seeker: Uh, and then it's 2 D8 plus eight.
c08381
Unknown: 19. Oh, no, 14.
c08382
Delwath: 14 plus 8. 22.
c08383
Unknown: 22.
c08384
Unknown: Thank you.
c08385
DM: Uh,
c08386
DM: yeah. It's below a... It's down to a quarter.
c08387
DM: She's down to a quarter of her health.
c08388
DM: Below a quarter of her health.
c08389
Delwath: And now it's her turn. Oh, no, Wellby.
c08390
DM: It's Wellby's turn. Just deciding when she's gonna use her last villain action, but it's gonna be after Wellby's turn.
c08391
Wellby: All right. I'm gonna bonus action drink a potion of greater healing.
c08392
Delwath: Oh, right. You only have 11 hit points.
c08393
Wellby: Oh, yeah.
c08394
Delwath: Oh, man. Sorry, I forgot that you o- I don't have any spells left.
c08395
Wellby: Uh...
c08396
Delwath: Sorry, I can't help you
c08397
Wellby: ... but now I have 23 hit points.
c08398
Wellby: [laughs]
c08399
Unknown: Um-
c08400
Unknown: Run away, run away
c08401
Unknown: ... slightly precarious-
c08402
Kenzo: You have haste, you have haste though, so try to-
c08403
Unknown: I, I mean-
c08404
Seeker: But the room upstairs is full of minions
c08405
Unknown: ... the room upstairs is full of minions.
c08406
Wellby: Yeah, I'm, I'm gonna keep shooting.
c08407
Wellby: This is still the, this is still the right strategy.
c08408
Wellby: Even if I go down, go down swinging.
c08409
Delwath: Um, right.
c08410
Delwath: I don't have any spell slots.
c08411
Delwath: I have one second level spell slot.
c08412
Unknown: I can heal you a little bit.
c08413
Wellby: I'll be fine. I'm
c08414
Wellby: good. Um-
c08415
Unknown: Seeker still has a few spell slots.
c08416
Seeker: And, like, somebody could toss him a potion.
c08417
Delwath: I can heal him where with the second level.
c08418
Unknown: I mean-
c08419
Unknown: Right
c08420
Delwath: ... if he goes down, I can bring him up with Healing Word.
c08421
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
c08422
Wellby: All right. D's-
c08423
Wellby: Which is also just a bonus action, so
c08424
Wellby: ... uh, another DC 19 con save.
c08425
DM: At who? The queen?
c08426
Wellby: Queen. That's a-
c08427
Unknown: 20
c08428
Wellby: ... 19 to hit.
c08429
Delwath: Does a 20 hit? Come on.
c08430
Unknown: No.
c08431
DM: A 20 does not hit
c08432
Wellby: I'll use Heroic Inspiration
c08433
DM: You need a 21 to hit
c08434
Unknown: Nice
c08435
Wellby: That's, that's a hit
c08436
DM: Uh, that was a 22 on the con save
c08437
Wellby: That makes it,
c08438
Wellby: uh, 6, 18-
c08439
Unknown: That's good. Those sound like good dice
c08440
Wellby: ... plus 24,
c08441
Wellby: uh, 28, 31, 32, uh, 37 and 8 is, uh, 45.
c08442
Wellby: 45, and then already in action that as soon as the triceratops attacks, I'll shoot her again
c08443
DM: Okay. Um-
c08444
Unknown: Oh, triceratops
c08445
DM: Okay. Before the triceratops she's gonna use her villain action.
c08446
DM: Sorry, let me just add up...
c08447
Unknown: [laughs] Triceratops has mighty...
c08448
Unknown: How many hit points does it have left?
c08449
Wellby: Uh, it has 69 still
c08450
DM: Oh, okay, so it'll be okay
c08451
DM: Um, the ash begins to, like, bursts out in a 60-foot radius from her, so that's everybody on this floor and the triceratops, but it doesn't go through the-
c08452
Unknown: Door
c08453
DM: ... um, the door.
c08454
DM: Everybody make a charisma saving throw
c08455
Unknown: Oh shit. Get it.
c08456
Seeker: So wait, I use my own charisma or I use the dragon's?
c08457
Delwath: You use your own charisma. [die rolling]
c08458
Unknown: 20...
c08459
Kenzo: No, a, a million
c08460
Wellby: It's close to it
c08461
Unknown: 30 something.
c08462
Unknown: Uh, I rolled an 18
c08463
Wellby: Uh, I rolled a
c08464
Wellby: 9
c08465
Unknown: I rolled a nine.
c08466
Seeker: Wait, is that 16?
c08467
DM: That's a 16
c08468
Unknown: Yeah.
c08469
Unknown: 18
c08470
DM: Sorry, 18, 9.
c08471
DM: What did you roll?
c08472
Delwath: I rolled an 18. I have a plus 10
c08473
DM: So you're 28.
c08474
Delwath: Okay, so it's higher than that, too
c08475
DM: Oh, okay
c08476
Kenzo: So I rolled a, uh...
c08477
Kenzo: Is it charisma?
c08478
Unknown: Charisma temp?
c08479
DM: Charisma, yeah
c08480
Delwath: Oh, do you need to know what it actually is?
c08481
DM: I don't need to know what you actually rolled, no
c08482
Kenzo: I, I rolled, I rolled a 16 so I'm gonna, I'm gonna use my, use the bardic you gave me.
c08483
Kenzo: So is it-
c08484
DM: Okay
c08485
Kenzo: ... d12 then pick the highest or just one?
c08486
DM: No, it's just one d12.
c08487
DM: [die rolling]
c08488
Unknown: Oh.
c08489
Wellby: Yes
c08490
DM: Okay.
c08491
Unknown: 20 [laughs]
c08492
DM: You, you two succeed.
c08493
DM: Wellby and the dragon-
c08494
Unknown: Oh, no
c08495
DM: ... take 55 points of necrotic damage-
c08496
Unknown: Oh, that's not good
c08497
DM: ... and if it reduces you to zero hit points you immediately fail one death saving throw
c08498
Unknown: Oh, my God
c08499
Wellby: I immediately fail one death saving throw
c08500
Unknown: Oh
c08501
DM: And you need to make another concentration check
c08502
Seeker: My temp hit points are already gone.
c08503
Wellby: Oh.
c08504
Unknown: Concentration check
c08505
DM: But once the temp hit points-
c08506
Unknown: Oh, yeah
c08507
DM: ... it, when the, if the temp hit points go away, the dragon form ends
c08508
Seeker: Right. I still have 122 on the temp.
c08509
Seeker: [die rolling] Um, so that's, uh,
c08510
Unknown: 16. 23.
c08511
Delwath: How much damage was it?
c08512
DM: 55, so you need to use another legendary here
c08513
Unknown: Ah.
c08514
Wellby: Wait, uh-
c08515
Delwath: Wait, wait, wait. Hold on. Hold on
c08516
Wellby: ... don't use your legendary
c08517
Delwath: Use your legendary to not fail the first saving throw
c08518
Delwath: Oh yeah, that's a way better choice [laughs]
c08519
Delwath: Use a legendary resistance to succeed on the saving throw she just made you make
c08520
Wellby: Oh
c08521
Delwath: Don't take the damage
c08522
DM: Well, no, you take half 'cause I haven't gotten to that yet.
c08523
DM: So you guys take a quarter, so 55 divided by 4.
c08524
Unknown: What's 55 divided by 4?
c08525
DM: 13.
c08526
DM: You save and now you take half,
c08527
DM: so you take 27, and you still need to make-
c08528
Seeker: So wait, I, I, I took the damage already on my character sheet
c08529
DM: So add back 27, add back 28 temp HP, and you pass the con save because-
c08530
Kenzo: To the, to your temp
c08531
DM: ... to your temp. Add 28 temp HP
c08532
Seeker: Uh, 22 plus 28 is 50
c08533
DM: Uh, now it's the triceratops's turn
c08534
Unknown: 'Cause he's switching.
c08535
Kenzo: He still has to make a concentration save?
c08536
DM: No, 'cause his previous roll would succeed-
c08537
Unknown: Oh, got it. Got it. Got it. Got it
c08538
DM: ... for the half, the reduced damage
c08539
Unknown: Nice.
c08540
DM: So Wellby is on the back of the dragon.
c08541
DM: Wellby, I'm g- I think you're gonna fall off the back of the dragon now that you're unconscious
c08542
Wellby: Also reasonable
c08543
DM: So you land prone on the ground.
c08544
DM: I will... Yeah, there you go.
c08545
DM: Um,
c08546
DM: and it is now the triceratops's turn and then
c08547
DM: lots of enemies
c08548
Unknown: Oh, shit.
c08549
Wellby: Oh.
c08550
Unknown: The triceratops protect you?
c08551
Wellby: Yeah
c08552
Delwath: There's not much
c08553
Delwath: legendary... Wait, hold on.
c08554
Delwath: Hold on. Can you banish Wellby?
c08555
Seeker: [laughs] I don't see why not.
c08556
DM: Uh-
c08557
Unknown: I mean, he failed-
c08558
DM: ... I can do it now, so I can do it again
c08559
Delwath: ... he failed a death save
c08560
Seeker: Or no, no, no, I can't do it again. I just, I just attempted it.
c08561
DM: I, uh-
c08562
Unknown: Ah, you-
c08563
DM: You just did it. You can only... It's, I think it's only once a turn
c08564
Delwath: It is once a turn
c08565
Wellby: That's a hilarious save
c08566
Kenzo: How many death saves do you have? T-
c08567
Wellby: I have one failure so far
c08568
Unknown: And have, but how many in total?
c08569
Wellby: Two more to go
c08570
Unknown: Two more to go.
c08571
Kenzo: Ah, that's a lot of enemies down there.
c08572
Kenzo: Yeah, maybe-
c08573
Wellby: Uh, triceratops is gonna come around.
c08574
Wellby: It doesn't do much, but it does something.
c08575
Wellby: Uh, two attacks on the, um-
c08576
DM: It needs to roll for-
c08577
Wellby: Oh, that's right. Yeah, [laughs] I failed that again
c08578
DM: It's gonna die from the-
c08579
Delwath: It still has enough hit points that it won't die this turn
c08580
Wellby: How much damage?
c08581
DM: It won't die this turn, yeah.
c08582
DM: Roll 4d10
c08583
Delwath: I'm rolling
c08584
DM: Okay
c08585
Delwath: I have 22.
c08586
Wellby: Uh...
c08587
DM: Um,
c08588
DM: I mean, remember you can move up to half your speed when you l- take a legendary action, so you could also land on top of Wellby
c08589
Delwath: Oh, you should do that
c08590
Wellby: Could the-
c08591
Unknown: Oh, I didn't think of that
c08592
Wellby: ... triceratops climb on top of me?
c08593
DM: Yeah, the triceratops can, like, stand their guard.
c08594
DM: I mean, you're small, right? So anything,
c08595
DM: anything that's more than two sizes bigger than you can occupy your space
c08596
Delwath: I think the dragon should probably land on top of Wellby
c08597
Wellby: But the triceratops is on top of him
c08598
Delwath: I know, but the dragon can, like, fill the space here
c08599
DM: The dragon's a little more threatening than the [laughs] triceratops
c08600
Unknown: Should we do that?
c08601
Wellby: Who was done-
c08602
Delwath: Well, after that cleanup and turn
c08603
Wellby: ... take away
c08604
DM: You can take a legendary before the blood m- molten blood thing goes
c08605
Wellby: So can I attack now with a minus-
c08606
DM: Six, yeah
c08607
Wellby: ... six to attack? Awesome.
c08608
Unknown: 20. 20
c08609
Wellby: Uh, so this is gonna be 1 plus 3.
c08610
Unknown: 20, 20.
c08611
Wellby: They both miss again
c08612
Delwath: [laughs] Triceratops
c08613
DM: [laughs] Triceratops was so good in the battle against the chaos
c08614
Unknown: Yeah
c08615
DM: It's not doing so well here
c08616
Wellby: Really thrown by Limbo
c08617
DM: Really thrown by Limbo. Um,
c08618
DM: okay. You're... Do you wanna take your legendary action now?
c08619
Seeker: So I'll pounce again and-
c08620
DM: So you're gonna attack somebody and then-
c08621
Unknown: Attack
c08622
DM: ... move half your speed, so land on top
c08623
Seeker: I will... Wait, wait, wait. If I move, the queen will get an opportunity attack, won't she?
c08624
DM: No, no, no Y-
c08625
DM: yeah, but do you really care?
c08626
Unknown: She's on you though. Will she move off you?
c08627
Unknown: Will she get off?
c08628
DM: No, she's flying
c08629
Unknown: Oh, she's flying.
c08630
DM: Aren't you like... Wait, wait, hold-
c08631
Seeker: It's the con s- it's the con save
c08632
Unknown: Mm.
c08633
Seeker: The concentration save. I mean
c08634
DM: I... Do you...
c08635
Delwath: Are you actually moving out of her reach?
c08636
Seeker: Oh, that's funny. Not really.
c08637
DM: Oh, actually yeah. No, you wouldn't be moving out of her reach.
c08638
Unknown: All right.
c08639
Seeker: So I make another pounce attack on the queen.
c08640
DM: Oh, okay. Sure.
c08641
Unknown: But that's only a 16.
c08642
Delwath: I was gonna suggest these guys but maybe we just-
c08643
Unknown: Well...
c08644
Delwath: No, no, that's fine. You're gonna miss anyway.
c08645
Unknown: 16. Miss.
c08646
DM: Yeah, that misses.
c08647
Seeker: And crouch on top of-
c08648
DM: So you're... The dragon is now looming protectively over the fallen body of the halfling.
c08649
Kenzo: This is so confusing and we're all on the dragon.
c08650
Delwath: We're on the dragon.
c08651
DM: And you're on the dragon's back.
c08652
DM: The Force of Blood is gonna a- attack the dragon.
c08653
Unknown: Oh.
c08654
Delwath: You only have one legendary resistance though, right?
c08655
Unknown: Oh.
c08656
Delwath: 'Cause this all falls apart if you fail that con save.
c08657
DM: Um-
c08658
Unknown: So let's go
c08659
DM: ... that's a 26.
c08660
Unknown: That hits.
c08661
DM: So that's 17 damage.
c08662
Delwath: A con sa- a con- con save, 17.
c08663
Unknown: I, I have two left.
c08664
DM: Three or higher.
c08665
Kenzo: Two legendary resistances left.
c08666
Seeker: Two legendary resistance, yeah.
c08667
DM: No, you used one to fail the...
c08668
DM: Y- you used two
c08669
Unknown: Sorry, one-
c08670
DM: You have one left.
c08671
Seeker: Oh crap, you're right. I did use another one.
c08672
Unknown: But you beat the-
c08673
Unknown: But that's okay.
c08674
DM: But you beat it.
c08675
Unknown: [laughs]
c08676
DM: Um-
c08677
Unknown: Let's play again
c08678
DM: ... the, the-
c08679
Delwath: Seeker's like, "I don't know about this getting hit constantly-
c08680
DM: Yeah [laughs]
c08681
Unknown: ... thing is bad for me."
c08682
DM: Um-
c08683
Seeker: Yeah, this, this dragon thing is not all it's cracked up to be.
c08684
Unknown: [laughs]
c08685
c08686
DM: The second
c08687
DM: hit is a 25.
c08688
Unknown: That also hits.
c08689
DM: So that one does 18 points of damage.
c08690
Seeker: Oh, did I miss the damage a second ago?
c08691
Unknown: How much was that?
c08692
DM: No.
c08693
Unknown: 16.
c08694
DM: 16.
c08695
Seeker: So 16.
c08696
Unknown: And then 18.
c08697
Unknown: 18.
c08698
Delwath: Make another, uh...
c08699
Unknown: How do the con saves work?
c08700
DM: Oh, and then, um,
c08701
DM: the b- b- b- b- b- b- b- Delweth make a
c08702
DM: constitution saving throw.
c08703
Unknown: All right.
c08704
Unknown: That's my sa-
c08705
Unknown: This annoying guy
c08706
Seeker: ... concentration.
c08707
Kenzo: You're fine. How does it work?
c08708
Kenzo: Is it based on the damage?
c08709
Seeker: It's, um, yeah. The damage sets the difficulty.
c08710
Unknown: But what, at a, a half?
c08711
Unknown: I don't, I don't know.
c08712
Unknown: 14, 16.
c08713
DM: Not enough.
c08714
Unknown: Uh,
c08715
Seeker: I guess it's... Oh, it's just the DC is half the damage.
c08716
Seeker: Is that what you said before? I think so.
c08717
Unknown: Uh,
c08718
Unknown: 19?
c08719
DM: Exactly what you need.
c08720
Kenzo: What's, what's the con save, uh, concentration save?
c08721
Delwath: It's half the damage.
c08722
DM: Half the damage or 10, whichever is higher.
c08723
Delwath: As long as it's less than 20 damage you need a three.
c08724
DM: You need to roll a three, yeah.
c08725
Unknown: Oh, so he gets a plus-
c08726
Unknown: Plus seven
c08727
DM: He gets a plus seven.
c08728
Unknown: Ah.
c08729
DM: So the last attack, sorry, I forgot about the bonus.
c08730
DM: The last attack is a 32, and that does 22 total damage.
c08731
Delwath: So you can roll a four or better.
c08732
Seeker: Oh, so I need to take 22 damage.
c08733
DM: And it suc- it hasn't gotten to use its boiling blood once.
c08734
Unknown: Nice.
c08735
Unknown: I need another four.
c08736
DM: So that ends its turn.
c08737
Kenzo: This boiling, boiling blood thing sounds really bad.
c08738
Unknown: It really sounds bad.
c08739
DM: [laughs]
c08740
Delwath: I've now used all my possible ways of not...
c08741
Delwath: I had to use my blessings of the ta'vie to roll more dice to avoid another saving throw.
c08742
DM: Uh, the queen-
c08743
Delwath: Oh wait, the queen gets-
c08744
DM: ... is not quite dead.
c08745
Delwath: That's not really fair. She has to... Wait, wait, wait.
c08746
Delwath: Are you making second radiance checks?
c08747
DM: Yeah, both of them have a plus 13 to their con save, so.
c08748
Unknown: So they have to roll a six.
c08749
DM: They have to.
c08750
Unknown: They should eventually fail.
c08751
DM: Yeah, so far they haven't.
c08752
DM: Um, the queen
c08753
DM: is-
c08754
Kenzo: On the dragon's back. Oh no, she's flying
c08755
DM: ... flying.
c08756
DM: Kenzo and Delweth-
c08757
Kenzo: We're on, we're both on the dragon's back.
c08758
DM: Sh- yeah, she's not... I think she's just gonna keep going after the dragon at this point.
c08759
DM: The dragon's kind of scary.
c08760
DM: Oh wait, does it get his moment of loss back?
c08761
Unknown: Me.
c08762
DM: Nope.
c08763
DM: Can't turn anybody into ash.
c08764
Seeker: Dragon has glasses. You're really gonna hit a dragon with glasses?
c08765
DM: Nah, that's a
c08766
DM: 16. That misses.
c08767
Unknown: Yeah.
c08768
DM: And then-
c08769
Unknown: Apparently not
c08770
DM: ... um, a 24 and a
c08771
DM: 30-something.
c08772
Unknown: Both hit.
c08773
DM: These are, these do a lot of damage.
c08774
DM: The dragon might be in trouble.
c08775
Seeker: I have 94 now.
c08776
DM: So that's-
c08777
Delwath: You have a tough... Oh, you have one more legendary
c08778
DM: ... 19 plus 14, so that's a total of...
c08779
DM: Oh wait, oh wait. Are you immune to fire damage?
c08780
Unknown: Yes.
c08781
DM: Okay, so-
c08782
Seeker: Dragon is immune to fire
c08783
DM: ... only 13.
c08784
Unknown: Okay.
c08785
Unknown: That's easy.
c08786
DM: And then the second one-
c08787
Unknown: 13
c08788
DM: ... is 15 total damage, so you take 13 plus 15 damage and two-
c08789
Unknown: Concentration
c08790
DM: ... all right, now that she realizes you're immune to fire damage she might change her mind next turn.
c08791
Unknown: She won't make it to next turn, so-
c08792
DM: She might not make it to next turn
c08793
Seeker: The first one is I gotta beat a three.
c08794
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
c08795
Unknown: Both times?
c08796
DM: Yep.
c08797
Delwath: Two rolls, they gotta beat a three.
c08798
Kenzo: Nice.
c08799
Unknown: Yes. [laughs]
c08800
DM: Was that a three?
c08801
Delwath: Yeah. I mean, you don't have to beat a three, you have to get a three.
c08802
DM: Right.
c08803
Unknown: Yeah.
c08804
Unknown: Oh
c08805
Unknown: my fucking god.
c08806
Unknown: [laughs] So many threes and fours.
c08807
Unknown: So many threes and fours.
c08808
Delwath: Seeker's just, like, hanging on.
c08809
Unknown: Ugh.
c08810
Delwath: Uh, I really get the sense Seeker's very uncomfortable being constantly stabbed.
c08811
Unknown: [laughs]
c08812
c08813
Unknown: It's really terrible.
c08814
Kenzo: It's like even though Seeker is a dragon-
c08815
DM: She's gonna use-
c08816
Unknown: [laughs]
c08817
DM: She's gonna use her bonus action to-
c08818
Delwath: Wait, she's moving Kenzo?
c08819
DM: No, sorry, not Kenzo, her, to teleport.
c08820
DM: You two both make dex saves.
c08821
DM: Actually, Delweth and, or Wellby and the dra- oh, Wellby fails another death saving throw.
c08822
Unknown: Uh-oh.
c08823
DM: The dragon and Kenzo and...
c08824
DM: Oh, the dragon doesn't have to 'cause it's fire damage.
c08825
DM: You two make dex saving throws.
c08826
DM: Nope.
c08827
Kenzo: Wait, me and, uh, who?
c08828
Unknown: Delweth.
c08829
Unknown: Oh wait, sorry. The triceratops has to save?
c08830
DM: The triceratops too, yeah. You take five points of fire damage.
c08831
Wellby: Yeah, triceratops.
c08832
DM: 10 points of fire damage.
c08833
Unknown: Oh.
c08834
Unknown: Uh, I rolled a-
c08835
Unknown: Five
c08836
Unknown: ... so 10
c08837
DM: ... zero points of fire damage.
c08838
Delwath: So half of five?
c08839
DM: No, five is already halved.
c08840
DM: Uh, and she teleports up here
c08841
Wellby: Uh, am I gonna take damage from Sigming Radiant at the start of my turn?
c08842
Unknown: No, you're immune.
c08843
DM: You're immune.
c08844
DM: Um-
c08845
Unknown: We're all immune
c08846
Seeker: Someone has to, like, make him, uh...
c08847
Unknown: I, my turn-
c08848
Wellby: How come the, the triceratops is not immune though?
c08849
Unknown: Because they-
c08850
DM: You can only do five creatures
c08851
Unknown: ... you summoned it after I cast it
c08852
Kenzo: Then you summoned it after
c08853
Delwath: ... you summoned it after I cast it
c08854
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
c08855
Delwath: Right? I can't, I can't retroactively-
c08856
Unknown: Yeah
c08857
Delwath: ... immunify somebody.
c08858
Delwath: You'll be... By your turn you'll be up though.
c08859
Delwath: Oh, no, we're due.
c08860
Unknown: Awesome
c08861
Delwath: You only have 10 hit points,
c08862
Unknown: if that.
c08863
Wellby: Thought I had more than that before [laughs]
c08864
Unknown: No, I'm just saying, you might-
c08865
DM: All right
c08866
Unknown: ... be back down again [laughs]
c08867
DM: Um, the, this Essence of Mist hasn't gotten to do much yet.
c08868
DM: It is going to attack the dragon,
c08869
DM: hitting twice.
c08870
DM: You are not immune to psychic or slashing damage.
c08871
Seeker: Oh, no, just fire
c08872
DM: So that's, uh...
c08873
Delwath: I'm really enjoying having the dragon here 'cause I do not-
c08874
Unknown: Oh, the dragon's so good
c08875
Delwath: ... feel good about how this would have been going without the dragon
c08876
DM: 30...
c08877
Unknown: We're, we're-
c08878
DM: So 32 points of damage
c08879
Unknown: [laughs] 3200 points of damage
c08880
Unknown: Yeah, it's pretty, pretty good
c08881
DM: So a 16, DC 16 constit- concentration saving throw.
c08882
Seeker: Oh, fuck. DC 16, so I have to roll a nine
c08883
DM: A nine
c08884
Seeker: And this is a more closer to a 50/50 one
c08885
Unknown: Yeah.
c08886
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
c08887
DM: Oh my God
c08888
Unknown: Oh my God
c08889
Unknown: Fucking...
c08890
Unknown: Ah
c08891
DM: Oh, and the next attack is a 14, so it misses
c08892
Seeker: Amazing
c08893
DM: And then it's gonna attempt to hide in the dragon again.
c08894
DM: Const- con-
c08895
Unknown: Oh, God
c08896
DM: ... DC 18 constitution saving throw
c08897
Unknown: Oh, fuck
c08898
Seeker: It's like 10 plus two
c08899
Delwath: You use... No, you use the dragon's plus seven
c08900
DM: You use the dra- it's a constitution saving throw-
c08901
Unknown: Oh
c08902
DM: ... so dragon's plus seven
c08903
Unknown: So 12
c08904
Unknown: 11
c08905
Delwath: You need to roll a 12
c08906
DM: 11. It's a DC 18
c08907
Unknown: Ah.
c08908
Unknown: 11 plus-
c08909
Unknown: It's a plus seven. Oh.
c08910
DM: You have to match-
c08911
Unknown: Yeah, I can't do math.
c08912
Delwath: Math's weak.
c08913
Seeker: You are not going into my mouth again
c08914
Unknown: 12.
c08915
Kenzo: Oh, nice.
c08916
Unknown: Yeah
c08917
DM: Yeah. You, you-
c08918
Unknown: So strong
c08919
DM: ... the dragon's just like, "[snorts] No.
c08920
DM: Back away," and the thing retreats.
c08921
DM: Um,
c08922
DM: that ends its turn
c08923
Kenzo: This battle is stressful as fuck.
c08924
DM: [laughs]
c08925
Kenzo: We've rolled so many saving throws.
c08926
Unknown: Yeah
c08927
Kenzo: The number of saving throws in this battle-
c08928
Unknown: Yeah
c08929
Seeker: ... is fucking ridiculous
c08930
DM: Uh-
c08931
Unknown: We've, we've only failed the dais-
c08932
Unknown: Yeah
c08933
Kenzo: ... and which is like kind of the gentlest one to fail
c08934
Unknown: Yeah
c08935
Kenzo: Like, everything else, like the black one-
c08936
DM: One of these days you're gonna fail the-
c08937
Unknown: Some of us failed
c08938
Unknown: Yeah [laughs]
c08939
Unknown: [laughs]
c08940
Unknown: The dead ones
c08941
DM: [coughs]
c08942
Delwath: Wait, uh, have all the bad guys gone?
c08943
DM: Nope
c08944
Unknown: They've not
c08945
Unknown: Man, who hasn't gone?
c08946
DM: The centaur and the minions.
c08947
DM: The centaur's gonna charge the dragon, its arm turning into a great blade
c08948
Unknown: I'm not in the way.
c08949
Unknown: It's okay.
c08950
Unknown: Goddamn it.
c08951
Wellby: Oh, you're fucking almost done with the dragon
c08952
Unknown: 34
c08953
Unknown: Oh, wow
c08954
DM: Miss.
c08955
Kenzo: The queen has got... We gotta kill the queen this turn
c08956
DM: Hit
c08957
Kenzo: The queen has got to go
c08958
DM: Hit
c08959
DM: I'm on it
c08960
DM: That's 17 points of slashing and 24 points of slashing
c08961
Unknown: 17
c08962
DM: So-
c08963
Seeker: This is not looking good
c08964
DM: ... three in be- Oh
c08965
Unknown: Oh, that's it. Oh.
c08966
DM: Seeker-
c08967
Unknown: Oh, no
c08968
DM: ... the dragon vanishes and Seeker drops on top of Wellby
c08969
Unknown: Uh, where's Seeker?
c08970
Wellby: Not, not causing damage I hope
c08971
DM: Not causing damage
c08972
Delwath: Oh, that's the wrong Seeker.
c08973
Delwath: But there's no bad guys, right?
c08974
DM: Uh, just the minions who are gonna swarm the ladder
c08975
Seeker: I never even got to use a breath weapon
c08976
DM: Wait, you never u-
c08977
Unknown: No
c08978
Delwath: ... oh, 'cause you cast chain lightning instead
c08979
Unknown: Which was all right
c08980
DM: Which was good. Um, every single creature was either resistant or immune to fire-
c08981
Unknown: Yeah
c08982
DM: ... except for that misty thing
c08983
Seeker: Oh, so it wouldn't have mattered
c08984
Delwath: It wasn't a very good breath weapon
c08985
DM: Um, but, but the ladder's about to die
c08986
Seeker: 73 hit points
c08987
DM: That's a 16 to hit.
c08988
DM: What's the... Oh, no, it's much higher than that.
c08989
DM: It's a 26 to hit
c08990
Seeker: Uh, the ladder's AC is 16
c08991
DM: The ladder takes, um, 80 points of slashing damage as it is ripped to shreds by little clouds
c08992
Unknown: The ladder is dead.
c08993
Unknown: Oh, shit
c08994
DM: Seeker's up
c08995
Seeker: Um, okay, I gotta think in dwarf mode again
c08996
DM: The, the queen is almost dead
c08997
Delwath: Do you have an 8th level slot?
c08998
Kenzo: Probably. Let's see
c08999
Delwath: Chain lightning the queen?
c09000
Unknown: Um,
c09001
Seeker: I do have an 8th level slot
c09002
Delwath: She's probably 30. You probably can't get the queen and...
c09003
Delwath: Or you could chain lightning all three of these guys
c09004
Seeker: I have a 7th level slot. I could use chain lightning
c09005
Kenzo: Chain lightning and get all the minions?
c09006
DM: No, it's not useful for minions 'cause it only hits three creatures
c09007
Delwath: [laughs] See, I think Delwath and Kenzo can...
c09008
Delwath: Delwath, Kenzo, and Wellby can probably take out the queen
c09009
Seeker: So I should chain lightning all three of these guys
c09010
Unknown: I think you should, yeah
c09011
Unknown: All right
c09012
DM: The,
c09013
DM: the
c09014
DM: centaur is pretty wounded.
c09015
DM: The
c09016
DM: Essence of Mist is pretty wounded
c09017
Kenzo: Are any of them immune to, uh, lightning?
c09018
DM: You don't know. You haven't soul sighted any of them
c09019
Delwath: You should have been soul sighting and using-
c09020
Kenzo: Yeah. Why can't I be soul sighting?
c09021
Delwath: We've soul sighted this guy already.
c09022
Unknown: We soul sighted the centaur
c09023
DM: Yeah, no, none of them are immune to lightning.
c09024
DM: That's right. You soul sighted all of them
c09025
Delwath: The, the thing of mist you haven't.
c09026
Seeker: All right. I cast chain lightning.
c09027
Seeker: They each must make a DC 19 dex save
c09028
DM: Oh, they're... These two are pretty bad at dex saves.
c09029
DM: Um, 17 fails.
c09030
DM: 18 fails.
c09031
DM: And then the mist is a 19, so succeeds
c09032
Delwath: And wait, you're up casting it 7th level?
c09033
Seeker: Yeah, that doesn't change the damage though
c09034
Unknown: No?
c09035
Seeker: It's... You can get an additional bolt, but there's only three of them
c09036
Delwath: Well, you can't hit the queen
c09037
DM: How, how far away can it be?
c09038
Seeker: 30 feet
c09039
DM: Yeah, no-
c09040
Unknown: Oh, well
c09041
DM: ... 'cause it's 30 feet from the ground to the ceiling
c09042
Unknown: Right.
c09043
Unknown: Yeah
c09044
DM: Okay
c09045
Kenzo: From the window to the wall
c09046
DM: Roll it
c09047
Delwath: 10 to 10, 10 to 8
c09048
DM: Roll your damage
c09049
Seeker: Is 53
c09050
DM: The only one that succeeded was the mist
c09051
Seeker: So that's 53
c09052
DM: 53?
c09053
DM: Uh, hold on. Let me do some math here
c09054
Delwath: And then Kenzo, right?
c09055
Wellby: And then top of the order is you again
c09056
Delwath: Yeah. So it's going to be you before your turn
c09057
Unknown: Awesome
c09058
DM: That one disintegrates from the lightning
c09059
Delwath: Did you... You made all the saving radius saves.
c09060
Unknown: They all made their saves
c09061
DM: Um, uh, yes
c09062
Unknown: Wait
c09063
DM: Uh, oh wait, I forgot on the one who just died
c09064
Unknown: Oh, okay
c09065
DM: The essence made its save.
c09066
Unknown: Like
c09067
DM: I didn't roll for the one who just died
c09068
Unknown: So
c09069
DM: But it died
c09070
Delwath: I... Yeah
c09071
Unknown: Yeah
c09072
Kenzo: It's coming. It's coming.
c09073
DM: Um-
c09074
Unknown: Okay. [laughs]
c09075
DM: The, the essence made its save-
c09076
Unknown: I mean
c09077
DM: So, sorry, it was 53 you said?
c09078
Unknown: Yeah
c09079
DM: So half of that is 26
c09080
Delwath: I can, I can bonus action heal and then run after the queen
c09081
Seeker: I'm having the, like, Phantom Limbs thing where I'm, like, flapping my wings and using my-
c09082
DM: Um, and then-
c09083
Seeker: ... reaction. I'm like, shit, I'm just a dwarf
c09084
DM: The force bounce of that 53 when
c09085
DM: the f- the, the metallic blood is bloodied.
c09086
DM: Uh, that ends Seeker's turn.
c09087
DM: Kenzo.
c09088
Kenzo: All right. Kenzo will, um, fly 30 feet up through here and land over here
c09089
DM: Yeah, from where you are it's probably 25 feet up, but you've got-
c09090
Unknown: Okay
c09091
DM: ... the bazillion moves, so.
c09092
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. Okay. So I'll come up here.
c09093
Kenzo: Now, um,
c09094
Kenzo: I guess it's still not worth using Langust Claw, right?
c09095
Kenzo: 'Cause like that wastes my bonus actions-
c09096
DM: Yeah
c09097
Kenzo: ... and I lose my three attacks, right?
c09098
DM: Yeah, it's probably-
c09099
Kenzo: So it's better just still to attack-
c09100
DM: Yeah, yeah
c09101
Kenzo: ... five times.
c09102
DM: Yeah.
c09103
Kenzo: So I'll attack five times.
c09104
Kenzo: All right.
c09105
Kenzo: First, uh, so let's do the two
c09106
DM: On the queen. So remember your-
c09107
Unknown: Okay
c09108
DM: ... one of them gets an extra D12.
c09109
Unknown: Yes, yes,
c09110
Kenzo: yes. Oh, that's good. That hits twice.
c09111
Unknown: Nice.
c09112
Kenzo: And that does, uh-
c09113
Unknown: 3D, 3D 12-
c09114
Unknown: 3D 12 plus-
c09115
Delwath: ... plus 20. No, plus 14
c09116
DM: Plus 14, yeah. 3D 12 plus 14.
c09117
Unknown: 3D 12 plus 14, yes.
c09118
Kenzo: Come on, good stuff.
c09119
Kenzo: That's pretty good.
c09120
Kenzo: 14, uh, 26-
c09121
DM: Wait
c09122
Unknown: ... plus 14. 26-
c09123
Unknown: 40
c09124
Unknown: 40.
c09125
DM: Okay.
c09126
DM: I gotta do... I can't do this on paper anymore.
c09127
DM: It's too complicated.
c09128
Delwath: Okay, three more attacks.
c09129
Unknown: Yeah.
c09130
Kenzo: Three more attacks.
c09131
Delwath: You can do it.
c09132
Unknown: Oh, well, one-
c09133
DM: Two, two, two hit
c09134
Delwath: Two hit.
c09135
Delwath: So two D12 plus 14.
c09136
Unknown: So, yeah, two D12 plus-
c09137
Delwath: Oh, no, plus 10, right? 'Cause your staff, it's not your staff.
c09138
DM: Yeah, it's only plus 10. The staff has an extra plus compared to the, your fist-
c09139
Unknown: Yeah
c09140
DM: ... 'cause your staff's a plus two weapon.
c09141
Kenzo: Yeah, okay. That's right. So two D10, two D12 plus 10.
c09142
Kenzo: No.
c09143
Unknown: A ban.
c09144
Unknown: 10. 15.
c09145
Kenzo: That's not great.
c09146
DM: Not dead.
c09147
Delwath: Okay. Delwath's up.
c09148
Unknown: Ah.
c09149
DM: Delwath's up.
c09150
Unknown: Okay.
c09151
Delwath: Bonus action, Healing Word.
c09152
Wellby: How many hit points do I get?
c09153
Delwath: Uh, not very many.
c09154
Delwath: Hold on, let me look. Unfortunately-
c09155
DM: He s- stays prone until his turn
c09156
Delwath: Unfortunately, I can't...
c09157
Delwath: Let's see, 44 or 2D...
c09158
Delwath: Should I save my second level spell?
c09159
Unknown: I'm gonna s...
c09160
Delwath: There's no, really, a difference.
c09161
Wellby: I mean, like, they're, they're gonna hit so hard that any hit-
c09162
Unknown: Yeah
c09163
Wellby: ... will do.
c09164
Unknown: Yeah.
c09165
c09166
Delwath: Uh, you take, uh, you have, [laughs] uh, nine, nine hit point.
c09167
Delwath: Oh, no, 10.
c09168
Unknown: Oh, uh, I will take it.
c09169
Unknown: 10 hit points.
c09170
DM: Woo-hoo.
c09171
Delwath: Okay. Then I will Raven's Whistle and fly up
c09172
Delwath: to there.
c09173
DM: Okay.
c09174
Delwath: Which is 20 feet away.
c09175
DM: Okay.
c09176
Unknown: And attack.
c09177
DM: Uh,
c09178
DM: yeah, okay.
c09179
DM: No, no, that's fine. Yeah. I'm just looking, do they get it o- the...
c09180
DM: One of those minions probably gets an opportunity attack on you,
c09181
DM: so that's eight points of damage.
c09182
DM: Four points of damage.
c09183
Unknown: Does it... Oh, it hits?
c09184
DM: It hits, yeah.
c09185
Unknown: This, this battle I've taken no damage.
c09186
Kenzo: Oh, no, no, what I'm talking about, I've taken a bunch of damage actually.
c09187
Delwath: Okay. Attack one on the queen.
c09188
Seeker: Over 250 damage.
c09189
Delwath: Uh, 12.
c09190
Delwath: I mean, 22.
c09191
DM: That hits.
c09192
Unknown: So,
c09193
Delwath: uh, crappy roll. Um, for-
c09194
Unknown: [coughs]
c09195
Delwath: ... uh, 10, 15 plus, uh, 12.
c09196
Delwath: So 15 plus 12, 27.
c09197
Unknown: Second attack.
c09198
Delwath: 10, 15 plus 12.
c09199
DM: So as-
c09200
Kenzo: 27
c09201
Delwath: Another 27.
c09202
DM: Delwath swings his blade.
c09203
DM: You can, you can see the runes, like, light up along the blade and there's this, like, in- you feel this intense moment of satisfaction as the blade strikes
c09204
DM: the queen and the ash just condenses and then there's this, like, this burst of radiant light as she crumbles into a pile of dust.
c09205
Unknown: Yes.
c09206
Unknown: Ooh.
c09207
DM: Still have one attack if you wanna try and get some minions.
c09208
Unknown: Uh, well, hold on, hold on, hold on.
c09209
Delwath: That was, like, 30 feet of move?
c09210
Kenzo: Oh, yeah.
c09211
DM: Yeah.
c09212
Delwath: And I'm using my Raven's Whistle.
c09213
DM: Right.
c09214
Delwath: So my move is 120.
c09215
DM: Yeah, okay.
c09216
Delwath: I'm not bothering with minions, I'm going down here.
c09217
DM: Okay.
c09218
Delwath: Uh, I'll stand right next to Wellby, right down there.
c09219
Unknown: I'll
c09220
Unknown: move the,
c09221
Unknown: um-
c09222
DM: The mark to-
c09223
Delwath: The mark to that one.
c09224
DM: The, the
c09225
DM: glowing invisible essence thing?
c09226
Unknown: Yeah.
c09227
DM: Okay.
c09228
Delwath: And then I will attack it.
c09229
Unknown: Uh,
c09230
Delwath: that's a 22.
c09231
DM: That hits.
c09232
Unknown: I keep forgetting about Bless.
c09233
Delwath: 10, 14 plus 12, 26.
c09234
DM: That ends Delwath's turn.
c09235
Wellby: [gasps] Says Wellby, standing back up again.
c09236
Unknown: Woo-hoo.
c09237
Wellby: And, uh, and going right back to shooting.
c09238
DM: [laughs]
c09239
Wellby: No delay on that. Uh, well, so there's two of them.
c09240
Unknown: I'm gonna shoot them both.
c09241
Wellby: Uh, 20 on this guy.
c09242
DM: That hits.
c09243
Unknown: Yep. Yes.
c09244
Wellby: ... damage in
c09245
Wellby: 20,
c09246
Wellby: 30,
c09247
Wellby: 35 plus 8 is 43.
c09248
Wellby: Uh, then bonus action shoot the-
c09249
DM: On that one, yep
c09250
Wellby: ... other guy,
c09251
Wellby: which is a hit, 26.
c09252
Wellby: And much more damage than that guy.
c09253
Wellby: That is solid.
c09254
Wellby: Uh, 24, uh, 30,
c09255
Wellby: 40,
c09256
Wellby: 47 and 8 is 55.
c09257
Wellby: I think haste is no longer action- active-
c09258
DM: Yes
c09259
Wellby: ... without that.
c09260
DM: Yep.
c09261
Wellby: So that's the end of that.
c09262
DM: So that ends Wellby's turn.
c09263
DM: Triceratops.
c09264
Wellby: Triceratops.
c09265
Wellby: This is your round, buddy.
c09266
Wellby: Missing another thing.
c09267
Wellby: Oh, no.
c09268
DM: [laughs]
c09269
Wellby: No, that is a, that's a fail very much.
c09270
Delwath: Wait, how many... What's his minus up to?
c09271
Wellby: Uh, it's gonna be... He was at minus 6.
c09272
Wellby: This will be minus eight.
c09273
Unknown: Minus eight.
c09274
DM: Okay.
c09275
DM: So he has two more rounds before he dies, for example.
c09276
Delwath: I feel bad that mostly the only thing I've done is-
c09277
DM: No, you wiped out 20 minions
c09278
DM: ... I know. These were super useful. 24.
c09279
DM: All right. And the fourth... Oh, the one...
c09280
DM: Oh, but it didn't matter 'cause you killed it the next turn anyway.
c09281
Wellby: Triceratops at 13
c09282
Wellby: with a minus 8, so it's gonna be plus 1, compared with what's on the die.
c09283
Wellby: Attacks first one, then the other.
c09284
Wellby: That's an 8.
c09285
Wellby: That's an 18.
c09286
DM: Oh, sorry. W- what is first, first one?
c09287
DM: 18 hits the, the second guy.
c09288
Wellby: Yeah, that's the one he was attacking-
c09289
DM: [laughs]
c09290
Wellby: ... back then.
c09291
Unknown: Yeah.
c09292
Wellby: Yeah. Triceratops gotta do something.
c09293
Unknown: Yep.
c09294
Wellby: Uh-
c09295
Delwath: Got one hit in.
c09296
Wellby: That is 2D12 plus 6.
c09297
Wellby: Come on, Triceratops.
c09298
Wellby: That's-
c09299
Delwath: That's pretty good
c09300
Wellby: ... that's 28.
c09301
DM: Ooh.
c09302
Delwath: 28 damage on the misty guy.
c09303
Wellby: Why doesn't Triceratops-
c09304
Delwath: Oh, actually the sickening radiance helped with him too, made him visibly-
c09305
DM: Yeah.
c09306
Wellby: Triceratops comes through in the end.
c09307
DM: Oh, oh, oh, oh.
c09308
DM: Triceratops gets up.
c09309
Wellby: Mm.
c09310
DM: It's like, "I'm here."
c09311
Unknown: [laughs]
c09312
DM: "I'm gonna protect Wellby."
c09313
Wellby: [laughs]
c09314
DM: Charges straight through that thing and it just
c09315
DM: vanishes into a splattering of smoke behind it.
c09316
Unknown: And then he turns around and he looks, "I'm tired."
c09317
DM: [laughs]
c09318
Delwath: You can go back to stone soon, buddy.
c09319
DM: Uh-
c09320
DM: Wellby claps. He's so proud of you.
c09321
DM: Um, Wellby, make a constitution saving throw.
c09322
Unknown: Oh, come on.
c09323
Delwath: Your blood's gonna... [laughs]
c09324
Wellby: For what purpose? [laughs]
c09325
Unknown: To see if your blood-
c09326
DM: Your boiling blood
c09327
Unknown: ...
c09328
Wellby: heals. Uh, 15.
c09329
DM: Um,
c09330
DM: do you wanna take damage or do something else?
c09331
Wellby: I don't think there's anything else I can do.
c09332
Wellby: I don't have Bardic because-
c09333
Delwath: No, no, no, no, uh, do something else.
c09334
DM: Wait, can you give him a...
c09335
Delwath: Oh, no, you, you, too late.
c09336
DM: You don't have a Bard, do you have a Heroic?
c09337
Wellby: Nope.
c09338
DM: Okay, your blood boils.
c09339
Wellby: Oh, no. Oh, no.
c09340
Unknown: Oh, Wellby.
c09341
Wellby: Oh, no. Oh, no.
c09342
Wellby: Is, is that bad for me?
c09343
Unknown: [laughs]
c09344
Wellby: No. [laughs] No.
c09345
DM: Your-
c09346
Wellby: On the other hand, all combat we've wondered what happens-
c09347
DM: Your choices-
c09348
Unknown: ... if my boils
c09349
DM: ... are between-
c09350
Unknown: [laughs]
c09351
DM: ... 37 points of fire damage-
c09352
Wellby: Oh,
c09353
Wellby: yeah
c09354
DM: ... or, uh, attack Seeker.
c09355
Wellby: 37 points of fire damage-
c09356
Unknown: Yeah
c09357
Wellby: ... is fine.
c09358
Unknown: Yeah.
c09359
Wellby: You've still got that second level slot.
c09360
Delwath: I still have one more first level slot too.
c09361
Wellby: Yeah. Perfect. Down goes Wellby.
c09362
Wellby: [laughs]
c09363
DM: Oh my God.
c09364
Wellby: Oh, my God. Oh, oh, my blood.
c09365
Wellby: [laughs]
c09366
Delwath: [laughs] But unfortunately I can't cast it until, um, they get to attack, but that's okay.
c09367
DM: Uh,
c09368
DM: are, are you sure that's the choice that you want, given that it still has three attacks?
c09369
Seeker: I have full hit points.
c09370
Wellby: Oh, sure, I'll just attack you.
c09371
Wellby: That's fine.
c09372
Wellby: Uh,
c09373
Wellby: good. Um...
c09374
Unknown: [laughs]
c09375
Unknown: I mean, I'm not quite full.
c09376
Wellby: Do I get sneak attack because an ally is within five feet of-
c09377
Unknown: [laughs]
c09378
Delwath: No. When ally's within five feet.
c09379
Wellby: Seeker. [laughs]
c09380
Unknown: [laughs]
c09381
DM: Oh, you.
c09382
Wellby: No, I mean, of Seeker.
c09383
Wellby: Um, okay, here goes.
c09384
Wellby: That is, uh, 21.
c09385
Unknown: Yeah.
c09386
DM: That hits.
c09387
Wellby: Uh,
c09388
Wellby: that's just 1D6 plus 8.
c09389
DM: N- no, I think, I mean, the Triceratops is an ally of yours.
c09390
DM: I guess maybe it's not.
c09391
Wellby: I don't know if they're within five feet of Seeker.
c09392
Unknown: I don't know. Maybe.
c09393
DM: How big is the Triceratops?
c09394
DM: Is it large or is it huge?
c09395
Unknown: It just dramatically-
c09396
Wellby: It's giant scale
c09397
Unknown: ... charged forward to the wall
c09398
DM: ... it just charged this, you just described it.
c09399
Wellby: Yeah.
c09400
DM: Oh, that's right. Okay, fine.
c09401
Delwath: It's kind of lame. 11.
c09402
DM: 11 damage on Seeker.
c09403
Seeker: Dude, what, uh, oh, 'cause you didn't sneak attack.
c09404
Wellby: Yeah.
c09405
DM: Yeah, yeah.
c09406
Delwath: There's nobody to sneak around.
c09407
DM: I'm down to 156.
c09408
DM: I'm okay.
c09409
DM: Right. Really, what he should've done is this first,
c09410
DM: so that he was within Seeker.
c09411
DM: Right.
c09412
DM: So he's gonna throw a spear at you.
c09413
Wellby: At who? At me?
c09414
Unknown: Which one?
c09415
DM: At Wellby.
c09416
Delwath: Okay. He's mad you didn't kill Seeker.
c09417
DM: Exactly. Uh, that's a 29 to hit.
c09418
DM: That's 12 points of damage.
c09419
Wellby: Uh, uncanny dodge.
c09420
Delwath: [laughs] You have four hit points left.
c09421
Unknown: [laughs]
c09422
Wellby: I have four hit points.
c09423
DM: He's gonna throw another spear at you.
c09424
Wellby: It misses.
c09425
DM: No, that's a 30 to hit, and that's-
c09426
Delwath: Is it less, is it less than-
c09427
DM: ... 20 damage
c09428
Wellby: ...
c09429
Wellby: four hit points? [laughs]
c09430
Unknown: [laughs] And down again.
c09431
Wellby: Ah.
c09432
Unknown: Oh.
c09433
Unknown: [laughs] And down again.
c09434
Wellby: Charming.
c09435
DM: Um-
c09436
Unknown: [laughs]
c09437
Wellby: [laughs]
c09438
DM: And then
c09439
DM: just for good measure he'll stab you once more.
c09440
DM: So you fail a death saving throw.
c09441
Unknown: [laughs] This is pretty...
c09442
Unknown: This is, this is-
c09443
DM: He's kind of pissed off right now.
c09444
Wellby: But he's the only one left, right?
c09445
Delwath: Wait, did you make his sickening radiance roll?
c09446
DM: Uh, no, I forgot.
c09447
DM: Oh, for once he failed.
c09448
Kenzo: He's the only one left now, right?
c09449
DM: But he's immune to exhaustion. Yeah, he's the only one left.
c09450
Kenzo: We got it from here on-
c09451
DM: He keeps healing every time he hits somebody.
c09452
DM: That's why he's so difficult
c09453
Unknown: ...
c09454
Unknown: take 19 damage. You got this.
c09455
Unknown: You're up.
c09456
Delwath: I think, I think there's nobody...
c09457
Delwath: Oh, no, the minions.
c09458
DM: Uh, yeah, the minions are gonna come well on-
c09459
Delwath: Oh, wait. They did, like, 80 points of damage.
c09460
Unknown: Huh?
c09461
Unknown: Yeah.
c09462
DM: Kenzo.
c09463
Unknown: No, but now I've, now I've drank my...
c09464
Kenzo: Now I have the, uh...
c09465
Kenzo: I wasn't resistant to damage the first time.
c09466
DM: Now you're resistant.
c09467
Delwath: No, against the latter they did 80 points of damage.
c09468
Unknown: Oh, okay.
c09469
Delwath: I mean, you'll be fine if you take 80 points of damage.
c09470
Unknown: It's only 40. You'll be fine.
c09471
DM: So...
c09472
DM: Oh, but they rolled a o- a one.
c09473
Delwath: You take no damage.
c09474
DM: So you take no damage.
c09475
Unknown: Well...
c09476
DM: As the minions swarm around you.
c09477
Unknown: Kenzo laughs.
c09478
DM: Kenzo laughs and dodges out of the way of these little bits of cloud.
c09479
DM: What can they do?
c09480
Kenzo: Brushes them away with his massive staff.
c09481
DM: Okay, Seeker. [laughs]
c09482
Unknown: [laughs]
c09483
Unknown: It's like-
c09484
DM: It's like a broom-
c09485
Unknown: Right?
c09486
DM: -he's sweeping the air
c09487
Delwath: I guess the... I mean, I can take Wellby up again.
c09488
Unknown: That's fine.
c09489
Seeker: Uh, so I should just attack the guy.
c09490
Delwath: You should just cast a spell.
c09491
Seeker: What's his weakest, his weak stat again?
c09492
Delwath: I mean, yeah, no, it's fine, 'cause there's nothing-
c09493
DM: Uh, dex was his weak stat.
c09494
DM: Con is his strong stat.
c09495
Wellby: Bonus action to drink a potion, but action to administer a potion?
c09496
DM: Yes.
c09497
Unknown: Okay.
c09498
Unknown: Um,
c09499
Seeker: I can banish him.
c09500
Unknown: Hi.
c09501
Seeker: Catapult, Erupting Earth.
c09502
Delwath: Do you have, uh-
c09503
Seeker: Telekinesis. Oh, it's a strength save.
c09504
Unknown: No
c09505
DM: I mean, dex is his lo- is his worst
c09506
Delwath: I mean, is there, is there-
c09507
DM: Catapult is dex
c09508
Delwath: ... besides throwing another chain lightning?
c09509
DM: Just uses up all your-
c09510
Kenzo: Uh, I don't... Yeah, I-
c09511
Delwath: You only have an eighth level slot left.
c09512
Unknown: Yeah.
c09513
Unknown: Maybe you should save that.
c09514
Delwath: Yeah. So Catapult for-
c09515
DM: Um-
c09516
Unknown: I don't-
c09517
DM: By the way
c09518
Unknown: ... just in case.
c09519
Delwath: Teleport?
c09520
DM: You notice that the, um,
c09521
DM: the floor is beginning to shake-
c09522
Unknown: Oh
c09523
DM: ... and there's mud spots appearing.
c09524
Kenzo: So this is gonna be like we have to, like, get out of here and do the Abaddon thing later.
c09525
DM: Yeah, there's some bad things are happening.
c09526
Unknown: Where is the... Which, which-
c09527
Unknown: Where is the thing that we-
c09528
Unknown: Where is the thing?
c09529
Kenzo: Yeah. Where's the artifact? Do we see an artifact in the room anywhere?
c09530
DM: Nope.
c09531
Delwath: Yeah, okay, we better finish this fast.
c09532
Unknown: Yeah, yeah,
c09533
Unknown: yeah. Um,
c09534
Seeker: so 5d 12 is better than 7d 8
c09535
Unknown: by a little bit.
c09536
Delwath: Marginally. Yeah. It's that catapult?
c09537
Seeker: Uh, Erupting Earth-
c09538
Unknown: Okay
c09539
Seeker: ... is slightly better. So I cast Erupting Earth.
c09540
Seeker: That's a dex save DC 19.
c09541
Unknown: Yeah.
c09542
DM: Okay. Um, sorry, I'm just seeing what it turns into.
c09543
DM: Okay. Ooh, that's gonna be bad for you.
c09544
DM: Okay.
c09545
DM: Uh-
c09546
Unknown: [laughs]
c09547
DM: But this is gonna be bad for him.
c09548
DM: Oh, no, he rolled a 19.
c09549
DM: So he takes half damage.
c09550
Seeker: Um, yeah, so I'll just do the...
c09551
Unknown: Divide it.
c09552
DM: N- no, with D12, you should roll all of them and divide by two, 'cause D12s are really high variance.
c09553
Unknown: Yes.
c09554
Seeker: Um, and I don't have an easy way to do that on here.
c09555
Unknown: Or do I?
c09556
Unknown: Just roll five D12s.
c09557
DM: Just roll five D12 and divide by two.
c09558
DM: Y- you might still kill him.
c09559
Unknown: Okay. Then-
c09560
Delwath: Just click the little die and then pick the D12s and type five of them
c09561
Seeker: ... oh, I can use this thing for D12.
c09562
DM: I mean, Kenzo can easily kill half those minions.
c09563
Seeker: Yeah. That's a 28. Divided by two is 14.
c09564
DM: Ah, okay, that doesn't kill him.
c09565
Unknown: Which is fine.
c09566
DM: But it almost kills him.
c09567
Delwath: Uh, ooh. Kenzo,
c09568
Delwath: kill the minions.
c09569
Unknown: All right.
c09570
Unknown: [phone notification pings]
c09571
Delwath: Wait, you can finally bonus...
c09572
Delwath: Oh, no, you should not.
c09573
Kenzo: Yeah. No, it's n- no.
c09574
DM: There's no point at this s- stage.
c09575
Kenzo: Oh, I critted.
c09576
DM: Oh, yeah. Okay.
c09577
Unknown: That does something.
c09578
DM: So that could kill multiples.
c09579
Unknown: How does that work?
c09580
Delwath: But also a two misses, right?
c09581
DM: Not these minions.
c09582
Unknown: Ah.
c09583
DM: Uh, what's...
c09584
DM: With the staff it's plus 14 or plus 13
c09585
Unknown: Plus 13.
c09586
Unknown: Yeah.
c09587
DM: They have a for- they have a 15 AC.
c09588
Unknown: Oh, so you hit.
c09589
Unknown: Oh, wow. Holy fuck.
c09590
Delwath: So roll your damage. So roll 2d 12 plus 7
c09591
Unknown: for the crit.
c09592
Kenzo: Oh, for just for the crit.
c09593
Delwath: Yeah, 'cause that just kills one.
c09594
Kenzo: Uh, 8.
c09595
Kenzo: 16 plus 7 is 23.
c09596
DM: That kills two.
c09597
DM: Each one has 20 hit points, so if you do more than 20 hit points, you carry over the effect to the next one.
c09598
Kenzo: Okay. And then the, the other one, which-
c09599
DM: Kills one more
c09600
Delwath: I took one away already.
c09601
Unknown: Yeah. But now I have-
c09602
Delwath: You don't have to roll damage.
c09603
Delwath: Minions die when you hit them.
c09604
Kenzo: I know, but I have to roll damage for the second attack.
c09605
Delwath: No, no. Minions die when you hit them.
c09606
Kenzo: Oh, so, so I, I roll... So I kill three.
c09607
Delwath: You killed three with your first two attacks.
c09608
Unknown: I killed three, not four. Right. Perfect. Okay. So now I, now I-
c09609
Unknown: Now you have three more attacks.
c09610
Unknown: Yeah.
c09611
DM: There's no reason to roll damage unless you crit.
c09612
DM: Basically, unless you roll a one or a 20-
c09613
Unknown: No
c09614
Delwath: ... that misses, but you kill two more.
c09615
Kenzo: Two more, okay. All right. So five.
c09616
Unknown: And now-
c09617
DM: So that ends Kenzo's turn. Dalwath is up.
c09618
Delwath: All right. I gotta fight this guy
c09619
Unknown: to start.
c09620
Delwath: I'm going to attack him.
c09621
DM: Yeah.
c09622
DM: Uh, sorry, at the beginning of the round, the ceiling collapses
c09623
DM: and begins to rain-
c09624
Delwath: Oh, wait. First I'm gonna bonus action heal-
c09625
DM: Okay
c09626
Unknown: ... what I can.
c09627
DM: Wow, this is bef- this is at the beginning of the round before you act.
c09628
Delwath: Yeah, this is good. This is good.
c09629
Unknown: It's good.
c09630
Unknown: Yeah.
c09631
Unknown: That-
c09632
Wellby: Otherwise I would immediately go down again.
c09633
Unknown: [laughs]
c09634
DM: It, uh, the ceiling collapses and begins to rain down.
c09635
DM: The door, the door is still there, but the rest of the ceiling collapses and begins to rain iron spikes down on you.
c09636
DM: Um, everybody,
c09637
DM: uh, takes 1d6 piercing damage every single...
c09638
DM: at the start of every single round.
c09639
DM: So that's three points each.
c09640
Kenzo: So for me it's me and-
c09641
DM: But this is every six seconds you take three points.
c09642
Unknown: Right.
c09643
DM: You take D6 piercing damage.
c09644
Unknown: But he takes half, right?
c09645
DM: You take one each, you take three, you fail a death save.
c09646
DM: Now Dalwath's turn.
c09647
Wellby: So your bonus action, you're healing me first, right?
c09648
Unknown: Yeah. Yes.
c09649
Wellby: What do... What do I get out of that?
c09650
Delwath: 2d, 2d 4 plus 5.
c09651
Unknown: Awesome.
c09652
Unknown: 3, 8.
c09653
Wellby: Okay. Okay
c09654
Wellby: [gasps] Says Wellby
c09655
Unknown: Okay. [laughs]
c09656
DM: [laughs]
c09657
Delwath: For a second time.
c09658
Unknown: Uh-
c09659
DM: Oh my God
c09660
Unknown: ...
c09661
Delwath: 7 plus 4 plus 12.
c09662
Unknown: Uh-
c09663
DM: 19?
c09664
Delwath: 7 plus 4 plus 12 is a lot more than 19.
c09665
DM: Okay.
c09666
Unknown: It's, it's-
c09667
DM: 11 plus-
c09668
Unknown: ... 23.
c09669
DM: That hits.
c09670
Unknown: Hey.
c09671
Unknown: 10,
c09672
Delwath: uh, plus 8, 30.
c09673
DM: Um, falls down to one knee, like looking at the ceiling up.
c09674
Unknown: Ah, I missed.
c09675
DM: Do you have one more attack?
c09676
Delwath: I do. [laughs] That might miss.
c09677
Delwath: Man, I should've used the mecha- oh, wait, does he only have...
c09678
Unknown: Yeah.
c09679
DM: You can use... Yeah.
c09680
Unknown: Can I use mechas?
c09681
DM: Well, it's kind of cheating 'cause you saw you rolled a 3.
c09682
Delwath: No, but I mean I meant to if he only had a few hit points left.
c09683
Delwath: After I rolled the one.
c09684
Unknown: 4.
c09685
Delwath: Uh, a 16 wouldn't hit, would it?
c09686
DM: Nope.
c09687
DM: Do you have a rock?
c09688
Unknown: I used it.
c09689
DM: Yeah.
c09690
Delwath: I used everything. Mm.
c09691
DM: That ends Delwath's turn.
c09692
DM: Wellby?
c09693
Unknown: Kill this fucking guy.
c09694
DM: [laughs]
c09695
Wellby: All right. Now I'm going to
c09696
DM: Um-
c09697
Unknown: Wait, do I need to kill it?
c09698
DM: Uh, yeah
c09699
Unknown: What, what, what else is in the room?
c09700
Delwath: We should just kill this guy.
c09701
Unknown: Okay. I mean, this guy as well.
c09702
Wellby: I'm gonna drink my potion of, ahem, greater healing.
c09703
Unknown: [laughs]
c09704
DM: [laughs]
c09705
Unknown: [laughs]
c09706
Wellby: Uh, 4, 7, 8, 9, 13.
c09707
DM: Oof. Yeah, doing good.
c09708
Kenzo: How'd that feel?
c09709
Wellby: Feels real good. Uh, and then I'm gonna shoot this guy and kill him, hopefully.
c09710
DM: But probably not.
c09711
Unknown: You shot a 3?
c09712
DM: Yeah.
c09713
Unknown: That's a miss.
c09714
DM: 17. That misses.
c09715
Wellby: Ah, that's extremely disappointing.
c09716
Seeker: It's understandable you're having difficulty, Wellby.
c09717
Seeker: You've been dead twice today.
c09718
DM: [laughs]
c09719
Delwath: At the very end of this-
c09720
Unknown: Sort of went around the block
c09721
Delwath: ... we rolled like a 1, a 3, and a 3
c09722
DM: [laughs] You were doing so well.
c09723
DM: Um-
c09724
Unknown: You have a second attack, right?
c09725
Unknown: No.
c09726
Unknown: Damn it.
c09727
Wellby: 'Cause I don't have, uh, haste up anymore.
c09728
DM: Yeah.
c09729
Unknown: You've only ever had one attack.
c09730
Unknown: 'Cause I died two or three times.
c09731
Delwath: Yeah. Wellby recently got a bonus action.
c09732
DM: The second attack is a bonus action, but you used the bonus action to drink a potion.
c09733
Unknown: Oh.
c09734
DM: Um...
c09735
Delwath: Man, that means this is gonna get an attack in.
c09736
DM: Now make a con-
c09737
Unknown: Yeah
c09738
DM: ... now he's right next to Seeker, so make a con save.
c09739
Unknown: Who's making a con save?
c09740
DM: You.
c09741
Unknown: He's making... He-
c09742
DM: He wants you to actually attack Seeker for real, so he's standing next to Seeker, so you have to use sneak attack if you fail your con save.
c09743
Wellby: Why is this a thing that's happening to me right now?
c09744
DM: 'Cause it's the-
c09745
Unknown: [laughs] It's my turn
c09746
DM: ... it's his turn [laughs]. He's boil-
c09747
Unknown: It's my turn. It's the triceratops's turn.
c09748
DM: Oh, you're right. It's the triceratops's turn.
c09749
Unknown: Oh.
c09750
DM: Maybe the triceratops can kill him.
c09751
Unknown: Wellby's gonna move-
c09752
Unknown: You know what?
c09753
Wellby: ... at the end of his turn to be over with his buddy, the triceratops.
c09754
DM: Well, he's gonna get an opportunity attack if you move.
c09755
Wellby: Uh, no, 'cause I cunning actioned his reach.
c09756
DM: No, you don't 'cause you used a bonus action on your potion.
c09757
Wellby: If I'm here and he's there, it is 10 feet-
c09758
DM: He has a 10-foot reach.
c09759
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c09760
Wellby: There's 10 feet between us, so-
c09761
DM: Well, he was attacking you from there before, so he must have been one step closer.
c09762
Unknown: Oh, all right. All right.
c09763
Unknown: Okay, cool.
c09764
DM: His spears have a 10-foot reach or a 60-foot throw, but he had stepped within combat of you, so.
c09765
Delwath: Maybe he'll fail the sickening radiance.
c09766
Wellby: All right, triceratops. This is-
c09767
Unknown: I mean-
c09768
DM: Finish him
c09769
Delwath: ... he might... The triceratops might die.
c09770
Wellby: No, there's no chance this is gonna survive.
c09771
Wellby: It is a minus 8. [laughs] It is 2.
c09772
DM: [laughs]
c09773
Kenzo: It's almost the highest I've rolled.
c09774
Unknown: [laughs]
c09775
DM: [laughs]
c09776
Unknown: It is, is-
c09777
DM: Oh, but if this guy fails the sickening radiance, then...
c09778
DM: What?
c09779
Delwath: It's 24 points of damage.
c09780
Wellby: Oh, the triceratops becomes a little statue-
c09781
DM: Done
c09782
Wellby: ... once again.
c09783
DM: Um, if this guy fails the sickening radiance, he's, he's almost certainly dead.
c09784
Unknown: Yeah.
c09785
DM: So he's got a plus 12.
c09786
Delwath: 19, that's a failure.
c09787
DM: He failed.
c09788
Unknown: Hey.
c09789
Unknown: Oh my God.
c09790
Seeker: Is the sickening radiance the, the single thing that did the most damage today?
c09791
Unknown: 33 damage. Yeah, that kills him.
c09792
Unknown: Oh, thank God.
c09793
Wellby: Oh, finally.
c09794
Delwath: Wow. The sickening radiance mostly...
c09795
Delwath: We still have the minions, but I assume they just kind of...
c09796
DM: Ah, Kenzo's just gonna kill those minions.
c09797
Kenzo: Just mop them up, yeah.
c09798
Unknown: Yeah.
c09799
DM: Kenzo mops up the minions.
c09800
Unknown: Yeah.
c09801
Delwath: Um, what becomes of the triceratops?
c09802
Unknown: Is it-
c09803
Delwath: The sickening radiance has done...
c09804
Delwath: did a lot of damage, but mostly it killed all the minions.
c09805
DM: It, it eliminated 17 out of the 20 minions.
c09806
Unknown: 17, 17 points of damage to the triceratops.
c09807
DM: And it did a lot of damage to the triceratops.
c09808
Unknown: It did, really.
c09809
Unknown: But there was a few that-
c09810
Wellby: Actually, I think that is the... Is that the only thing the triceratops-
c09811
Unknown: Yeah
c09812
Unknown: ... took damage from?
c09813
Unknown: Yeah.
c09814
DM: Yes.
c09815
Unknown: Guys-
c09816
Unknown: But yeah
c09817
Kenzo: ... that combat, I think, was like-
c09818
Unknown: 212 points of damage
c09819
Kenzo: ... five hours long.
c09820
Unknown: No, it's just after midnight.
c09821
Unknown: No, it's been a-
c09822
Unknown: We were eating dinner like three hours ago.
c09823
Delwath: No, no, no, no, no. That's when we entered the tower.
c09824
Unknown: It was 10.
c09825
DM: The tower took five hours.
c09826
Unknown: Okay.
c09827
DM: It was like 10:30 when we started this combat.
c09828
Unknown: Oh, okay, okay. Oh, that's right, that's right.
c09829
DM: It actually went faster than the Empress of Chaos combat.
c09830
Seeker: Yeah. Oof. I, I took-
c09831
Unknown: Seeker took like 300 damage
c09832
Unknown: ... 200, almost 300 damage.
c09833
Unknown: I don't play it.
c09834
Kenzo: I took 200.
c09835
Unknown: He died, so I get-
c09836
DM: [laughs] Really? Holy shit
c09837
Unknown: ... 20 went back.
c09838
Kenzo: Yeah.
c09839
Unknown: You died twice.
c09840
Wellby: And then I only have 156.
c09841
DM: Okay.
c09842
Unknown: [laughs]
c09843
DM: But at, but at the moment there's-
c09844
Delwath: Okay, we have some problems
c09845
DM: ... needle steel raining down on you.
c09846
DM: The floor is collapsing, but there's still a door somehow suspended in the ceiling.
c09847
Delwath: I, I'm flying up.
c09848
Unknown: Well, shit, I'm, I'm under it.
c09849
Unknown: I'm, I'm on the air right now. I'm, I'm above the door.
c09850
Wellby: I'm gonna grab onto you.
c09851
Delwath: I can't... I, I, I can carry like four tons.
c09852
DM: You're, you're, you're, you fall to the ground.
c09853
Kenzo: Oh, fuck. Okay.
c09854
DM: Well, actually no, the gravity e- sorry, gravity ends, so you're just floating in space.
c09855
Unknown: Oh, perfect.
c09856
Unknown: You can walk.
c09857
Kenzo: Oh, good.
c09858
DM: There's no grav-
c09859
Unknown: I'll take it
c09860
DM: ... 'cause she's dead, so there's no gravity anymore.
c09861
DM: But it's all collapsing.
c09862
Kenzo: Where, where-
c09863
Delwath: Detect magic.
c09864
DM: Um,
c09865
DM: the door is magical.
c09866
Unknown: I'm gonna-
c09867
DM: Who's looking at the door?
c09868
Kenzo: I'm going up to the-
c09869
DM: Which side of the door?
c09870
Delwath: I'm taking the door.
c09871
DM: Can't... The door won't move.
c09872
Wellby: Wait, wait, wait. The door is open or closed?
c09873
DM: The door is open right now.
c09874
DM: You are-
c09875
Delwath: Wait, but is it set? What is it attached to?
c09876
Kenzo: Look, look, look, look. We dropped down through the door.
c09877
DM: It just cannot move.
c09878
Delwath: Oh. It's, it's not attached to anything.
c09879
DM: It's not attached to anything.
c09880
Kenzo: We came in, we came in through the door.
c09881
Kenzo: I think if we go up this way, it's not gonna be the same thing
c09882
DM: I think the door is the artifact
c09883
Wellby: You're already on the other side of the door
c09884
DM: You're already on the other side of the door
c09885
Kenzo: Well, I'm just up above it
c09886
Unknown: But I could go under it, then go up
c09887
Wellby: Door, door with goggles
c09888
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah goggles
c09889
Wellby: Maybe the door goes to multiple locations
c09890
Kenzo: That's what I'm saying
c09891
DM: Door with goggles. Arcana check
c09892
Seeker: Arcana check
c09893
DM: That's my play
c09894
Kenzo: That's, uh-
c09895
Unknown: 29
c09896
Unknown: ... 30
c09897
DM: Um, everybody takes another
c09898
DM: three points of piercing damage
c09899
Wellby: What is the healing situation here?
c09900
DM: Um-
c09901
Unknown: Eh
c09902
DM: ... the door, in fact-
c09903
Delwath: I don't really have a lot of spell left
c09904
DM: ... has a, has a, um, like, a-
c09905
Kenzo: I give, I give you, I give you a potion of, uh-
c09906
DM: Do we-
c09907
Unknown: ... of, uh-
c09908
Wellby: Greater healing?
c09909
Unknown: Superior healing
c09910
Delwath: Do we have a minute?
c09911
DM: So we take 10-
c09912
Unknown: I think-
c09913
DM: You take 10 D6-
c09914
Kenzo: 10 D4 plus 20
c09915
DM: ... damage for a minute
c09916
Wellby: Do you have that if you took haste, though?
c09917
Kenzo: I, I didn't take haste
c09918
DM: He had a superior healing-
c09919
Unknown: Oh, no. I had a-
c09920
DM: He had one already from before
c09921
Unknown: Yeah
c09922
DM: So-
c09923
Wellby: Awesome. How many was it? 10 D4 plus 20
c09924
Kenzo: 10 D4 plus 20
c09925
DM: Seeker, looking at the door through the goggles-
c09926
Delwath: Oh, wait. It's an action to get back a spell slot with my rod
c09927
DM: That's true
c09928
Delwath: I'm getting back a spell slot
c09929
DM: Okay.
c09930
DM: Seeker, looking at the, through the door, you see there's, like, a knob you can turn and it points in t- there's two different directions it can point-
c09931
Unknown: Got it
c09932
DM: ... on the bottom of the door
c09933
Seeker: You're welcome The bottom meaning the side facing us or the-
c09934
DM: The side facing down
c09935
Seeker: Yeah. And-
c09936
DM: Like the door, the door swings down like this
c09937
Unknown: Mm-hmm
c09938
DM: And at, on the sort of no- knob at the, at the
c09939
DM: hinge point-
c09940
Unknown: Ow!
c09941
DM: ... there's a-
c09942
Unknown: Are you okay now?
c09943
DM: ... switch you can turn-
c09944
Unknown: Yes
c09945
DM: ... that changes, that-
c09946
Delwath: I forgot I could do that
c09947
DM: ... point- it's like pointing at one rune, and you turn it and it points at a different one
c09948
Seeker: Well, what do the runes say?
c09949
DM: Well, you can't... They're, they're not really-
c09950
Unknown: Oh, I'm out of spell slots
c09951
DM: ... I, I wouldn't say they're really runes.
c09952
DM: They're just, like, um, chaotic patterns
c09953
Unknown: Well-
c09954
Unknown: But there's only two options, right?
c09955
DM: There's only two options
c09956
Unknown: Switch to the other option
c09957
Seeker: I s- okay
c09958
DM: Switch it
c09959
Seeker: I mage hand, I guess, and switch it
c09960
DM: Okay.
c09961
DM: And then what?
c09962
Seeker: Is the doors open right now?
c09963
DM: Yeah
c09964
Seeker: Should we close it and reopen it?
c09965
DM: Yeah
c09966
Wellby: Yeah
c09967
Seeker: All right. Mage hand close it, mage hand reopen it
c09968
DM: Uh, you are looking up into a, um, clear crystal globe filled with a pale yellowish light.
c09969
DM: It is going to a different place than it went to before
c09970
Seeker: That looks like a better place than where we are now, which is being repeatedly stabbed, so I-
c09971
DM: So you all take another
c09972
DM: three points of piercing damage
c09973
Kenzo: Was that one or two for us?
c09974
DM: Uh, one for you.
c09975
DM: But your potion's gonna end pretty soon-
c09976
Unknown: My-
c09977
DM: ... because it only lasts for a minute
c09978
Delwath: Yeah, it's probably just-
c09979
Unknown: I don't have a potion
c09980
DM: Oh, yours lasts for-
c09981
Wellby: Yeah
c09982
DM: ... no, yours still also only lasts for a minute
c09983
Unknown: Oh, no
c09984
Unknown: Is it magic?
c09985
DM: The door is magic, yes
c09986
Unknown: The globe of light magic?
c09987
DM: No, it's like a room that's filled with a globe
c09988
Delwath: I think we should go in it. It seems safer than anywhere else, right?
c09989
Wellby: Well, in we go
c09990
Unknown: What are we waiting for?
c09991
DM: Okay
c09992
Seeker: We go in
c09993
DM: You go in
c09994
Wellby: You hold that
c09995
DM: Um, no. No, no, no, no, no.
c09996
DM: Um, you are in a...
c09997
DM: Wait, where did I put my notes?
c09998
DM: Uh, you see,
c09999
DM: um,
c10000
Unknown: Oh, yeah. Go for
c10001
DM: you see,
c10002
DM: um,
c10003
DM: a,
c10004
DM: uh, floating...
c10005
DM: Like, you're now in this globe.
c10006
DM: Like, the metal rain is falling around you.
c10007
DM: Everything is, um...
c10008
DM: But this seems to be, like, a permanent sphere of stability.
c10009
DM: Um,
c10010
DM: there are four tables
c10011
DM: floating in spa- floating in this space.
c10012
DM: There's no f- it's like a big glass circle.
c10013
DM: There's no floor, but about halfway up there's, like, four tables floating in the sort of midpoint.
c10014
DM: Um, each, they're small.
c10015
DM: They're, like, almost more like footstools.
c10016
DM: They're, like, the size of, like, low down like that sort of table, not like big tables like this.
c10017
DM: Um, on one of them there is a scimitar
c10018
DM: on which black flames are dancing,
c10019
DM: putting out darkness.
c10020
DM: Another one has a plain leather bag.
c10021
DM: Um, another one has a strange black, gray, reddish orb that has incredibly dense
c10022
DM: little runic,
c10023
DM: uh, words on it that spiral in all sorts of directions
c10024
Kenzo: That might be the thing
c10025
DM: And, um, the other has a, uh,
c10026
DM: a scroll, just, like, a spell scroll
c10027
Delwath: It's like an almost, like a,
c10028
Unknown: like a magic scroll?
c10029
DM: I mean, it looks like just a magic scroll
c10030
Delwath: I mean, I'm detecting magic
c10031
DM: Uh, yes, all, all four of these things are magic
c10032
Unknown: Wait
c10033
DM: The leather bag, the scroll, the relic thing, and the scimitar
c10034
Unknown: Did you want some more tea?
c10035
Seeker: Well, the relic seems villainous
c10036
DM: Yes
c10037
Delwath: Um, I was gonna run the dishwasher 'cause we're not doing-
c10038
DM: Yes, great idea
c10039
Unknown: ... do you have any other-
c10040
DM: Here, I'll just reuse this mug.
c10041
DM: Come
c10042
Delwath: Uh, okay. I'm just gonna
c10043
DM: So what are you taking?
c10044
DM: What are you doing?
c10045
DM: You can see the, the relic thing is sort of expanding and contracting and expanding and contracting
c10046
Seeker: Everything else is so distracting, but I will, uh, investigate the relic with my goggles
c10047
DM: Okay.
c10048
DM: Uh-
c10049
Seeker: But I'm not, like, reading reading through it.
c10050
Seeker: I'm just looking at it
c10051
DM: Okay. Ma- make a, make an arcana check
c10052
Unknown: Oh,
c10053
Unknown: 21
c10054
DM: 21 total?
c10055
Unknown: 21 total.
c10056
DM: Oh, that's not that high.
c10057
Wellby: No, I rolled a four.
c10058
Unknown: [coughs]
c10059
DM: It's gonna take a little bit more time for you, or more
c10060
DM: care. Uh, well, how much time are you willing to spend?
c10061
DM: You're pretty sure that with, like, 10 or 15 minutes you could, you could figure it out.
c10062
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c10063
DM: Um, whether you wanna spend 10 or 15 minutes right now, you're not sure.
c10064
Unknown: I'm sending a,
c10065
Delwath: Winks to Rai right away.
c10066
DM: Okay.
c10067
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c10068
DM: Um,
c10069
DM: the-
c10070
Seeker: [laughs] Right, good thing you remembered
c10071
DM: ... I... You can see actually around you that the, the sort of, the tower is completely collapsed now, and the ash is beginning to sort of blow off-
c10072
Unknown: Wait, wait, wait, wait
c10073
DM: ... into a storm.
c10074
Kenzo: And, and, uh, b- b- uh, I, uh, Kenzo before the battle ended grabbed a handful of the, uh-
c10075
DM: The dust
c10076
Kenzo: ... the, the ash of the lamp-
c10077
DM: Yeah, yeah
c10078
Kenzo: ... that I was fucking-
c10079
DM: No, I know. You said you wanted to do that.
c10080
Unknown: Yeah. Wait, what?
c10081
Unknown: Oh, in the mirror.
c10082
DM: Look in the mirror.
c10083
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
c10084
Unknown: Good call. [yawns] Um,
c10085
Unknown: should I do identify on it?
c10086
Delwath: So there's a... Hold on. There's a scroll, a weird-
c10087
Unknown: A bag.
c10088
DM: A bag.
c10089
Unknown: A bag.
c10090
Unknown: And a scimitar.
c10091
Delwath: A scimitar.
c10092
DM: A scimitar and the rock.
c10093
Unknown: The relic.
c10094
Unknown: So-
c10095
DM: You could do identify. Only takes a minute
c10096
Delwath: ... we put the scimitar, and the scroll, and the relic in the bag and we leave.
c10097
Unknown: It's gotta be that simple, right?
c10098
Delwath: I'm joking. We don't do that.
c10099
Unknown: I will, um-
c10100
DM: The bag is small. It's only about this big.
c10101
Seeker: I will do identify on the relic.
c10102
DM: Okay.
c10103
DM: So Seeker spends a minute.
c10104
Delwath: Wait, if we're taking a minute I'm getting back two more spell slots.
c10105
DM: Okay.
c10106
Unknown: Good.
c10107
DM: Anybody else wanna do anything in the one minute you have?
c10108
Wellby: Is there anything else in the room? I'll investigate the rest of the room just in case.
c10109
DM: Nothing else in the room.
c10110
Kenzo: Uh, can I still check something with the elf thing?
c10111
Unknown: [clears throat]
c10112
DM: With the what?
c10113
Unknown: With the elf...
c10114
Unknown: The forest. The tree.
c10115
DM: Oh, um,
c10116
DM: uh, a few hours seem to have passed.
c10117
Unknown: Okay.
c10118
Unknown: Um,
c10119
Delwath: I'm gonna ask the Taunshe.
c10120
Wellby: Well, that's a good idea.
c10121
Delwath: Some questions.
c10122
DM: Okay.
c10123
Wellby: Yeah. That's good.
c10124
Delwath: Why not, right?
c10125
DM: Yeah. So let me say what Seeker learns from identify.
c10126
Unknown: Yeah.
c10127
DM: Okay, so this is
c10128
DM: a
c10129
DM: artifact precipitated out of the material plane when it and Limbo mixed.
c10130
DM: The basic use is an informationally hyperdense arcane formula.
c10131
DM: The basic use of which is,
c10132
DM: um, to stabilize planar positions,
c10133
DM: create, uh, islands of stability in chao- in Limbo.
c10134
DM: The more advanced use can actually shift planes.
c10135
DM: This requires a one-hour ritual.
c10136
DM: Uh, somebody has to read the, the scrolls as you conduct the ritual.
c10137
DM: At the ritual's culmination, the sphere is destroyed,
c10138
DM: um, and whoever reads the rolls has to make a DC40 intelligence arcana check.
c10139
DM: However, you can improve your check by
c10140
DM: you and up to two other partic- um, people can expend spell slots-
c10141
Unknown: Right
c10142
DM: ... to help you
c10143
DM: beat the check, and you get a bonus to the check equal to the combined level of the spell slots expended.
c10144
Unknown: Dude, Rai got a level up.
c10145
Unknown: Oh, I like that-
c10146
Kenzo: 'Cause now Rai doesn't have to do the balancing act thing anymore, right?
c10147
Unknown: [clears throat]
c10148
Delwath: Can you just expend one spell slot,
c10149
Unknown: or as many as you want?
c10150
DM: Uh, up to three people can each expend one spell slot.
c10151
DM: But you get-
c10152
Unknown: And you got
c10153
Unknown: not Seeker.
c10154
Unknown: Including me.
c10155
DM: Including Seeker.
c10156
Seeker: But my highest spell slot is probably fifth, right?
c10157
Delwath: Eight. You didn't use your eighth.
c10158
Seeker: [clears throat] You're right.
c10159
Seeker: How did you keep track of that?
c10160
Unknown: I have no idea.
c10161
Delwath: 'Cause I told you to use it to cast chain lightning, and you said, "No, I wanna save it."
c10162
Unknown: [laughs]
c10163
Seeker: Oh, okay. Well, good thing it did.
c10164
Delwath: [laughs] Or maybe Tim said, "Maybe you should save it."
c10165
Unknown: [laughs]
c10166
Unknown: DC 40 is-
c10167
DM: No, I didn't say anything
c10168
Unknown: ... it's hard.
c10169
Unknown: Um-
c10170
DM: See, that's why you should've saved your insp- Wait, did you save your inspiration?
c10171
Unknown: Actually, I did.
c10172
DM: You did save your inspiration.
c10173
Seeker: So I have a D12, I have my plus 17.
c10174
Delwath: And wait, you have... It's not...
c10175
Delwath: No, hold on, DC 40, but if you take eight and Delwath takes five, that spells a five slot.
c10176
Delwath: That's 13 plus 17 is 30.
c10177
Unknown: Yeah.
c10178
Delwath: So it's a DC, you have to roll a 10 or better.
c10179
Unknown: Right.
c10180
Unknown: It's 50/50.
c10181
Unknown: And then I have inspiration.
c10182
Delwath: But with inspiration-
c10183
DM: However, if you fail, your mind is disintegrated and wiped across the entire-
c10184
Delwath: Right. So you need a, you need a mechanism to get advantage.
c10185
Seeker: Does anybody else have a-
c10186
Unknown: How do we do that?
c10187
DM: Uh-uh.
c10188
Wellby: When we rest before... Um, why don't we go back to where Rai is-
c10189
Delwath: Wait, it's an arcana check?
c10190
Unknown: ... and we rest.
c10191
Delwath: Doesn't Seeker get advantage on arcana checks?
c10192
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah. It's an arcana check.
c10193
Unknown: Whoa.
c10194
DM: You just wear your goggles, and then you have advantage.
c10195
Seeker: Okay. [laughs] So I roll twice.
c10196
Unknown: Dude, this is fucking easy.
c10197
Delwath: So what's the statistics? You have to roll-
c10198
Unknown: So confident.
c10199
Kenzo: What, what's the, what's the-
c10200
Unknown: What statistics?
c10201
Delwath: You have to roll a nine or better 'cause you c- get a minimum of a one on the bardic.
c10202
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
c10203
Delwath: If we take a short rest, if we felt like we take a short rest, you could get, I'd give you a heroic.
c10204
Seeker: Actually, I still have a heroic.
c10205
Delwath: Ah, there you go. You have three rolls.
c10206
Unknown: I- this is so-
c10207
Unknown: So-
c10208
Seeker: What are we even doing here? Why, why, why are we doing this?
c10209
Wellby: Why don't we go back to Rai with this?
c10210
DM: Well, you, you can't rest here.
c10211
Unknown: Right.
c10212
DM: It is the, uh...
c10213
DM: This entire region of Limbo is rapidly collapsing-
c10214
Unknown: I guess we have to take-
c10215
DM: ... into utter chaos.
c10216
Delwath: We have to, we have to... Well, we already sent the-
c10217
Unknown: Yeah
c10218
Delwath: ... Winks to-
c10219
DM: Yes
c10220
Unknown: ... get Rai.
c10221
Wellby: What are the other three things?
c10222
DM: Uh, Seeker can only cast identify once.
c10223
Unknown: Yep. So we take them. We take everything.
c10224
DM: So you have to rest before you can do it again.
c10225
Kenzo: We take everything, right?
c10226
Wellby: Right?
c10227
Unknown: Yeah.
c10228
Unknown: Are they-
c10229
DM: Could just take everything. All of them are magic
c10230
Delwath: ... are they, they're not like...
c10231
Delwath: Is this like a treasure room or a trap room?
c10232
DM: [laughs] I don't know, you tell me.
c10233
Delwath: I, I check for traps.
c10234
Unknown: Does it, does it-
c10235
DM: [coughs]
c10236
Delwath: Does it... I mean, are they like... No, what I, what I mean is like, are these like carefully displayed on a ped- does it like have the look of like
c10237
Unknown: they're like-
c10238
Wellby: Give me more light
c10239
Delwath: ... we've seen lots of like dragon treasure, like-
c10240
DM: I mean, it's not. Like, it's more...
c10241
DM: Yes, it's not set up, yes.
c10242
DM: It's more-
c10243
Delwath: It, it looks like they're displayed
c10244
DM: ... yes. Yeah, yeah,
c10245
DM: yeah.
c10246
Delwath: Um.
c10247
Wellby: Yeah, let's grab them and go.
c10248
Wellby: We'll figure it out when we get back to Rai's.
c10249
DM: Okay. So you grab things.
c10250
DM: Rai,
c10251
DM: shortly after you do this, you sense, you see like the
c10252
DM: orb starting to shake slightly.
c10253
DM: You all kind of grab on, and Rai
c10254
DM: yanks it. Uh, Seeker, make an intelligence check.
c10255
Seeker: Ugh, intelligence check.
c10256
Unknown: Like you can step that way.
c10257
DM: Oh, yeah.
c10258
Seeker: That's with a plus 11.
c10259
Seeker: Oh, no, that's 10.
c10260
DM: Just a plus five.
c10261
Unknown: Plus five.
c10262
Seeker: That's a 21.
c10263
DM: Okay. So you manage to expand, you know, hold your sphere of stability against...
c10264
DM: But there seems to be a collapsing wave front of chaos that you're racing against, um, that's just, like you can see, it's not, like normally you're passing
c10265
DM: through Li- Limbo and things would change, but you could see things.
c10266
DM: Like there would be stone for a while and it would shift.
c10267
DM: You're like racing a front, in front of this wave front of just
c10268
DM: swirling madness.
c10269
Unknown: Mm.
c10270
DM: That's like a, like an explosion expanding out from where this tower collapsed of, uh,
c10271
DM: not like unstable even for Limbo.
c10272
Unknown: That's no good.
c10273
Seeker: We should probably just teleport.
c10274
Unknown: That's it.
c10275
Delwath: Mm, you can't use your slot though.
c10276
Unknown: No, that's true.
c10277
DM: So m- racing forward,
c10278
DM: uh, you get a little bit of distance from this thing, like you're maybe 30 minutes ahead of it, ahead of this wave of expanding explosive, explosive chaos,
c10279
Unknown: 30 minutes ahead.
c10280
DM: as you appear in the monks area
c10281
DM: with something like 30 minutes before a chaos bomb hits the monastery.
c10282
Seeker: And but the ritual-
c10283
Delwath: Takes an hour
c10284
Seeker: ... takes an hour.
c10285
DM: Oh, sorry. You have an hour and a half before the-
c10286
Unknown: [laughs]
c10287
DM: Yes. It, it doesn't act- the ritual could actually just only take five minutes.
c10288
DM: The point is you have 30 minutes of spare time.
c10289
DM: I forgot the ritual.
c10290
DM: I said the ritual took an hour.
c10291
Wellby: We can't short rest again in 10 minutes, can we?
c10292
Wellby: Let's roll on rest.
c10293
Delwath: He's still got prayer of healing to get spell slots back, but he can't get a short rest.
c10294
Seeker: No. Is there a third spell caster?
c10295
Unknown: I mean, Rai-
c10296
Unknown: Rai
c10297
Unknown: ... Rai has spell slots.
c10298
Kenzo: Rai should, Rai can help.
c10299
Wellby: Can Rai help?
c10300
DM: Uh-
c10301
Delwath: Oh, wait. Can I use a, can I use a, I can use a mystic arcana, right?
c10302
DM: No, that's not a spell slot.
c10303
Unknown: Really?
c10304
DM: Yeah, 'cause the whole point is you can do that-
c10305
Delwath: I, I know, but it seems like you should be able to expend the magical energy here
c10306
DM: Ah, so I mean,
c10307
DM: what are you doing about the monks?
c10308
Seeker: Oh, what do we do about the monks?
c10309
Seeker: What about the monks?
c10310
Seeker: Well, they're all gonna die.
c10311
DM: In 30 minutes...
c10312
DM: Well, in an hour and a half,
c10313
DM: uh-
c10314
Wellby: We're gonna, we're gonna load them all across the rainbow bridge with us.
c10315
Seeker: Oh, there you go.
c10316
Seeker: Right?
c10317
DM: Five, we a- yeah.
c10318
Wellby: We call the bridge and just march everybody back.
c10319
Delwath: We totally could.
c10320
Wellby: But presumably we need to stabilize things prior to doing that?
c10321
Delwath: But also, if you succeed at the ritual, won't you be able to control Limbo?
c10322
Delwath: But maybe not the chaos bomb.
c10323
DM: No, you-
c10324
Wellby: Yeah
c10325
DM: ... you're not controlling Limbo.
c10326
DM: You're, you're destroying the sphere, so you probably introduce actually even more chaos.
c10327
Unknown: Right.
c10328
DM: But you move Limbo away from the material plane.
c10329
DM: Um, yes, Rai can contribute.
c10330
DM: Um, but he's u- I mean, he's drained a lot of his magic doing stuff, so I'm gonna say he can give you a fifth level slot.
c10331
Delwath: Okay. But if Rai gives a fifth level slot...
c10332
Delwath: Hold on. You have a heroic inspiration,
c10333
Delwath: right?
c10334
Delwath: I do.
c10335
Delwath: You have a bardic inspiration.
c10336
Unknown: Uh, I do.
c10337
Seeker: The final legacy of Seeker
c10338
Delwath: I can cast guidance, which gives you a D4.
c10339
Unknown: Oh.
c10340
Delwath: So that means you're...
c10341
Delwath: And if Rai gives away, you said a fifth level slot?
c10342
DM: Yeah.
c10343
Delwath: So Rai plus Delwath plus Seeker is 18.
c10344
Delwath: 18 and 17 is-
c10345
Unknown: 35
c10346
Delwath: ... 35. Guidance plus bardic makes your minimum
c10347
Delwath: 36, 37, 38.
c10348
Delwath: So if you roll a three or better-
c10349
DM: No, it's only plus two.
c10350
Wellby: Much like teleportation
c10351
Unknown: ... plus the one from the roll.
c10352
DM: Oh, yeah, plus the one from the roll.
c10353
Delwath: Right. So if you get a three or better, yes, you succeed-
c10354
DM: It's a three or better to succeed
c10355
Delwath: ... it's a three or better.
c10356
DM: So you get three shots at rolling a three or higher.
c10357
Unknown: Come on.
c10358
Seeker: Oh, that should be doable.
c10359
Unknown: On a D20?
c10360
Unknown: Yeah.
c10361
DM: That seems, that seems-
c10362
Unknown: Come on
c10363
Wellby: ... this is like a one in 1,000 failure or something like that?
c10364
DM: Safe.
c10365
Kenzo: So safe.
c10366
Wellby: Yeah.
c10367
Delwath: It's... 'Cause to get a three or higher is 85%.
c10368
Delwath: You have a 15% chance of...
c10369
Delwath: Or no, you have a 10% chance of failing,
c10370
Delwath: but 10% times 10% times...
c10371
Delwath: It's one in 1,000. You're not gonna fail.
c10372
Seeker: Yeah, that was what I quickly calculated as well.
c10373
Delwath: Yeah. That's pretty safe.
c10374
Seeker: I don't know. Safety first, everybody.
c10375
Seeker: We gotta bring it down below one in 1,000.
c10376
Unknown: [laughs]
c10377
Seeker: No, I'm just kidding. [laughs]
c10378
Delwath: I don't think I have anything else that can help.
c10379
Seeker: The chaos bomb is coming. We've got to do this ritual.
c10380
Kenzo: Let's do it
c10381
Seeker: Seeker begins the ritual
c10382
Kenzo: Wait, so where's Rai?
c10383
DM: Uh, Rai doesn't move
c10384
Kenzo: Well, like where, where, where is our, we're right now or we back in the monastery?
c10385
Unknown: Yeah, you're back in the monastery.
c10386
Unknown: Okay.
c10387
Unknown: We're...
c10388
Seeker: We bring it up close to Rai-
c10389
Unknown: Yeah
c10390
Seeker: ... to be with him in this important moment.
c10391
Delwath: Oh, wait, we still have to kill the giant ooze, don't we?
c10392
Kenzo: Yeah, we have a whole Isengay arc tomorrow.
c10393
Unknown: Right. Yeah.
c10394
Unknown: Right.
c10395
Delwath: Right, right.
c10396
Kenzo: This, this is just the-
c10397
Delwath: I was like, wait, what are we gonna do tomorrow?
c10398
Kenzo: This is the clean, this is the cleanup.
c10399
Kenzo: Tomorrow's when we gotta put the heart root back in the thing.
c10400
Kenzo: Right, right, right, right.
c10401
Seeker: All right. So I'm looking at this
c10402
Seeker: sphere of black and gray and red with swirling runes.
c10403
Unknown: Yeah
c10404
Seeker: A deeply complex pattern all around it.
c10405
Seeker: I find the starting point
c10406
Kenzo: and begin to read. [die rolling] Nice.
c10407
Unknown: Yeah.
c10408
Delwath: You don't even need any of your bonuses.
c10409
Unknown: [laughs]
c10410
Unknown: [laughs] So-
c10411
Seeker: That's a 35 plus the 10.
c10412
Delwath: Oh. That's a 35 straight up, plus...
c10413
Delwath: That's like a 50. [laughs]
c10414
DM: So Seeker begins to read, and for a moment, um, you,
c10415
DM: you are the multiverse.
c10416
Unknown: You have, like, this
c10417
DM: brief second where you can see everything, all the connections, all the planes arrayed in a hyper dimensional plane.
c10418
Unknown: Ah.
c10419
DM: All, like, neatly ordered-
c10420
Unknown: Hmm
c10421
DM: ... and arrayed next to each other.
c10422
DM: Seeker's gonna spend the rest of his life trying to get this knowledge back.
c10423
Unknown: [laughs]
c10424
DM: But you can see it really clearly for just-
c10425
Seeker: This is the one thing he's always wanted to see
c10426
Unknown: ... a second.
c10427
Unknown: Uh-huh.
c10428
Seeker: The one thing
c10429
DM: And then you just see the one little place where you just have to push very slightly.
c10430
Unknown: Mm.
c10431
DM: Or rather pull very slightly, and Limbo kind of
c10432
DM: drifts. The rest of you, you don't feel anything or notice anything.
c10433
Unknown: Um, but-
c10434
Kenzo: Well, did, does Seeker pull it or not?
c10435
Seeker: Oh, yes. [laughs]
c10436
Unknown: Or you could push.
c10437
Unknown: What if it was a test?
c10438
Unknown: [laughs]
c10439
Kenzo: You can do anything right now, Seeker.
c10440
Unknown: [laughs]
c10441
Kenzo: Anything at all.
c10442
Kenzo: This i- this moment right now-
c10443
Seeker: These planes are too far apart
c10444
Kenzo: ... [laughs] yeah, this moment right now is the equivalent of, like, you actually getting a crown.
c10445
Kenzo: Like, you've be-
c10446
Unknown: [coughs]
c10447
Kenzo: You just gave him Seeker the ability to do whatever the fuck he wants with the fucking multiverse.
c10448
Seeker: You see Seeker sort of making a subtle smirk as he does the right thing.
c10449
Kenzo: [laughs]
c10450
Unknown: [laughs]
c10451
Unknown: So
c10452
DM: n- n- nobody else really feels anything, but you, Seeker, you see, like, there's a tearing
c10453
DM: and then, um, like a v- v- v- v- v- v- v- v- like, zipping sound as a seam is sealed,
c10454
Unknown: and Limbo,
c10455
DM: it's like, almost like a bubble that kind of collapses in on itself a little bit like this and then
c10456
DM: reinflates slightly further away from the material plane.
c10457
Seeker: That's all we needed to do.
c10458
DM: And you just spend a moment just watching the dance of everything, like, for a lot-
c10459
Delwath: Can you, like, mutter, like, how many planes there are at least out loud to us?
c10460
Unknown: Um.
c10461
Unknown: Probably not.
c10462
Seeker: Probably not. [laughs]
c10463
Unknown: No, it's too-
c10464
Seeker: Like, information overload at that point
c10465
DM: ... it's informational overload, yeah.
c10466
Seeker: Looking at, like, a huge high, high dimensional diagram.
c10467
DM: Right, it's like in 17 dimensions.
c10468
Unknown: Yeah.
c10469
Unknown: Ah.
c10470
Unknown: So
c10471
DM: I need something not combat music for this.
c10472
Unknown: So then
c10473
Unknown: for a minute-
c10474
Unknown: Mm
c10475
DM: ... everything is just quiet.
c10476
Unknown: Yeah.
c10477
DM: And from Rai you have a moment of, "I guess it's done."
c10478
Unknown: It is done.
c10479
DM: The great war is finally over.
c10480
Unknown: [instrumental music]
c10481
DM: At this moment, you can...
c10482
DM: The monks are, like, all crossing the bridge, going back to Vindristarna.
c10483
Kenzo: Oh, the rainbow bridge is here.
c10484
Unknown: Yeah.
c10485
c10486
Kenzo: Yeah.
c10487
Kenzo: Nice.
c10488
DM: And Rai just kind of turns and looks at you all for a moment.
c10489
Unknown: Wait, he turns?
c10490
Kenzo: Can he move around now?
c10491
DM: No, no, no, he doesn't turn. Actually, wait, hold on, hold on.
c10492
DM: Wait, wait, wait. I, I ruined it.
c10493
DM: Um, start again.
c10494
Unknown: All right.
c10495
Unknown: Um,
c10496
Unknown: he
c10497
DM: pauses for a moment in your mind,
c10498
DM: and you see just sort of flying in the corner of your eye a little golden bird begins to fly in a circle around his head,
c10499
DM: and he... The jade begins to fall off of Rai's body, and he turns and he looks, and I s- he says, "I think we're done.
c10500
DM: There's always more to do, though."
c10501
DM: And a voice says, "Let it rest.
c10502
DM: Let the world move on.
c10503
Unknown: Doesn't need us."
c10504
DM: And Rai begins climbing a staircase followed by this golden bird
c10505
Unknown: and vanishes.
c10506
Unknown: Mm.
c10507
Kenzo: Was the voice from the golden bird?
c10508
Unknown: It was Kir?
c10509
Unknown: It's Kir.
c10510
Unknown: Yeah.
c10511
Kenzo: Whoa.
c10512
Unknown: Yeah.
c10513
Delwath: Rai returns to the plane of
c10514
Unknown: somewhere.
c10515
Unknown: Where did he go?
c10516
Unknown: And as he's leaving,
c10517
Unknown: um,
c10518
Unknown: there's one
c10519
Unknown: parting message.
c10520
DM: His voice takes on this...
c10521
Unknown: You haven't heard him speak before.
c10522
DM: He starts speaking. His voice takes on this echo of power,
c10523
Unknown: and he says
c10524
DM: I wish, Dimitar, for you to live as long as life on this world gives you pleasure.
c10525
Unknown: Oh.
c10526
Unknown: [laughs] Amazing.
c10527
DM: And he steps. He vanishes then.
c10528
DM: But you can hear this is a wish spell.
c10529
Unknown: Yeah.
c10530
c10531
Unknown: That's awesome.
c10532
Seeker: Dimitar, the immortal emperor [laughs] of this circular island.
c10533
DM: [laughs]
c10534
Unknown: What have you done, Rai?
c10535
Unknown: [laughs]
c10536
Unknown: Our whole next campaign-
c10537
Unknown: No
c10538
Wellby: ... is just him coming down again. [laughs]
c10539
Delwath: And eventually he grows up to be Cha'mutte.
c10540
Seeker: [laughs] Looping time back around-
c10541
DM: Right
c10542
Seeker: ... to before time.
c10543
Seeker: That'll be kind of perfect, actually.
c10544
DM: The-
c10545
Unknown: Oh, wow. That was great
c10546
DM: ... there is a crack-
c10547
Delwath: Yeah. We're, we're-
c10548
DM: ... through the floor
c10549
Unknown: ... all running to the bridge
c10550
DM: Okay.
c10551
DM: You all run onto the rainbow bridge as the monastery decays around you,
c10552
DM: moments before the chaos explosion hits,
c10553
DM: and you race across, the last ones, the monks having all gone before you while you were talking to Rai, run across the bridge
c10554
DM: and
c10555
DM: return to the Elven Forest,
c10556
DM: uh, in the middle of the night,
c10557
DM: not even a day having passed-
c10558
Unknown: Wow
c10559
DM: ... since you entered Limbo,
c10560
DM: and all now level 20.
c10561
Unknown: Amazing.
c10562
DM: So you can fight the Oozes level 20.
c10563
Unknown: Oh, fuck.
c10564
Delwath: I get a ninth level spell.
c10565
DM: Yeah. And you get plus four to wisdom and dex, so your AC's gonna be like 23 now.
c10566
DM: And you get power word heal and power word kill.
c10567
Seeker: Whoa. Delweth will see clearly.
c10568
DM: Well, power word heal is great 'cause it restores like 100 and it's like a ridiculous number of-
c10569
Unknown: Yeah, mm
c10570
DM: ... hit points.
c10571
DM: So that is obviously where we will stop tonight.
c10572
Seeker: That was-
c10573
Unknown: Wow
c10574
Unknown: ... amazing.
c10575
Unknown: That was amazing
c10576
Unknown: Wow.
c10577
DM: And tomorrow is, of course, Isinge and the Ooze, and it's the end.
c10578
Seeker: That was beautiful, Tim.
c10579
Unknown: Yeah.
c10580
Kenzo: Amazing.
c10581
Unknown: Yeah.
c10582
Delwath: I like how the dice always seem to work out.
c10583
Delwath: Like, Seeker rolling a three constantly on the dragon was like [laughs]
c10584
Unknown: [laughs] It was amazing.
c10585
Unknown: It was amazing, right?
c10586
Unknown: Yeah.
c10587
Unknown: It was like exactly right.
c10588
Seeker: Of course Seeker couldn't be like, just like, uh, stylishly and elegantly triumphant-
c10589
Unknown: Exactly, yeah
c10590
Unknown: ... as a dragon.
c10591
Unknown: [laughs]
c10592
Seeker: He just had to absorb a lot of hits over and over again and just barely make it through.
c10593
Unknown: Exactly.
c10594
Unknown: Yeah, that's right. Abs, abs, abs.
c10595
Unknown: It was perfect.
c10596
Seeker: Um, oh, God, never gonna be a dragon again.
c10597
Delwath: [laughs] He's like, "I'm changing my name."
c10598
Unknown: It's horrible. Too stressful.
c10599
Unknown: Something else. [laughs]
c10600
Unknown: You can be a dragon if you wanna be.
c10601
Unknown: Um...
c10602
Seeker: [laughs] That was really fun.
c10603
Kenzo: Why was, uh, why was Qair a golden bird?
c10604
Seeker: That's what, that's what Qair turned into when we were in like 9th grade.
c10605
Unknown: Yeah.
c10606
c10607
Seeker: Or 10th grade.
c10608
Unknown: Cool.
c10609
Seeker: 'Cause he got like actually perma-killed and had to transmute or something.
c10610
Seeker: I don't remember exactly when it happened.
c10611
DM: No, what happened was like all of us thought that you didn't like your character.
c10612
Unknown: Oh.
c10613
DM: Or at least I thought you didn't like your character.
c10614
Unknown: No.
c10615
DM: And so you ha- I like we had a chat.
c10616
DM: I was like, "You have a, you know, you can change your character now if you want to."
c10617
Unknown: Hmm.
c10618
DM: And you're like, "No, I like Qair," and so Qair came back as the golden bird.
c10619
Unknown: Ah.
c10620
Unknown: Hmm.
c10621
DM: But that was like the beginning of all the, like, Qair-
c10622
Unknown: Astral plane
c10623
Unknown: ... astral plane stuff.
c10624
Unknown: Yeah.
c10625
Delwath: Oh, I can take true polymorph, and then I can be a dragon too.
c10626
Unknown: [laughs]
c10627
c10628
Kenzo: Then it's only Schwartz. Only Seeker.
c10629
Unknown: Oh, man.
c10630
DM: Well, no, with true polymorph you can make anybody.
c10631
Delwath: I could make... [laughs]
c10632
Unknown: Whoa.
c10633
Unknown: Finally, I can live the dream.
c10634
Unknown: Finally.
c10635
Kenzo: Yeah, before this campaign ends, you, you all need to enjoy being dragons.
c10636
Kenzo: That's pretty, that's pretty important.
c10637
Unknown: [laughs]
c10638
Kenzo: Even for fun.
c10639
Unknown: I don't know, man.
c10640
Unknown: Uh...
c10641
Delwath: The new form can be any kind you choose that has a challenge rating equal to or less than the target's challenge rating or level.
c10642
Kenzo: We, we, we, uh, grabbed those items though, right?
c10643
Delwath: I mean, it's different.
c10644
Unknown: Yeah.
c10645
c10646
Unknown: It's different than shape shift.
c10647
Unknown: No, it's basically the same.
c10648
DM: I don't think you retain your spell casting.
c10649
Unknown: It-
c10650
Unknown: Uh
c10651
Delwath: ... so it retains its hit points, hit dice, alignment, personality.
c10652
Seeker: Yeah, that was pretty cool to be able to do with Chain Lightning.
c10653
Wellby: So wait, does true polymorph permanently do that?
c10654
Unknown: Uh,
c10655
Unknown: it-
c10656
Unknown: Temporarily
c10657
Delwath: ... the transformation lasts for the duration or until the d- but if you m-
c10658
DM: If you maintain concentration for a full hour, it is, it is permanent until dispelled.
c10659
Unknown: Yeah.
c10660
Unknown: But you go-
c10661
Wellby: So over a couple of days we could be a party of four dragons.
c10662
DM: You could, although I think you're actually-
c10663
Unknown: We might
c10664
Unknown: ... stronger than-
c10665
Unknown: Yeah
c10666
Unknown: ... a party of four dragons.
c10667
Unknown: Oh.
c10668
Delwath: But you can also turn a creature into an object.
c10669
Unknown: Right.
c10670
Delwath: Like you could just convert things into-
c10671
Seeker: Yeah
c10672
Unknown: ... objects